In this video
We are going to design
Are very
Simple AI as
Are task for this job is
Weather
The gold we will give our agent is a specific
Tupac user
Let's use a practical example
We will ask
What is the weather in London
And should I take an umbrella
So you can
Play the question
This is a
Play Simple identical
It is not just a straightforward data retrieval
It is the second influential
So the agent cannot just know the answer
It requires
It must plan to get external data
And then it was a reason about data asking itself
Does light rain mean an umbrella is needed
To provide a complete
And helpful answer
Let's look at the art design architecture diagram
This is the map of
We have the user
Who acts as an environmental
They sent the
As you can see that the user to go with something to prom
And vehicle is a goal for agent interpretation
And in the center of the agent
We have a little
And this is all alarm the reasoning engine
It receives the user prompt
It also has access to definition of
Available capabilities and
So that means we have our
What's under the art agent
In this case our tool is
Weather API
An alarm
Don't decide to call weather API according to user go
Send API radio
And get ready
And the last step is reason
According to incoming weather data
Agent Ellen reasoning about
Does light rain mean an umbrella is needed
I'm prepared and return
The final answer
To