In this section
We are going to learn
What are a agent
This section will cover
How are agents
Key component
Is done
Use
Intelligence of the AI agent
Let's forget to technical jargon for just 1 minute
What is an AI
So basically a agent is not a just a to
The easiest way to think of AI agent is a digital employee
You can't think about how you work with a human assistant
You don't give them a million tiny step-by-step instructions
You don't say
Play click this button
Don't type this
And then
You give them a goal
You say please res
The top five competitors for our new product
And send me a summary by Friday
So you trust
They have the skills to do
Using a web browser
Reading document
Writing a summary
On the agent works on the same principle
It is a software entity you give a
I need autonomously uses its
Which we call
Tools or AP
To achieve that call
This is the fundamental difference from a simple tool like calculator
What do you have to do all the
Also we can say that an a ag
Is an entity that can do three things
It can perceive its environment
This mean
Nancy
Need information
Like any email arriving a stock price changing
Or a user sending a message
Second it can reason about those perceptions
This is the brain
Usually another
That makes a decision or a plan
Based on the new information
And it is overall
And the third one is
It can act on its environment to make the
This is what it does
Like calling an API sending an email
Organic a piece of code
This simple powerful cycle
Reason
Sing an
This is the agency
This is the engine of everything we are going to build on this course
What really
Is a piece of sulfate an AG
82 agent exhib
It's for key principles
You can think of
Is is the soul of an agent
These are the
Being golden
Having autonomy
Being reactive
I'm being proactive
So now let me explain
What is one by one
The first one is
Is golden
This is the most important principle
It all
What's better
A traditional secret Pol
What's instructions
An agent purses a girl
What is the difference
For example
An instruction is
Run this report at 5:00 p.m.
But a goal is could be
Ensure the executive team
Is the French say state that they
Every morning
You can see the difference
The goal is flexible
The agent might run the report or it might see the database is done
And send an alert instead
It does whatever is necessary to achieve the objective
This is a Who
Is it in Hobby right to soft
So the second principal is auton
This is the principle that makes it truly agent
Autonomy means the agent can operate without Direct
Step-by-step human interv
It makes its own decision about how to achieve its
You can think back to
Digital employee anal
You don't tell a developer
Which specific line of code to
You tell them what teacher to do
The autonomous decide on the implementation
This is what we are building soft
That you can delegate a task
Not just a function call
Another principle is
Reactivity
Drill that is mess
It is not stat
API
Play School Miss
And users change their
Reactivity
When is the agent can respond to this
Is in its environment
This is a massive difference from a simple Secret
If a secret tries to call an AP
Play and gets a 500 ER
What
Eat GR
However an
Send perceives that error
It is reasoning brain says that failed
My goal is to get the data
I'll try to backup API
Is eggs again
It is a robust resilient and re
And the last principal
Proactiv
This is the advanced principle
This is what separate a good Agent from a great one
Brockton is means that the agent doesn't just sit there and wait for things to happen
Next initiative
And that
Is it anticipates problems
Let's imagine a silver monitoring AG
If only reactive AG
Will send you an alert at 3:00 a.m. saying that
Silver disc is 100% full
And this is not very helpful
Inst
A proactive agent would see the solar disk
Is 90% full
I'm feeling up
I am proactively archiving old
To prevent a crescent
Which one would you rather have
That's a product
It is about taking initiative in service of the
So when you put all these four principal together we can say that and a agent is golden
Autonomous reactive and proactive
You get something that much more than just a secret
I'm much more than just a simple call to an alarm
You get any kind of software component
And you get an entity that can Perce
The reason an act on behalf of the achieve go
In a complex