In this video
We are going to learn
How a Agee
Uses generative a
Many people use these terms are interchangeable
But they represent two distinct approaches to artificial intelligence
We are all quite familiar with generative a
Play this include the chat
Image Jenner
What's on Google Assistant be used
But agentic AI represent
What's a fundamental shift in cap
Understanding these difference is essential
Before we can build any true agentic architect
Let's start by defining the generative a
Genetic AI is a fundamentally reactive system
This is it's definitely the
Beats for you the user to do something
Specific
It waits for you to prom
Once you provide that
Its entire job is to generate
How to contact
Based upon the patterns it learned during the train
This systems are essentially
Sophisticated pattern matching Miss
They have learned the
Mystical relationship
Difference between
Between pixels
In a image or between notes in a piece of audio from massive data set
Can you provide a
The generative AI
What should come
But
Put ants at the moment of generation
It doesn't take further step
It doesn't
Light on the world without your
New subsequent input
So now let's define agentic a
Identity
Play systems are not reactive
They are proactive systems
No like generator AI
They often start with a user
But the crucial difference is
Holiday treat that
It is not just a request for a single piece of content
It is interpreted as a
The agents purpose is to perceive that goes through a series of action
To do
An AG
Make system goes through a life cycle
Which we call the agency
This is a continuous process
And this process operates
Which minimal human inter
So now let's understand
What is the role of the llm for both app
This can be a point of confusion
How can they be so different
If they both use l
The answer is that they shared a common Foundation
Alarms are the backbone for many generative AI chatbot
But in agentic system
Play an alarm
What's a
More specific role
It provides the reasoning engine that powers the AG
If the agent is a
The alarm is the engine
But you still need to
Listing
And the sensors
List of the AT&T architecture
To actually go anywhere
The alarm is the cognitive component
Did power the agents decision
So now let's see an application of the generative AI
Consider a YouTuber using a generative AI
They might use it to review a
Suggest something Concepts or even generate background music
But look at the
At
There's a human in the loop
That mean
Is the human Creator is looking at the generated content
Reviewing it
And most likely refining to prompt to try again
The AI Jenner
Is it possibilities
But the human creates them
The human is a director
The generative AI is the specialized creative
So now let's look at
Education of the agentic AI
So AG
Let's try in a scenario state require
Management and multi-step process
Let's consider a personal shopping agent
You don't give a prompt like write me an advertisement for a
You give it a
This this product for me at the best price
The age of 10 by itself Octavia hunts for availability
Is montour's price fluctuations
It
What's the checkout
Is using the payment apis
I need coord
It's delivery
It is a manager not a tool
Is lightly operate by itself
Seeking input from you only
It's absolutely need
At this point we can ask
How does the agent decide to hunt for a product or monitor a
So it comes with the Deep connection
Thinking for the
How does it
Is this autonomous decisions
It does this by using the generative a
Which is the alarm
What is the reasoning process
This is a key concept called
Turn off the reason
Did people see in the upcoming
The agent essentially use the alarm
Ability to think through a problem
It is a process
Where the agent breakstone a complex
Ask into smaller logical steps
Almost like talking to itself
This internal dialogue is a form of generation
But it is used as a step into the
What is the final output
This is the difference from the using l