In this video
We are going to learn
When to use and when not to
Use a
This is the most important
Just because we can breathe an agent doesn't mean we
An agent is a complex
Is powerful
An expensive component
Both in terms of the competition
And in terms of the design over
Choosing when to deploy an AI agent versus
Does edric alarm call
Is it critical architectural decision
Let's start with a simple example of the core architectural choice
Tool versus
Is it like that you have to decide
Does this problem require a simple tool
What does it require an autonomous work
Is it good or traditional function is like a humm
You use it for a specific well-defined tasks
Hit this
It is the thermostat
It is fast
And it is 100%
An agent is like
Hiding a carpenter
You don't give
Step by step instructions
You give them a go
Read me a book
The carpenter than autonomously select their home
Who's Lex
Who's
Increase a
An adults to problems
Like eating and not in the wood
The first and most important question you must ask
Am I just hitting a nail
Or am I building a bookshelf
So let's start
Repeat then not to use a
First the golden rule of the Atlantic architecture
If you can't handle a task
With a simple function or Secret
Do that
Using an agent that it is not needed adding unnecessary uncertainty latency and
And second do not use an agent for
What is structure deterministic
If your application
A specific input
And Isabel to
Linear sequence of operations
A traditional program
If you are required
100 person
Predictability
An agent is the wrong choice
Agents
Monday
If you are willing A system that for example
Moss process a transaction in an exact same way every time
You do not want an agent's creativity in
And finally for simple information retrieval
Just need to find and summarize doc
What's based on equity
Is
What non-agency great pipeline is more efficient
So now let's understand
When to use an AI agent
Or we can ask
When do we hide the carp
When the problem is open-end
Or under
This is when the goal is clear
But the pet to get that is not clear
When did tusk
Multi-step and multitude
It is not a single call
The agent must perform
Is the cast of different actions over time
When the task exists in a dynamic environment
What are the agent
React to unforeseen
An Engaged in trial and error
When the system is design
Improvement over time
Learning from feedback
From its environment or from users
And finally
Play when you need to really conversational
Collaborative inter
What are the agent and us
Work together to solve a problem
So now let's detail open Android
This
Is the user can provide
I want to talk to
And the exact sequence of the steps to fulfill
It is not known in advance
You cannot hardcore a workflow for
You must rely on the agents core engine
Which is the LL
In order to reason and plan the
What's on the
For example
The test could be convert to CSV to Json is defined
You can use
But if the tuskys
Analyze this CSV and find the three most important
Lights for the marketing team
Please open
Because the agent must deck
Who's should it
Who's Judith Plott a
Should it run aesthetical analyze and so on
Multiple process
Many tasks are too complex for a single shot of information retrieval
The agent needs to do multiple things in sequence
So this is where our agent architecture becomes
What's essential
The agent must
It is planning model
To break down the task
It must use it is true model
To select different tools at different step
And it must
Use it is memory to remember
What did you learn in Step 1
To inform me this decision in step 3
Ecological example is a research assistant
It doesn't
Let's find a document
It finds 10 doc
Read some
And then synthesize a new password
From all of them
This is
What is the Pro
So let's summarize this into a clear three step decision frame
Run face with a new problem
We can ask these questions in order
Is the Tuskegee simple and determine
If
You can use the secret or a function
Who's the tuskys complex but the
Yes or no and defined
We can use a traditional work
If the task is complex open-end
And operating in Dynamic environment
We can use an only use deploy an AI AG
This framework will help you to choose the right tool for the right job