In this video
We are going to learn
Reload use cases
Play AG
But before
Let's understand
What
Make a good use case for a
First of
It should in
An open-ended
Not a rigid instruction
At the age of 10 ultimately select and
Multiple to
In a sequence to achieve that go
And we are looking for problems
What's that require an active worker
Not just a positive
That include a
Go to step on the
Who's in a second
To achieve the
So now
Let's start the railroad use casts
And we are going to start
With the Enterprise automation
First of all
The AI in
Look for administrative tasks
That means instead of
Assistant monologue check
You give the agent a
Put our new engineers
So the agent and autonomously works through that plan
Provisioning account
Send an email
NCAA meetings
Buy interfacing with all those different systems
And the Second Use case could be
The team to customer support AG
This is not a simple jet
A user say
My order is broken
The agent is give the goal as
Ethan autonomy support from a multi-step process
Authenticating the user
Looking up the order and finally issuing to the front by calling a payment AP
So after that we can go to the technical and data
Agent use casts
And the next use case could be the autonomous data scientist
You don't tell it how to analyze data
You give it a file and a go
Find the
The age of 10 ultimate write and execute python
Close the
And provide a summary
Another use case could be
Play octave research on agency
Traditional rate is positive an agent is active
You give it a
Write a res
Eat pizza report
Activate researching multiple sources
Synthesize
And most importantly
Crit
It's on
About an research
Please find a gap
And another use case could be
The AI paid programmer
In this case you again give it a go
For example the factor this model
I need
Put but it doesn't stop there
It runs to test
Perceive the fail
Anna loves
Is reason about the error and it
It's on
So another group of use
Is our complex system integration use
The first one could be loyalty and agriculture
The agents goal is to maximize yield
It perceived the real-time data from the soil sensors
What's on video AP
I need reasons that the soil is
Annoying is coming
Ethan XY interfacing
Did I already have
To turn on the physical irrigation system
Another use case could be disaster
This often uses a multi agent system as a problem is too large for one AG
A coordinator
Is it given the
Until
Satellite agent
To find the image and a social media agent to find
What is today's
This specialist
Is working par
Updating a shared memory
In this case a life station map
So another group of this case are business and scientific agents
The first one could be equal mass and Market
The goal is to run a flash
The agent analyze customer data
Personalize and send the marketing emails
And then perceive the real time sales data
An autonomous
Advertise
Don't respond
Maximize return of investment
An Android case could be
Healthcare
Scientific res
Is Soldier given agent a go
Find potential drug candid
The agent plans a complex Circle
Does biomedical databases
Run simulation software
Analyze the complex result