In this video
We are going to learn
Challenges and limitations of AI
It is clear
La
What's his transformative potential
From agriculture to health
Is 280 oper
However
Is Architects an engine
Do you know there is no such a thing as a magic solution
With great power
Come significant comp
60 and
Our job is not just with what is possible
What to eat what is Rob
Secure and reliable
So now let's go to the our
What's the most fundamental challenge which is the non determinism
Traditional software is determined
If you give a function the same input
You will get the exact same output every single time
Like 2 + 2 always
What is equals
Play AG
Because their brain is an element
Are non determinist
What's the cast
Dismiss
Give me the exact same
For example summarize this email
An agent might prod
Use a slightly different summary today
Danny did yesterday
If I choose a different plan or a different word
What is isn't about to be
It is a core property of the technology
This property however
It's a massive challenge for us in testing and violation
How do you write a unit
Is for correctness when the output is intentionally variable
This is the ghost in the agent
And this beating us to the next challenge which is the security and guardrail
In all this case we celebrate giving
But we must remember that
What is to
There are AP
Is database connection
Does uncooked interpret
We are giving an autonomous
What's 90 * 67
The keys are Kingdom
What
When
University of
To close the
Creativity
Connect to
90% discount
Evil intentions
Misconfigured AG
Give a vocal of the cleanup to database
From calling to delete all user Comm
This is the fake agent problem
Are critical architectural challenge is to design robust guardrail
Did enforce
Greek permissions
Limiting an agent
Blessed
Use without stif
I think it's auten
Exchange on the TV business real
These are the cost and lat
First
Let's start with the
Agency groups are not
Every reason
Sing or planning step
Is at minimum one full llm
Is seemingly simple five step
What's good
Turn off 15 seperate large alarm
This can be thousands of times more expensive than
Running a tradition
El Grande agents stuck in a
Could become a significant financial liability
And the second problem is
Latency problem
Set alarm for 12
The major Dam in
Not millisecond
If I step agent plan
An easy to take 30 seconds or more to execute
This latency
What is unacceptable for mineral
Such as a real-time chatbot or a fraud detection system
Are architectural questions
How do we design for
Most efficiency
And how did he use a synchronous pattern
Change these latency
So the user isn't just starting
Sing a spinner
After all
Is we can go to the next
Which is the observable day
When your traditional code
You get a steak place
You can see the exact line
The function
And the data that caused the ER
But what is the status for Asian
If an agent prod
A bad result
We need to know why
Did it misinterpret the initial go
Did it pick the wrong tool from its toolbox
Did you make a faulty logical leap in its Chain of Thought reasoning
Without the ability to answer this question
The agent is a black box
The architecture question
How do we put a system to
Is Andy Buck an agent's internal monologue process
Are architectural challenges is the
Robust racing unlocking system
What do you call observable
So we can effectively debug an agent's thought
And after that we can go to the our last
Which is the hallucination
The house nation is Vander model generated
Is plausible sound
But factually incorrect
For
This person too dangerous
First is factual hallucination
The agent confidential
The product
What's 50
But it actually
What's 75
Simply because it invented the fact instead of using
I think it's stool
On the 2nd and more dangerous for us is actionable House Nation
The agent tries to act on its own station
It might imagine a tool that doesn't exist
Or
What do you call a real
With imaginary parameters
For example trying to book a flight with a meal preference argument
When are API doesn't support that argument
Disney at best
Is
Where is Eastwood corrupted dat
Are architecture challenge is to Grant the
Secret to finding it
What's
Switch to minim
Israel ticket
So the architecture question is
How do you grant the agent in reality
And how
Play secretly Define
So it cannot imagine new
So is it concl
Then we can say that
These challenges not determinism security
What's latency and hallucination
My team intimidating
It's meant to be realist
But these are not blue
They are not reason to avoid Building agentic Systems
Play these challenges are the very reason discourse exist
Solving this problem