In this section
We are going to learn
What are identical
We will cover
How do agent work clothes
Atlantic orchestration pattern
Dream
And platforms for Willingboro
We will expl
Is Agency for clothes
Are the key to building
Truly comp
Unreliable agentic applications
To understand why they are so powerful
Beam
Look at the old
Which is the traditional work
So what is a traditional work
It is a concept we are all familiar with
Is the struct
Repeatable sequence of
To achieve a business call
This is the flow chart model
The pet is predefined
Is everybody
From a business process model and notation model for formal diagrams
Is cicd pipeline
Which is the Unchained success of will test and deploy model
An even simple
Local tools like zapier or just when this happens to that
The single most critical characteristic of a traditional workload is that
It is determinist
It is
Given the same input
It will execute the exact same steps
Every single time
What are the limits of the traditional work
Traditional clothes are incredibly powerful
For automating known unpredictable
They provide reliability and efficiency
Did you call limitation is
They cannot handle ambiguity or
Unexpected input
Dial
They are designed for a perfect world scenario
On
As soon as they encount
Ambiguity
Unexpected in
Let's take a simple customer support workload
The rules if the email contains
Is the word ref
Rocky to the building
This
Until a customer right is it my last order was wrong I want
My money
In the customer
What's the internet is identical
The keyboard are Miss
The deterministic work
Doesn't understand the intent
So it
Probably rotting this ticket to a Jenner
Play Slow support
So this is the problem that the agency workload is designed to
An identical is a stateful architecture
That uses a large language model
Reasoning ability to dynamically wrote tasks
Between different agents
The analogy is no longer
Play Factory assembly
Do you need analogy
60 project manager
A project manager doesn't just follow aesthetic flow chart
They receive any piece of information
They assess the current state of the project
And they use their reasoning
To deck
What
Next best step
This is exactly how an energetic workload oper
And the key difference is between traditional and agent of their clothes
The pet is not defined in advance
It is decided at run
The new model has three key characteristics
Did everyone understand
What's 80 state
The workload has a memory often called a state
Is the greatest pet memory
That is passed between
In every
Dissipate accumulates cont
Like user query
Play and
Research dat
Second
Is 111
The call rotting
Which is the East State
Is
Is buy an alarm called
Do manager
St Luke's at the current state
And reasons about
What what to do next
On the third
Turn on the result of
Is that the workload becomes non-deterministic
Play or adapt
Because the alarm is making the choice
The pet is no longer fix
It can correctly wrote the money back email
It can decide a task need a search tool and a calculator tool
It can even decide that
It is first item
I need needs to look back and try again with a different app
Is it somebody we can say that
The traditional clothes are aesthetic flowchart
Deterministic rigid and brittle
Identical
Are adaptive project manager
A non determinist
Is Bulls the flowchart a run
This is the architecture for building complex
AI applic