In this video
We are going to learn
Components of agentic work
Do you know why we need work
To build complex
State
Applications
By composing simple module agents
No
What's OS
How are these work clothes
Technically constructed
What are the actual Architectural Components
That make them
So in this lecture we will put on our Arctic Cat
I learned the anatomy of a modern agriculture
We will find that it is composed of
Today fundamental parts
If you look at any Atlantic workload
Weather is good with the landcraft Microsoft framework or custom code
We will find these three core components
The first one is
The
This is the s*** memory of the entire process
It is an object that takes
Is the current status of the
What is the user query
And research d
And the second one
The knot
These are our workers
The agents or tools that actually perform the
This is our research agent or our Sunrise agent
On the third one
What is the
This is the rotten
It is the manager that looks at the state
And this
Which note to Santa job to
Here you can see the image for the agentic
We have a
On the
You can't think of the factory
Understate is
Put shade parts
What are the actual work
Start from the
And we have AIDS and these
Represent the managers decision
On where to move the next
Let's deep dive into this components one by one
The first one is
What is the
This is the arguably the most critical piece
Take me to the state is just a stateful object
You can think of a Json object or a python dictionary
That is passed
Homestead to
It is the single source of fruit for the work
For example
When a girl begins
The state might look like this
It contains
The user credit
And all other fields are
After
Like our research AG
It is only job is to take the user credit from the state
Performance
And then it is finding back into the state
As you can see
The state object is modified and now contains
Did you search data
On this the state object is the memory
Play that will be passed to the
We can go to the second component
Which is the knot
These are our work
A note is any function tool or most commonly an agent
Deadpool
What's one dis
Specialized tasks
It is job is simple
Read the data it needs from the state
Execute
Android is
Back to the state
The key architectural principal here
Is modular
Did you search
Only knows how to research the summary note on the
How to summarize
This is critical
Do not dance service are status
They are given the current state of the world
They perform their single
And Daisy turn the update
For example the summary
Doesn't know or care
The research
Run before
It only cares that research data exist
Is in the state object
It was giv
So finally we have a component today which is the
If notes are the workers stations
Does AIDS are the manager
Who directs the full of work between them
NH
Simply the logic that
It is job is to read the current state
Unda
Which note to execute next
In a traditional workload
This age
Is just a deterministic if statement
For example if research data is not normal
Then go to the summary
But in an identical
This is why we inject the llm reasoning
The age it
Is an alarm call
It asked the alarm
Give me the current
Which agent should I call
Little Soldier the summarizer
Or are we
Is what makes the workload adaptive and intelligent
This is the project manager
Turn on let's put it together and raise the floor of one job through this anat
First of
The workload
And the user created populates the
Here you can see the starting and we have a state
And second and
Are manager llm is invoked
It looks at the state and
There is no research dat
I need to write to do research note
So at the Third
The research note
This is our work or not
It reads the Creator from the state
On course
An update the state which is findings
On the first step is the
Once again
It looks at the new state and says that
Now we have a research data I need the route to do summary
So 85th stage we have a summary note
Answer me or not
It basically
What's the research data from the state
Summarize
And it's the somebody to the state
I'm finally
The 8th runs a third
It looks at the
Ancestor somebody is complete
On Roosevelt Club to the Finish note
So is there somebody we can say that
The state is persistent shared memory of the
What's the other work
Modular agents that perform the task
It's all the rotting log
Which is the 1119
That reads the
And decide which not to call