In this video we are going to learn
Atlantic orchestration patterns
We learned to me of agentic workload into three core comp
These are the
On the
No the next logical step is to ask
What are the common blueprints or design pattern
For arranging this block
How do you connect all
What's an
Define the capability of
In this lecture
Google
The four most important orchestration pattern
That you will use to
Read almost any agent applic
So let me start the first button
Which is
Sequential handle Pat
The first and simplest pattern is the sequential hand of
Which are called a Sandy
Is the diagram shows on the slide
This is
Is linear
Here you can see that
Add note a
Then not be done
All not represent our AG
The age logic here isn't until
It is a determinist
Play hardcore
180 is
Is hand off to
The state object is
What's best on the
With each
About eating it's contrib
A perfect example is a simple reporting AG
First research note
Dennis somebody you know Dr
And finally
Play an email
Listen to the result
This button is useful for simple predictable task
But it is not really agentic
Is it
Next to Adaptive reason
So here you can see the image of the sequential hand off
First
And go to the research
What's a research data to the state
And go to the summary
Read the research data and it is somebody
And go to the
Email
Read to somebody and send the email
And go to the result
So the next button is
Conc
Parallel
We can call multitasker design pattern
In here the workload folks the execute multiple not
At the same time
Ethan joins back into the single thread
In here the 8th logic
Is more comp
Because the age
Speak after the note
Simply the
The age before the note
What is a junior
I need more
Wait until the boat
Finish date
Acoustic example is equated that needs to data from two independent sources
The workload can run a web search
On a database create a note in par
A final Joyner
Then receive both sets of the data
To create a unified password
This button is all about
Repeat an eff
You can see the image of the concordant and peril
Example
It is starting with the rotten note and rotten
Start the
And this job is a credit
What's 3 in the planet source of the information
The first one is web search
Run in parallel with the database query
Play and dog
And lastly we have a junior
Did you see the results from all these AG
What's inquiry
To synthesize a final answer and go to the
We can go to the next button
Which is the major
Make Siddiqui
This is the most important pattern
And when we have already familiar with the Majestic or city kilometer
We call it to the orchestrator pat
In this design Pat
Do you have a
Route
After any worker not finish
An up
What's the
The work of always
Return to
Is Central water
This route
Is it magent
All
What's 66
The age logic is the L
Good
Looks at the new updated
And reasons about the next best
Should it call the Note 8 again
Should it call the not be
Or is it the job finished
So this project manager pattern is the most common flexible
And Powerful
For willing to relay adaptive and stateful agents
Here you can see the image on the slide for mag
Tiki router
As you can see that we
Central rotten Road
After any work
Finish
This is
An update
The workload always
Return to
Central route
On Santa
Right to progress into
Delete
And after that router
Reasoning about it
And this will be decide to next best action
To call the Note 8 again
Should we finish the
So the next button is
Can you chat on debate Pat
This is a multi-agent loop
In this model
Multiple
Can talk to each other
Initiate contact
The state object is usually just a list of the chat messages
Erat
Which agent gets to speak
For example
The right to the agent drops a report
The Russell passes this to the critic agent
And the critic AG
What's a crit
Underwater than pass the entire conversation history
Back to the right to the
Count for division
Diesel continues until the critic agent is
Or some other exit condition is
This pattern is exceptional for
According to high-quality
Iterative requirement
Cancel
Here you can see the image of the group
Play and debate design pattern
As you can see that we have a group manager
Answer the writer agent draft Airport
And after that this will be
Paste to the critic agent by the route
On criticism educated message for example
This is too complex
Simplify
And
Play agent passes the entire city back to the writer AG
Android
Rewrite history
Based on the critic and return the result
So is it somebody we can say that
We have call work lopat
Which are the sexual hand
For
Call Leonard and predictable
Concurrent and parallel Pat
Repeat an efficiency on independ
Magenta Carter orchestrator pattern
For flexible adapt
Unstable single agent for clothes
Debate but
Put Advanced collaborative and iterative multi-agent tasks
So is an Arctic