In this video we are going to learn
Frame
Books for willing to work
Escort first app
We have learned the anatomy of the workload
And do you know the patterns for arranging
No we moved from the bully friend to the construction site
How do we is a developers and r
Actually will this system
We could try to write a massive if can I smoke or complex while
What is
Discuss this become unmanageable
To do this professionally
Play videos
Quote First framework
We will focus on the land crab is a perfect example of the
But before that
Let's understand the core problem
Why not just write a simple python
The answer is
Add boiling staple
Cyclic graphs is much harder than it appears
You have the money to manage the state object
First thing is from function
And most importantly
Are most powerful Pat
Just like the magenta Carter and the group
Are cyclic
Day
Bullying this
If statement
And why Lo
Results in a beautiful
Dim the nested
This is impossible to debug or
And another reason is
Non determin
The
Is rotting choice is non Dieter
How do you manage this in a stand
So we need a framework that Natalie understand or Anatomy including the
Notes
I'm designed to handle Cy
So this brings us to length of framework which is the graph
Minecraft
Is a framework that
Is purpose weed for creating the state will multi-agent work clothes
It is not a framework for bullying agents
It's a framework for willing to work
What's the date coordinator
Inland
You formally Define your state as a fighting
And the framework now
Which these secret for you
You define your
Your work
A simple python function
And register them with the workflow using the add note function
And you define your
The writing logic
By exclusively connecting these not
Using the adage function
He transforms our abstract blueprint into concrete
Manageable
So we will see this kind of Frameworks in the next section