In this video
We are going to learn
Local platforms for Willingboro close
We have learned to quote first film
Looks like link
And this code first airport provide maximum power and flexibility
Play but it can't be the cause of the development
Add special
What is expertise
So we will analyze the role play
Uncritical trade routes of the local Norco platform
To building a giant eagle
So let's stop
What is the role of
Is local
No good Platt
Did primary goal is to abstract away the
60 Optical we just
So instead of the writing python code to Define
What state
This platform
Give you a vis
Dragon drop interfaces for connecting comp
You are quite literally driving your work clothes
You'd like a research agent
Wanted to come
What's the drug is somebody agent
And then drop an
Orlando connect them
This Promise is simple which is the speed
You are configuring ever
Not
This can empower
Citizen developers like business analyst or data scientist
To build their own identity autumn
Without needing a full engineering
So now let's explore
Is local local
Escape play
So these local landscape for are is the BT expanding
But we can go to Main Place into 5th categ
The first one is
Is the traditional automation platform
Most liked it and or zapier
These are the classic
Is Dundee
Which have now become a native
They have added an alarm for
Like classify email or Sunrise text
Directly into the existing visual
On the second time
Is visual Groff wheelers
Make flow Voice or light flow
These are essentially
Play Minecraft with a user inter
The original front ends for length
And they made directly to our concepts of the
And Finn
We have a all-in
On agent
Dislike GPT
You can put inside of
Get the extraction is taught
You don't even see a
You just configured an agent with instructions
An upload the tools it can use
The platform itself minutes to
Read and rotting logic completely behind the
So now let's understand
Why
Choose
Is local Platte
First and
Repeat
You can go from an idea to a functional internal
Order a prototype in a single afternoon
Not a 2 weeks to
The time to volume is undeniable
Second is accessibility
You can Empower your business
Is stupid the exact automation they
Which phase of your senior engine
To work on the complex
Call product
Turn reduce the infrastructure over
Repeat that 4 minutes the wrong time
You don't have to worry about provisioning service
What does
Or monitoring the agents execution
And finally this platforms enforce the best
They force the weather to think in terms of the modular notes and clean state
Which can prevent a lot of bed design
Hoverboard these benefits come with a significant long-term architecture
First limited flexibility
What happens when you need
Did a custom group chat pattern
But the platform only support
Sequential
You are fundamentally limited to Pat
What's the weather
Decide to provide
On second one
Is Vander
This is the big
Your entire world
Your business logic
Is not configured inside
Add a third party
If you need to migrate or if they raise their prices
You cannot just move your
You have to start from
The third one
Do black box problem
When the agent be
Is the Translate
Play debugging can be a knight
You have very little control over the underlying problem
The State Management
Where to find Green Arrow hunting
And finally cost at
Why is Chipotle prototype paying for execution on a sauce platform can become
Exponentially
Play expensive
Play done running a quote for Solution on your own intro
So is it somebody we can say that
You should use local Platte
News for prototyping
An internal to
They're perfect for quickly automating
Non-critical simple and dinner at work clothes
Including
Ask that are predictable and feed the sequential hand of Pat
But you must
Who's got first framework
For your call for the pictures
This is your intellectual property
You use
Why you need
Does cyclic work
Was like group
And then you need a total control over performance
Loyalty and cost at
Your secret sauce