Welcome to day 3 where we will be covering functions and modules in Python
Will start with
Define functions with deaf have you already done this in the previous day or yesterday
But you're going to go in more details about what are functions
Malfunction is a reusable block of code
That performs a specific task
Functions improve modularity and code reusability it helps you
You said for example if you see somewhere that you're repeating the same code over and over again
Just create a function out of it and call that function from one single place
Send future if you have to change something and change on the other one place and don't have to change every single place
Did you have the same functionality
Defining a function
Did you find a function you use the def keyword as you saw in our calculator example
In yesterday's video
So you use the DF keyboard to define a particular function
No and it's at the Syntax for that
Might look like I'm going to create
File save it inside
RD3
Call it
Samples
And here if I want to create a function you say start by saying def
Then comes the function name so here is the function name whatever name you want you feel like you give here
And then
The parameters so whoever is calling this particular
Function needs to send parameters
If it can be empty too if you don't want to send anything it's just like say print hello for example you don't need
Any parameters in here but if you want to add two numbers then you add
Two different parameters here that are passed and below it
The next line
It goes well code block goes
Malfunction can return or not return something if you want to return something back
Whoever called it like how we did in our calculator example
You can use the return keyword
And pass a result back
Do the calling calling variable
Parameters are values passed to the function for processing
The return values
Are values returned by the function after the processor
Let's look at some examples in this case so we already created
That's fine I am going to
Comment this out
And here
Create
A function
Parameters
Return
732 function to create a function as I mentioned you use def
And then I'll say this is for my addition I'm going to say add
Add numbers
And I need to send two parameters because I want to add two numbers you can also add three numbers if you want
But I want to make it simple
Add two numbers A&D and returns it back
Now I can return it directly like this you can also do
Is
Inside here
I can create a variable C and say a + b
Ninja Turtle C so that is also possible but less lines is always better so I always like to say
A + b
Instead of doing this I'm going to comment this out
And now to call it let's say a variable result
Wants to add two numbers can you add numbers
And pass two numbers for example 5 and
Three in this case
And I want to print that
Summation of addition of those two numbers
I can just
Put in that
Result variable
If I go to my
Kansas City today
And here I have the three samples so I'm going to say python
Three samples dot pivot and some music
45 minutes
Lexus 48
645 + 3
Get it out so that this is how you can create a function again
Function is created by the keyword def
Radio defining a function
Then the function name whatever name you want to give
The parameters that it has or if you don't want to pass any parameters you can just skip it for example in this particular case
I can just say
Add two numbers and I can just
Return
Two numbers like this
Run
Add two numbers and return it back but you have to
Change the variables here which doesn't make any sense but
This is how you can create call a function with no parameters in there
Next
How did you know functions
Let's look at
And lifetime of variables
No scope
Has two different types of scope one is called as a local scope
Weather variables defined in the function are only accessible without within that function which means for
Example if I create a variable C here
The scope of this variable C is only for this particular function if I use see here it will not know
What sea is and it will probably say nothing I don't know what she is so that is called as a local scope Within
Particular function
We also have something called as a global scope
Bad videos defined outside functions are accessible
Throughout the program so that's the global scope
Lifetime
Where local variables exist
Only as long as the function executes
So it means is the
Is the local variable that I created for example to see that I've created here
Only exist as long as the function executes as soon as the function is done executing those variables do not exist
Global a variables versus throughout the program
Unless it's modified within a function using the global keyword
I can show you some examples for it to run into examples let's first go ahead
And commented out
Let's start with the local scope
So for local scope I am going to create a function called as
Greet
An inside here
I am going to say message
Equal to
Hello
Now this is a local variable inside this Greek function
Which means if I try to use that outside it will not know what is the value of this variable
Now if I call the Greet
Function here
Bishop call this this
Call this function and print the message but
If I try to print
Something like
Message here
It will not know because this function this message variable is local scope only to this
Next function it's not available
Outside that's why you invented just so that we better understand this I can go back
Clear it out
And run that and you see it gives me a racist name message is not defined it doesn't know where it's defined what are you trying to do
So this gives you another
The remote
It will just work as same as before but doesn't try to run this and it will not give you a message so if
Play if you want to use this outside one thing that you can do is you can use Global scope so
Comment these out
Let's look
Global SC
No cancel Google
Costco
I'm creating a variable called as greeting
Equal to let's call it hi
And I'm creating a function
Call Desi hello
And inside here
I am going to say print
Greeting
So what's happening is the the message that I created here I
Created that variable outside which means it's available here
Inside the function
As well as
I can just say print
Greet
Outside the function two and it will not give me another because if you see where the variable is defined is
Outside the function and is also accessible to the Sprint statement right here now if I run this year
I will not have any
I don't even say hi
Here and then hide from here just say
I can just concatenated
Inside
The function
And this one I can say from
Outside the
Fun
Granite high from inside the function because it called this it will print it and then it will print this
Send hi message from both inside and outside the function so that's how you can create a global scope for this
Next let's look at importing and using modules now what are modules modules are
Python files
Containing a collection of functions and variables that can be used so instead of creating functions if there are
A lot of things that you are doing and want to reuse among different teams
Python files containing a collection of functions and variables that can be
Building modules can include something like
Python is already given you some modules like math module OS module and random module
First let's look at importing modules
There are different ways you can import modules you can import an entire module
Read I can give you an example
Just comment this out
So if you want to import an entire module you do
For example I want to import the math module so I'm going to say import
And in here
No I can use that module by saying math
Dot there's a function called a square root in there
Is it called that √16
If I run this so I don't have to write the code
To actually
Get a square root of a particular number I can just say Maddox square root
And if I run this it will say
4 is the square root of 16
Next is
Importing specific functions now math has a lot of different functions but if you want to only
Import a particular functions in this case
I want to from
I want to import
Square root
So that way I don't have to write this I can just say √16 and it will know what I want to do
So go ahead
And it gives me the same result because of course
Instead of
Importing an entire module I'm just importing a particular function
From that mod
Another thing that you want to know about importing modules is using aliases
So here
Instead of
Calling it Matt
I can call it sometime the module names are really big
So I can just imagine
So I can use an alias here and then I can say m dot square root sometimes let's say I create a module
Vivian is dancing on the mountain
So I can just say
Import viviani dancing on a mountain
As Viv something like that so there are some functions that there will be some modules that you'll see which have really long
Turn names and if you want to use a shorter version of it this is how you can use aliases
To create this
No another option is
Creating your own custom modules
Know sometimes what will happen is you'll have a lot of functionality that is available in your code and your multiple files
And you want to reuse this modules
Different different files so what you can do is you can create a py file
Bed custom functions and variables inside that particular python file
And you can import that into another script using import
And the name of the mod
Directly we'll see those in future but that's how you can create your own custom modules
Man you have a lot of code which might be needed in different
Different places that you can use that one example I can give you is for example let's say you have
Organization
Which has five different departments and they have the same login because the organization is the same login
Behind it
So instead of
Creating the login functionality every single time for five different departments
You just create that component or a module one time
And then get let all these five different departments import that module
Into that code
That every time a user comes in they can log in so that's can be a good use case of creating
Custom modules
Let's jump into hands on exercise
My first exercise today
Is creating a function
To calculate factorials now I've given you something similar as an exercise in the yesterday
What is a video
But here are objective is to write
A function
To calculate the factorial of a number
And call it within another function
So first we will Define a function called as factorial n that calculates the factorial of the number n
Then we'll create another function called Sprint factorial
And as a parameter
That called the factorial
Function and print the result
Let's go ahead and write the code for it
So I'm going to save this and close it
Create a new file
Python file
Save it inside my day 3
Exercise
And here first let's create a function
Call Dez factorial
Of
I'm here I'm going to see if
Equal to
What happens to factorials if n equal to 0 or
N equal to 1
That means I just returned
One in this particular case
I will call
The same function so I'm going to return
Factorial
10 -
So what I'm doing is I am reducing that number by one
And multiplying whatever the result is from this particular keep on multiply
If you don't know what factorial is for example
If I say what is factorial of
Let's give an example
5 factorial is 5 * reduce that
Doing something
The first number
Reduce that number by 1 for run it here
So which means
It will call it 3
Now the number will be to
Again it will call this
Now it will be one
In that case it will return back one here so this will give me
5 * 4 * 3 * 2
Equal to 120
You can do the math and check it out but that's what factorial of 5 is or we can run the function and check it out
A little while so what I can do here is I'm going to say create another one
One function
And this one is to print a factorial
Print underscore
Factorial
And here
Result
Equal to
Factorial of
And this will
This is used to print
The factorial
Toriel
Is
So that looks good
And now let's test this function I can call it I can say print
Underscore
Factorial
And pass the number five is what you wanted to test so this will call this function
Can you get the result from this particular function which is just
Only doing what I'm doing is I'm kind of separating these two step here here
The reason is
So I can kind of
Separate the functionality of finding a factorial and printing of factorial separately in two different functions
I can save it
Go here
Clear this
Lights on
Exercise
1.56 factorial of 5 is 120
I can change the number
Factorial of tennis 362
You're something simple
* 1 * 2
2 * 1 is 2 so that's why factorial of 2 is 2 in this particular case so this is success
Completing our exercise where we are printing of factorial of a given number
My second exercise
Is to build a custom
Python module
No objective here is to create a module
The basic math operations
And use it in a main script
So let's create a python file called as math operations
With functions for addition subtraction multiplication and division something that you've done in a previous day and
Will import and use this module in another script will create two different files
So first
For this let's go ahead here
I am going to call it
Since it's a module I am going to call it Matt
Underscore
Operations
B
And save it inside day 3
Not here I'm going to create
A bunch of functions let me do that a comma B
Tradition will return back
A + b
Next is
Subtract
Comma
And this will
Return
Minus B
Next one
Is to multiply
Comma
And then here
I can see a return
Times
Next is
Divide
Comma
Hear it again I will check
He is not equal to zero
I will say return
8 / B
I will say
Return
Division
Zero is
Allowed
So I have
Four different functions here
Inside my Mac dot operation where it does addition subtraction multiplication
And division now I will create a mean script
I'm going to call it
Exercise 2
EBay
And inside here
I am going to import that math
Underscore
Operations
Am
I'm going to use the AL
Navigate
Next
I'm going to say number one
Equal to 10
And I'm going to say number two
Equal to
And then I'll say print
Addition
Add is a function that we have there
And I'm going to pass number one
Comma number
So we can do more
Clear this
Is it python
Exercise
Dot pyre Texas edition is 15 so what I did was since it's in the same file
It picked up a same folder he picked up this file
Call this function to add
And then
So similarly now I can add
The other four which is
Traction
Multiplication
Division
And here I'm going to say
Divide
Multiply
And
So now if I run this
10 + 515
10 - 55
10 * 550
10 / 52.0 we have
Function here
Or we have our main code here
Exercise to dot by where we are printing out all the different
Functions
From
Module that we created which was called math operations here which has all the functions in there
Now I can use the same thing in this exercise too I can call it an exercise one
I can create another file and have them
Import this particular module and use it over there
So I hope you were able to follow along if not let me know if you had any problems
But next
For additional practice I would say that you can write try to create
Function to check if a number is even or odd
And call it with another function
And then try to create a module for string operations including functions
To reverse the string count the vowels in
And check for palindromes
Imported into a script and test the functions so you create a module and then import it in another script
And test if it works for you
So today in day 3 you had some Hands-On experiencing defining functions
Understanding variable scopes
And working with modules
By practicing with built-in
And custom modules are you developed reusable modular code
The critical skill in Ai and software development so this will be very much helpful in our future future
Reduce so I hope you follow this along nicely and if you had any problems or questions let me know and I'll get back to you