Day
Data structures here we're going to cover list
Doubles
Dictionaries and sets now we probably have used some of them before
But let's go deep dive into each one of them
Let's start with list
So what are list
List are ordered mutable collections
That can hold a variety of data types when I say mutable that means they can be changed
And upended deleted
Edited all those things when is this immutable that means once you create them
It stays as there
So let's start again ordered
Mutable collections that can hold a variety of
Data types let's see how do you create a list
Someone start with an empty project
Create a new file python file
Save it inside
AI boot camp Week 1
Clear new folder for rd4
And
I'm going to sit there
Dat
Structures
I'm here not to create a list of let's say I want to create a list of numbers
Show me some numbers equal to
Create this number one to three and four so this is a list
A phone numbers 1 2 3 and 4
I can create a list of fruits
Where I can say
So again square brackets
Banana
So this is my list of fruits which are list of strings inside here this was list of integers
This is list of strings
I can have a mixed
List
Which has combination of both
Or more so one is the number
I can have apple
And I can also have volume in here the third element is true
So that's how you can create a mixed list
The next time I want to talk about accessing these elements
Now you can access this Elements by index so what I mean by that is
So for example if I want to print
Numbers
And I want to print
The this is the zeroth element first and second element and this is the third element so the 0 the IND
Exit 0123 again for this is 0 1 and 2
01 and 2
So if I want to access the third number which is
01 and 2 so that's the index and that's what I'll pass here
Similarly if I want to
Access the first fruit I'm going to say fruits of zero
If I want to access inside this mixed
How to access the
Second element which is Apple
Melissa zero and one so this is first element 01 index
I save
Cancel this CD day for
And I'm going to say python
Before data structures and if you see
This is two which is this one
Apple and apple games I can change this
201 and 2 which is Cherry so index 2
Can print it
3 cherry and Apple
So that's how you can access this element by accessing through the index that's what it's called
We also have something called as negative indexing what happens here is so for example
If I say that fruits of -1
So what will happen is this is the index 01 and 2
Now if you go in the opposite direction from here 0 - 1
Will be the last item here -2 - 3
So if I say fruits of -1
It should give me Jerry so if I go here
And print
It'll give me cherry because
Index of -1 is this is 0 so the previous the last one
Is -1 so that's how you can use negative indexing
You also can
Next we going to talk about modifying this list
Is two different ways you can modify a list that you can add items
And you can remove items now if I want to add items
For example in my fruits I want to add more items
I can just sit here let me comment these print statements out
And I can say fruits
Append so that's the key word and add to the end of a particular
And it's in this particular list I have apple banana and orange
I want to open another one I can see orange
Another way of attending or adding items is I can see fruits
Dot insert
In this case I want to insert a particular index let's index one
I want to insert grip
So this is index one right now so this will insert grape
In between apple and banana
Fruits right now the entire day
Look something like this apple
In grape was inserted
Add banana and Cherry are there
Orange orange showed up at the end
If I don't do this here
Running again
I have apple banana cherry and orange
If I don't do this
I have apple grape inserted at one and then banana and Cherry move one index to the right and that's why we
The grape is in translated and index number one
Clear this out
Not want to remove something
What I can do is I can say fruits
Remove
And I can specify what I want to remove so for example if I want a banana remove banana
So I can just say remove banana so if I
Do that
Run it
It was a apple
Grape okay I didn't print it again let's go ahead
And then this after the removal of how it looks like
So before and after
So before I have apple grape banana cherry and orange but after I remove it
It removed banana from here and move everything one index to the left so Jerry came here orange came here
Send text to 0123
You can also delete
By saying delete
Fruits
Index that says zero
You can print it out just to show you how this works
Go ahead
So if you see apple grape banana Cherry Orange
Then I deleted the mood bananas it became Apple grape
Teddy and orange
Then I said delete fruit and index 0 should remove apple and move everything one index to the left
That's why we have
Jerry and orange juice
Another option is if you want to remove something from the top
You can say
Fruits
What this does is it removes the last element so if I go ahead
And print it now
Clear this
And now you have
If you see the video this apple grape banana Cherry orange we removed banana so we had Apple grape cherry and orange
Then remove the first item which is Apple so we got grape cherry and orange
Now when I said pop
It popped the last item which is orange if I call it
One more time
It will remove
Even the Cherry so it pops two of the items one is orange and one is
Charitable pop items from the last from the last elements from the last indexes
Let's look at
Slicing list
Now slicing is kind of
Getting elements from a particular
Play so for example I just want to get grape and Cherry from this particular
So how do I do that so I am going to first remove
My delete statements from here
Still display this
So I have
Apple grape banana cherry and orange
No I want to get
Let's call it
Sliced
Fruit
And here I am going to say I want fruits
From index
NetSpend this print
Sliced
So this is how you can slice a particular
List of items
It's like what is printing is 1 to 3 so 01 so this is the first one
Do banana and it doesn't take Cherry because I said one but before 3 that's what it means
If I said one before
It will display grape
Banana and
I can just say
So depending on which items you want so 0122
And before 4
So that is banana and Cherry so you can kind of
Slice a particular list into a smaller list and use that for some other operation you want you can probably
Think of thousands of different operations that you can do with this right now
But that's what
That's how you kind of slice a particular
List of items by giving this
Index colon index
Send text
Now that you completed list
Let's look at
Couples no doubles are similar to list but what exactly are supposed to
Ordered
Immutable collection of items
Unlike list
Which were ordered mutable collection
Apples are immutable which means you can't change them
Let's look at how to create apples so I'm going to go back here again
Go ahead and comment everything
Go all the way to the top
And first let's create a couple of colors
I'm going to create a couple by giving the rounded brackets
And here first is red
My favorite three colors red green
And I guess you guessed it blue
So these are three colors
Now in here I want to
Create a single item couple
What do you have to do is
Let's say I would say glass
And if you want to create a single item Temple you need to put a comma at the end of it or else it will not take it as
Make sure that if it's only single item you have to give
The name of the first element of the first element that is either a string or maybe
Specifying that this is a single item
And this is a three item top
Next thing that will look at
How to access elements in a table it's very similar to
List census ordered list
It's an ordered item
Order the data structure
So you can just say print
Colors
And you can just say zero
And get the first color
You can also use the negative indexing
As I mentioned and it will give me
Blue the last element over
Can clear it here
Columbus and you see red
For index at zero
And -1 which goes the other way around
And that's why we get blue here now again something that
Do you want to remember is immutability
Doubles cannot be modified after you create them
However they can contain mutable items like list inside them so we have strings here
In this particular case but you can have left inside there which and list can be mutable so that
How you can create a mutable
List of couples
Next
Let's look at dictionaries
So first what are dictionaries
Dictionary store
Key value pairs for
Fast lookups now in case of list it was order
In case of couples they were also ordered so you can access them using 0123
But in dictionaries you access items using the key value pair
So you can assess the value
Using the key item
So let's see how we create dictionaries
738 a dictionary here
Get commented out
And move it down
For dictionaries
I am going to create let's create a student dictionary
And to the student
I'll give a name
And then I'll give
I'll give
Let's say 25
I will give as let's agree
So this is how you can create
Key value pair where the key is in this particular case name is and great these are different keys and
And values are Alice 25 and
So unlike list where you have like in order to 01 and 2 here you don't have an order but you have
Increase volume
If I bring the student
Go back
And print it
Is the name Alice age and grade you'll probably see the way it is specified year
It's not it's not an order item so it might be saved in any order the way it's access
Is through the key value
Let's talk about that accessing and modifying data
Do access first
You'll probably can access this key with the values inside here
From the key so I can say what is
The name of the student
When I bring that it says Alice so that's how you access so you can see age
And you can get
Age or you can say
Grade
And assess
The grid of this particular student
Do the next thing that we don't talk about is
Adding and updating so what if I want to add something
To this particular
Two particular
So I can just say
It's over here
Print entire student
And then do the student I want to add a stop subject
I can see student inside square brackets
Little square brackets are used for
List but when you are assigning a key
And a value you can do it using this I can say
Subject that I want to add to the student is math so this creates a key value pair
If I print this out
What is the name is great and subject or discretion
Clear it out
And again now if I want to update something you can again do it similarly
Consider
I want to update the age
From 26 to 32
Now if I print it out
You'll see name is Alice a just got updated to 32 grade is a and subject is math so this is how
How do you add and update items
Inside a particular dictionary
Next
Let's look at how do you remove items
Again something similar to list
You can just use DL
Student
Send a picture of the item you want to delete for example
I want to delete the grid
That's how you can remove
Also let's print it out first
And then you can also use the
I can say student
Pop but in this case you can't give empty you'll have to specify what you want to
Popsicle subject is what I want to pop
Take this printed out
Let's display it so first one this is the original one
And then I said delete the grade and if you see grade is missing here
And I said pop subject
And if you see it popped subject out of this particular
Dictionary and now I only have name and age here
Next thing that we're going to talk about is
Iteration now how do you iterate through a particular dictionary the way to do it is because
For list
Search is easy because they are indexed
But if I want to
Rhett
Over a particular dictionary in the way to do it is
For key
Add value
Student
Items
So what it does is
Everything inside student
With the calling this function student or items
Put them in a list
This is what this function does item
And now you can access
Each
And its value from the student dot items items
Function
So I can just say print here
And value
So this will show me what will I get when I do this
So is his name is Alice age is 25 grade is it so it created a list of
Key value pair
From a dictionary
And then I can trade over them one at a time and display those values
Next
Let's look at
Now what are sets sets
Unordered collections of unique items
So the one thing that you would remember and said says you can't have repetitive items like for example if your numbers
Set of numbers 1 2 3 4 that's fine but what if you have
11223344 then it will
Kind of drop those duplicates and it will give you a set of 1,234
So I
Warheads are unordered collection
Off unique items
So how do you
Create sets
Create search
Just
Make sure that this is commented
And go down here
Create numbers
Equal to again angular brackets
3 and 4
She's not key Value Place because inside angle brackets keep all your studies
But if you use angle brackets with items inside here that's an unordered collection of unique items
Which are set
You can also create a empty set
For example I create just a variable name called an empty set
And to create an empty set you can just set
That's how you can create an empty
Now how do you add
Remove
Elements from a set
I think that's the next topic adding and removing elements
To do that
First I can just say inside
Numbers
I want to add
So let's
Numbers here first
Sonic
I said 1234 and if you see one two three four five so I did one more item
What if I want to add
What if I try to add four
57234 and output is again 1 2 3 4 5 because 4 already exists so you can't add duplicates
You can add some other numbers
But no duplicate as long as there's no duplicates it all works fine
Now what if I want to
Remove something so I can just use something similar
Answer the movie
And I want to remove the tattoo
So I want to 348 and if you see here 13482 got removed
When I call the remove function on a particular
Next thing that I want to talk about
Is set operations are you probably have learned about this before but set as three different operations first is Union
Which
Union of two different sets when you try to so for example I have this let's create a new one
How to move this
Set one equal to
I have one comma two comma three
And I have
Which has
Call Mom
Now if you seen this particular case if I try to
Union or put both the sets together
Set
And Union is done using the pipe symbol so I'm saying set one
In this case let's look at the output
Coastal cleared out
And then done it again 1 2 3 4 5 what happened by Union them
It took both of them put them together but since there is three that is duplicate
It used to be only once 1 to 3:45 that's what union is
Next that you want to talk about is intersection which is
Intersection between two different
I said so in that particular case
You can use the and sign
Something like this know the intersection between these two
Search is 1,200 exist but three exist in both of them
So three is the intersection point
So if I run it
I get only a
Orbit value of 3 so that's intersection
Talk about difference
Differences
From first set what is difference as compared to the second one
That is done by using the minus symbol
Look at the first set and the second set the second set will only check the difference for
What is there not there in set
So that is 1 and 2 so this will give me
Difference of set 1 and set 2 which is 1 and 2
So if I run
Baby I have an output which is one too so that's the difference between set one and set two
So we created
Union using the pipe
We created the intersection using and
And we created a difference using minus so that those are basic
Set operations that we have
I'm going to come in this out
Save it close it
Because next
You're going to jump into our hands on exercise
Exercise one
Is the manipulate data in a dictionary
The objective here
Is practice adding removing and modifying key value pairs in a dictionary
So first what we'll do is we'll create a dictionary to store information about a person
Will perform different operations like adding a new key value pair
For the person's address
Danville modify the
Lucky today and will remove the great key
If it exists
So let's go ahead
Create a new file
Colorado python file
Save it inside day for
Call it exercise one
And here
473 dead person
Do you value pear
Is
Al
Next I'm going to say the age of this person
Is 25
Next time I want to give a grade
And the grid is a grade
So this is my personal the first thing that I want to do
Add
So as I mentioned you know first thing that I want to do is add an address
Sexy person
Address
Equal to
Main Street
So that's the address for Alice
Next I want to update
Call
San Jose update is
So I'm going to say person
From 25 I'm going to change her age to 32
Next if there's any grade I want to remove those
Grades from the
Use the so I'm going to check if
The different way of doing
In person just checking if the key exists
With grade
What do I want to do
I want to delete
Person
So next
I am going to say so once I'm done with
Deleting this let's print this person out
What kind of completes are in dark exercise where we have created a dictionary with three keys with
Share values
And we added a new key value pair and address to
This person
You get the age of Alice to 32 from 25
And then we saw this great that is existing we removed it from The Weeknd
Print this here first to check and then after our operations
Let's check it again
So let's go ahead
Clear this out
And say
Lights
Exercise 1.54
Your name Al
Is 25 grade A
Then we added
Address 123 Main Street is there
Updated the age from 25 to 32 so that's there
And then we removed grade if it exists so
Remove that grade here so that's our
Great exercise one if you had any issues or problems let me know and I'll get back to you and let's get to
Exercise 2
Which is the frequency counter
The objective here is to write a program
That takes a sentence
And returns a dictionary
With the frequency count of each word
So what we do is we'll take a user input for a sentence here
Then we'll split the sentence into words
And then we'll count the occurrence of each word and store the counts in a dictionary
So let's go ahead
And you can follow along
If you had any problems let me know in between but
I'm going to start
Exercise 2.0 Ty
NC
First let's take
Sentence
As input from our user I'm going to say
Sentence to the user
Let them enter give us the input
Then I want to just write this down split
Now that can be done by
Creating an office first apparently of the variable
Words which is a list
Not to this list
I'm going to call the split function
So what this does is split function it will take a particular sentence
And split it and put it inside this words
What's left so that's what it will do
Next let's initialize the dictionary
Initialize
Empty dictionary to do that
I am going to say word underscore count
Equal to mg dictionary
Next now I want to count
The word
Frequency
So do that do that I am going to say for
In our words list
I'm going to go through each and every word
And I was a word equal to
Dark Lord because the user might have entered the same word for example
I can say
AI in Capital Area in small couple of times and then it would
Take the match to different words
So I'm converting to lowercase for case insensitivity here
Next I'm going to check
If
Invert underscore Council checking if this
What has been counted before if it has been
Counted before
I am going to say
Underscore
For that particular word
I want to increment
The number to
I'm going to say
Underscore count
For this new word that we
Came across
I am going to see if equal to 1
And that's it
So let's go ahead
And print
Word count at the end
So there you go so we have
Code ready here
Let's run
And play with it so I am going to clear this out
Pyth
Exercise 2.0
Enter the sentence so I'm going to say
The AI
Engineer
Is the
Future
It says the comes twice because one with capitalized one without capitalized
Yeah I want engineer ones is Once and Future ones list
Give a bigger one I said
Engineer is the
Engineer of the
Future
Who
Work on different
Project
And
Amazing
But that's fine so there
3 * 8 is twice engineer is twice as you can see
From here to take those things and then give me
Word count are they here
At work on dictionary which is what we wanted to do so now we have our word frequency counter
Here I hope you were able to follow along
If you had any issues or problems let me know and I'll get back to you
Next for some additional practice I recommend you can write a program
Reverse a list of
And remove duplicates using a set
Then another thing that you can do is create a program that stores
Grades in a dictionary and calculate the average
Tried
And let me know if you can
Get that working now to summarize on day 4
Get some hands-on experience working with python built-in data structures understanding their properties
Please and Performing operations on them
The handsome exercises insured practical application building a strong foundation for handling
And organizing data effectively in Rye projects