Day five
Working with strings
First you're going to cover
Stream manipulation today
You're going to look at
First thing which is concatenation
Concatenation is process of combining multiple strings using the plus operator
All the joint method you use the plus operator couple of times earlier but let's go ahead and look at how it looks like
I'm going to create
The new python file
I want to see if this inside my week
Day 5 and call it
Day 5
Underscore
I'm here
I can create a string first
Which is let's call it
Hello
And then I'm going to create another variable
String which is
Concatenate these two together I can see a result
Equal to First
Plus I want
Space between them so I'm going to say space empty space
And
Now this when I
Print it out
I will say hello space world
Nuclear this
CD dot dot
And I have my day five strings here
I want to see python
Day five
Think I spelled python wrong
Go again and it says hello
Which is output of this so this is how you can combine multiple strings
Using the plus operator
In this particular case
Next
You look at slicing
No slicing is the process of extracting parts of a string using indices now we have done this with less
Earlier but let's look at how we can do this using someone
Common desert and how we can do it for Strings
What is a text variable
And call it
Python
Program
Now I want to just print python in this case
So I can see from text
I want to see from index 0 up till 6
So 012345 I don't want to 61
So that's why I said 026 not the 6th one
You can also have
Specify that you want to see programming
By saying
-11
Colon to the end of the space
So what it does is in this particular case is going to go until the 11th my negative
And then print the rest of the characters so let's go ahead
And you'll see for this one it was Python and for this one two three four six seven
891011 so this is -11 index
And until the end of it so that's why it's giving me programming
So next
Let's look at formatting
You can use the F strings
Or format
For dynamic string creation we already use the F string bunch of times
Which is let's go ahead
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a string called as name as
Alice
An age equal to
Now I can use the F string which is the format string
And I can say my name is
Inside this specify name so the curly brackets
Are used for variables
And I am
Yes
What is the sentence that I create now if I run it
I get my name is Alice
And I am 25 years old so this is very important
Betty
Formatting technique that we use while working with string so make sure that
You get used to this and you'll be using quite a lot as and when
We progressed through our boot camp
Let's look at
Common string Methods
We have split
Which splits a string
Into a list based
List based on a delimiter so you can specify like if you don't specify anything it will use
The default delimiter space
But if you specify a particular delimiter like pipe or comma for CSV files you can use
And split a particular string and put it inside
List of items
You also have joined with joints elements of a list into a single string and we have
Replace which replaces the substring with another one
Another one that you want to look at is strip
This removes white spaces or specified characters from the beginning and end of
So let's go ahead and play with these
1 * 1,200
And delete everything
And first let's start with
Split
Which is
Something
Like this
Now if I have a sentence so for example
Sentence equal to
Python is
Now I want
This based on the spaces that
But it has
You can say sentence
Dot split and as I mentioned default is
Space so when I bring the words
Get it
Is a python is sponsored created a list
With each one of them based on the space here now if I had
Oh comma here
I can specify that comma is my delimiter
Give me the same thing python is
And uses that as a delimiter
Next that I want to show is
Joe
So that is
Join this is the function which joints elements of a list into a single string so to do that
For example now whatever words I have here which is python
Is fun let's move it back to the original one
It looks simplest
So I have this
Words
If you want to join it into a sentence I'm going to say a sentence or send you
Sentence
Equal to
I want to say join
And let's print it out
San Jose print new
Send it
Go
Set python is fun
It took the entire thing
And join the words together
Using space because that's what I've created here and created this if I give pipe
Say python pipe is pipe fun so that's how you can use this joint which again
Joints elements of list into a single
Next thing that you want to look at is the place which replaces the substring with another
So let's create a new one I am going to
Common the Sprint
Common the Sprint and I am going to create
Text
It says
I love
That's a jav
And then I'm going to create another variable
Updated text
And you probably already
Figured out what I want to replace what do I want to replace
I want to replace Java
Lights on no think about it you have a book on Java and you replace everything that's a Java in there with python
It becomes Java programming to Python programming
Will that not be easy but again
Python is much more easier
That's why I love python
Updated text
If I run this
I love by Tony Stark I love Java because Java got replaced by python
Similarly the last one that you're going to talk about this trip which removes white spaces or specified
Play characters from the beginning and end of the string
Space space space space space space space space space
Hello comma
And I have space space space space space space space space space at the end of it
Now I can say clean
Equal to I can give that message
Nobody thought it will remove all the spaces from front and back
So I'm going to say give me
Find me the play clean
Can you take
I have another one I'm going to
Commanders just so that we just say hello world
Yes all the space has been removed
If I just
What is
I just print
Messi first just to see the difference
This is my message thing with the space in front and back
And this is my clean up sandwich has no spaces in front and back so that's how strip works
Next thing that we're going to talk about is
Regular expressions
For pattern matching of this is very interesting and is used quite a lot if you've done any bit of programming you know how important
Now what are the Expressions it's a way to search
Matt and manipulate text based on patterns
For example you know email is a particular pattern and where you look for
Text in the start
At the rate sign and the domain name
Something calm
AI or got anything and then so it's a particular pattern that you're falling so it's helpful
To search and match and also manipulate
Text based on particular patterns that's where we use
Regular expression
The thing that we use
Does a module available
It's called the re module a regular expression module
We import the regular expression module
400x operations the way to do it is something similar to Matt that you're done before
Where you can just say
Import
Audi vehicle that side
Module that you would want to
Want to import when we using regular expressions
Some of the common functions that are available in the regular expressions
Are you not search will you give the pattern
End the string
So what it does is
It searches
For a pattern in that particular strengths so if you have like
A big huge document full of string and you want to find
Emails in that in that particular string so you can give a pattern
I'm looking for email style pattern inside that string and pass it there and it will give you
Another thing that we have is find all
Which actually finds all the patterns all the currencies of a particular pattern
In the first case it will get you the first one
But find all the list you all the currencies of that particular pattern
Next we have
Audi.com
Is substitute which means is replaces
Occurrences of a particular pattern
So let's try out some examples where we can use the regular Expressions so I'm going to go
Go ahead and create
I'm going to call it
Day
Underscore
Rejects Dot py
Here first as I mentioned
We need to import Ari which is our module for regular expressions
Now I want to create a string here
Which
Contact me at 1:23
You know that's my phone number
So what I'm going to do is I'm trying to find all the digits in a particular string
To do that I can just say digit
Equal to Ari
Dot as I mentioned
Find all is the function
And here I'm going to see the rejects that I'm trying to look for
This is the pattern
Slash the which is digit
More than once if it appears just display me those
And inside my text
Show print
Digits
So what it will do is it will try to look for digits either one or more than one because I've said last year
So
Is the 456 and then 7890 because there's dashing between them
That's why it will separate them out so I am going to go here
Clear this out
Madison python
Big 5 underscore
Rejects Indigo 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
90 so that gave me found me
All the digits that are there one two three four five six and 7890
Now what if I want to replace all the digits
With X for security purposes
So I can say updated
Underscore text
Equal to r e as I mentioned so which substitutes numbers now I'll have to first give the pattern
Whenever there's a digit now in this case I'm not going to say plus because if I say plus it will replace one two three as a sing
Rolex but I want every single digit so
Is one digit 2 is 1.12 so I'm not giving the plus sign
So and then I said that I want to replace with x
And what is my
Text this is the text that I want to do it on
And I want to say print
Updated text
So you can probably see what is the use case for this
Price for privacy reasons
You want to hide your email or phone numbers or anything that you have in the text
Xxxxxxx
Best XXX at least I know it's in the right format of a telephone number
And it's been replaced by X Whenever there is a digit in here
So try to play around with different
Functions like these all the different patterns that are available and let me know if you are able to do something
Let's jump into our hands on exercise
Google create a text cleaner
The objective here
Is to write a program
That removes unwanted characters example punctuation Extra Spaces
Is from a particular string
Take a string as input from the user
And then
Will remove the punctuation Extra Spaces and convert the text to all lowercase
So let's start with the project of an exercise one
45 I'm going to save it as
Exercise 1.3
I'm here
I would need
Was regular Expressions to do the
What substitutions
And I'm going to create a function called it
Clean the text
And whatever text is provided here
The first
As I mentioned I want to remove
Punctuation
Section for that
I will first say
Text
I want to create a new variable text
I want to substitute
Now in this case
I use on now for punctuations
I will use the square bracket
And I'll use the
Are
And say - W - suspicious and Furniture if you see this it says
Returns the string obtained by replacing the left most non-overlapping occurrences of the
Pattern listing the replacement RTL so that's what this does
So I am going to go ahead and say replace those with
Nmt
And for operations this is the text that I want to operate on
Set remove all the punctuations from the text that is there
Next I want to remove
Extra pieces
Now for the moving spaces I want to send a text
Equal to
Where is the space join
Text
Dot split
So this will split my ENT
Remove all the spaces and then join them with spaces just to clean it up
And finally
I will say
Convert
2 lowercase
So this will return
Mike text that I've created
Call the lower function that is a built-in function that converts the text into lower and that's what
Will be returned
Now let's instead of asking user that's a creator
Input texture but you can ask the user for a text to you already know how to do it
Houston Space
Hello world
And then I'll say I'll put some exclamation marks here
Welcome to
Python comma
Programming dot dot dot
Play some more spaces
And I'll see screen text
Equal to call the function clean text
Intuit
Fast
Input text
And then
Elsa print
Text
Is
Let's hope that it shows me hello world welcome to Python program
I mean all in lowercase and without any punctuations and spaces so I'm going to run this
India the name of the file is exercise one
Is it python
Exercise 1.5
Hello world welcome to python
Programming
It got me
The entire thing all lowercase and cleaned up the entire
Text for me perfect
So next thing that I want to do is
Exercise 2 which is
Check if a string is a palindrome
And a palindrome
Is a word a phrase or sequence that reads the same backward as well as forward for
Example madam
M a d a m
Which reads same from front or back
So that's a palindrome so or another example
That I can give you is if it's
That's a sentence says A Man A Plan A Canal
Panama
That is actually a palindrome because
The other way is also reached the same thing A Man A Plan A Canal Panama
Let's go ahead and
A new file for this
I'll call it
Exercise
History of one I'll call it to
And here
I'm going to check first
So this function
Is going to check
Is
And it needs an input parameter is a text
And your first time I'm going to remove all the
Non alphanumeric characters and convert to lowercase to do it in one single line and do something like this
Character
Don't know what
In the text that is passed
Is character
Dot is
Addison numer
So this goes to the entire text and then convert them remove all the non alphanumeric characters
And convert everything to lowercase
Next thing I'll do is return
Text
Equal to
Colin colon
-1
What this does the destructive the text is equal to its reverse
And if it is
Then it's going to say true
If it's not it's going to say fall so this by saying this text colon colon -11 is going to reverse the text and check
Thank you both of them look exactly same
So even if it's like Madame versus A Man A Plan
Remove the spaces and make sure that it's
Exactly the same strings front or back
So that's what it does so now let's create
Input underscore texture
I'm going to ask the user to enter in this particular case so we can
Try a bunch of different ones
Listen
Is
Palindrome
Whatever my
Input text is that user provided
I'm going to say print
I need to display that
So I'm going to use this
Photos under quotes
And pass the input text
When I say
Palindrome
And if not
I will use
Elsa print
Not a calendar
So let's try it out
Go ahead
Did everything
And say bye
Exercise 2.0 by
So first one let's keep it simple Madam Madam is a palindrome and say
Madden
Python Nexus 2 made in
Is not a palindrome because it doesn't read the same
Next one is as I mentioned a man
I'm sorry
Run this function first
A
A plan
Canal and make sure that I don't do any
Panama so if you see a man
Canal
P a n a m a
Got it
Is a palindrome because if you read it out if this check if you remove all the commas and spaces
And if you read it out
It's exactly the same
From front versus Reaver
Davis we have our court here which
If you were able to do both these exercises that's good if not if you had any
Issues or problems let me know in my messages and I'll check them and get back to you
For some additional practice
You can try to write a program
To count the number of vowels in a string
Find it
Next you can create a program
To find and replace all email addresses in a text using Rejects
So answer that you can always go online and just search for
Rejects expressions or rejects creators and you'll find some projects
Creators online where you can test it out and then use it in your code
And they have one more
Which is the right program to reverse the word in a sentence not the letters the words in a sentence
So try that out and let me know if you have any problems
Suggest to summarize on day 5
We did some practical experience in working with string mastering common methods
And learning to use
Regular expressions for text processing task
Now these skills are essential for natural language processing NLP and that's why we went through these and also
So for data cleaning in your applications
If you had any issues or problems let me know right now because these are the basic foundational
Thanks for function that we need to do for NLP and