Welcome to day6
Today we are going to cover
File hand
No specifically
File handling in Python is much more easier with all the functions that are available
We will start with
Reading and writing
Text friends
First thing here you want to look at
Opening fights
Open files you can use the built-in open function
Open a particular file
Now when you open a file usually you have to specify the dried or you want to append something or
Read and write
More that you have
Critically specify here
So we have different modes
The default mode is read
Which you can also specify by the letter r
We have the right mode which overrides the file if it already exists
Which you can use the W keyboard
We have a
Which adds data
To the end of the file you can use a for that
And finally we have read and write which is R Plus
Which you can use if you want to read and write a particular file after you open it
So this was about opening files how about reading files
You can use the dot read
To read the entire file cont
But if you want to just read one line at a time you can use
The dog treat line function
And what if you want to read all the lines
So you can use read lines
What it does is
It gets all the lines
And gives you a list of the entire writer
If you want to see an example of how this works I'm going to create a new file here
And save it inside my day6 I'm going to call it
Day6 samples
Want to start with something called is a bit statement which we talked about in a little while
But to open a file I say open
And I give the name of the file let's say
Sample dot txt that's the name of the file
Now you have to specify here as I mentioned earlier
The different modes for opening a file
Is
I did read
Or a pen
Or read and write
And I'm going to say read this as a file
So this will be my file that has all the contents of whatever
I've opened here
And then I'll take content I want to get that content I'm going to say file
So once I open the file as a file
I am going to take that file and then read it
Now this will read as I mentioned the entire file content into one single variable which is
And you can just say print
Contentious
Now what if you want to read only one line you can just say
No the thing with red line is it's always used with the loop
Very Loop through each line at a time and do process the content
But sometimes you just want to read the first line or one line then you just use replay
Also we have these lines which will give a list so this content will be a list of each and every line
That this file has
So that's how you use open and read
Now let's go ahead and look at writing to files
Now to write two files
You use the function dot right
Which writes a string to a particular file
You can use the right lines
To write multiple lines from a list if you have a list of items
And you want to write them to a particular file you can just say right lines and it will take each and every item
So the way to do this is
You specify that you want to write to a file
And here instead of this I'm going to comment this out
What is a file
Can I have object that I have I'm going to write to it
And I want to write something like
Hello
So that's what I'm doing right now if I want to write
Multiple lines I can just say file
As I mentioned Dot
And here I give a
Area of items I'm going to say
Alice
Something
So this will write take this list of items and write these in different lines
Inside a particular file that's how write lines work and write works
So next let's look at
Using which statements for file management we already used it
But how does it work
And first of all what is the width statement
Now this ensures that files that you opened
Are properly closed after the operations even if
An exception occurs so make sure that something is not going right and your program
Can crashes it will make sure that the file is still properly saved and secured
And it does you don't lose the content that you're working on so that's what the statement does the Syntax for this is I
You can just continue here
Specify with so as I mentioned it with
And then
You say open
A particular file
Which we have done already here
So as a particular file
So what this does is
At the end of it here
Is
Automatically
So this will make sure that the file that you open in this case are sample dot txt file is automatically closed
And you don't have to worry about closing it in some programming languages you'll probably have to close an open file
But in Python if you use with
You don't have to close the specific
So what are the advantages
Off using
This particular
Bed as I mentioned it ensures files are properly closed after operations even if an exception occurs
The advantages include
It simplifies the code making it much easier you don't have to remember to close the file and also
It reduces the risk of file corruption
So if you have a file open and operations are going on and things are happening it might cut up a particular file so making
Making sure that every time no matter what programming language you use
You open a file you have to close it so that's what
Make sure
So that's why I always using with is a very good
Best practice
Next
You don't look at basic exception handling for file operations
Why use exception
What does it prevent the program from crashing due to files related errors example file not found or
What is a file issue
File is corrupt or file has some problems
Or it is not readable by that particular user so they can be a bunch of different
Problems made access a letter or maybe the file is not there so having
Exception handling helps you make sure that your court doesn't crash
And move to the next line or exits gracefully depending on what you're trying to do
So that's why exception handling is important
We use something called as the dry except blocks
So let's jump into
How to use the triceps block
So I am going to quickly write some code here I said try this is how you start with
And then inside here
You start with
Open the file
So for example sample dot txt file I want to open
I want to open it and read more
As file
I want to take the content
From that file
Answer file
Comment all these things here because I think
Scott mess
So I'm going to say comment
I'll just get rid of
And here
5.3 now
If this doesn't work out
If it breaks
I have to do exception handling
Except
Not found
If the file was not formed because there is no file called a sample.to it will crash in our case
So that's why exception handling here
And I'm going to give an ER
Do I use just saying file not
Something like this
So what happens in this case is I'm trying to open this file
But if the file doesn't exist I don't want this application to crash I want to just print a message saying
File not found
So some of the common
File note or common file handling exceptions
Include we have file not found error which we just saw where the file does not exist
We sometimes look for permission error
Where the user doesn't have sufficient permissions to access the particular file
And then finally also the io error
Play gentle input output errors
Where you look for all kinds of editing permissions or input output address so that's what
You're looking iOS
So now that we understand how to open the file read a file go through a file to exception handling let's
Play jump into
Some Hands-On exercise
Are first exercise today
Is to count the words and lines in a particular file
So the object to hear is to write a program to read a text file
An output the number of words and lines
So the instructions that I would probably follow here will be
Open the file in read mode first
Because you don't have to write something we just have to count the lines
Then we count number of lines using the loop
And then finally we'll count the number of words in each line using the split function that you used before
Let's go ahead and write some
Open the new file
I'm going to save it as
Day6
Exercise one
Now here
First let's write the function so I'm going to say
I always start with the function
The reason is
It's always helpful to reuse this somewhere else if I need this in future
Someone say count Words
Lions
And I'll pass it a file name
Now first thing is start always with the tracks of
Sunset
And unless you're
Open the file
I use that file name that is passed to me
And I'm going to say this is
Indeed only more
And take that and assign it to this variable file
So my file is available
I'm going to say Lyons
Equal to
Dot read lines
This is
I can read all the lights into a list of items so lines will be a list of items with
Call the Lions in
Next I'm listening line
Underscore counts I'm going to count the lines which is
Using the length function Len
And then say how many lines are there in this particular how many list of items are there inside
So that's what I'll get here
I'm going to say
Underscore accounts I need to get the word count
What is a sum
Line
Play Tamil explain you in a second of what I'm doing here
Line in lines
So I'm going to hear this I am writing a for Loop
Where I'm going to eat and every line inside the lines list so I'm going each and every item inside this
And I'm saying
A based on spaces so that will give me words
So this will give me the number of words that are
And then finally I'm serving all of them
To get the total word
So next step
How to say
Number of
Equal to
Use something similar but this time I was a number of words in there
No next
I will get outside
Of the try and try
The except
Phone so this file I'm not created yet
So this should if I run this
Statement or run this code it will just say file not found so I'm going to say print f
Specify what the file name is
So that's the error that I'll give the user so let's write
Right here outside some
To run dysfunction
Somerset count Words and lines
And I'm going to give a file called a sample Dot txt
If you look at my
Let's say open door this particular folder where we have
D6 code but there's no sample dot txt file here
If I run this code
Let's go ahead here
And then clear it out
Set python
Day6
Exercise 1 b y
File dot txt not form because there is no
File inside here that's called sample dirty so let's create one
So create one
Save
Sample Dot txt
And here I'm going to say
Hello world
How are you
What is the
Today
Are you working on
Technologies
So just some basic four lines of text
Now let's go ahead
And run this
And it says number of lines is 4 so 1 2 3 4
Number of words is 17 so if you count these words 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13
1415 season 17
So
Found the words and the lines and displayed out
So this is what we are expecting
What are the first exercise
So I hope you were able to follow along if not if you had any issues let me know
Now let's look at our second exercise
My second exercise is to write and read a list of items
So the objective here
Is to create a program
That writes a list of items to a particular file
Then reads it back and displays the content
So what we will be doing first is will write a list of items to file each on a new line
And then we'll read the file and display it
So which means we'll have to write a couple of functions one to write and one to read
So let's start with our exercise 2
Can you find
Save it as D6
Exercise
2.5
Let's imagine the first step
To write
Items
And then I want to know what is the file name that I want to save this
Whatever I want to write and what are the items that you want to write
Inside this function I'm going to first say I'm not using the try
Except but it's a good practice to always use that I'm just going to keep it simple and straightforward for now
Is your file name
As file
And then I'm going to say for item for each and every item that is passed in the items at least that we
I am going to say file
Not right lines but we can use directly right lines and use this but
I'm just going to show you how to use this for Loop
Item plus I want to do new line here so slash n
So based on whatever we get I want to write that line and then go to a new line
Next
Our next function that I mentioned was to read
Items
And then pass the file name
Because I have full access to this OS and I don't have to worry about
Any of the exceptions
Sometimes you might have to because what if you don't have the permission or access
But for read
I don't know if the file is available or not so that's why
I am going to use the
I accept
Open
File name
Comma I want to do it in the read mode
File so I get the contents of this file inside this file
The items
Equal to file
Daughter read all the lines not going to do one at a time
But all of them together
And then
I'll print
Sing items
For item in
Items for since I have all the items in there
I'm going to look through each one of them and print
Each item at a time
But I'll also
Strip those items if there's any spaces or anything so I don't have to worry about that
And then finally
My except block here
Which is only for file
I'm not looking for any other errors because I know that I have permissions I have
No input IO error operations
But again when production code you should try to catch all the exceptions that are
File name
She had no diapers
Okay that's perfect
No next thing is to test the functions
Someone say I want to see the items
Call Ed
Apple
Banana I'll call it
Fruits
Then we have
And that's a dates
Just for consistency make sure everything is capital here
And then first I'll write to a file so I'm going to say right items to a file
Now this doesn't exist
I want to call it fruit start
DxD this file doesn't exist if you see here
There is no
Food store txt I'm going to clear it out
And to this so right to file needs to parameters what is the name of the file
And the other one is the items which is my fruits
So that's once I've given that now next I want to read
Items from the file
In the file name that is same as this
Fayetteville perfect if I change the name to let the items dot txt let's see what happens just for the fun of it
Go
Again at least there's no file that says full stop txt right now
So now when I run this
Lights on
I'm going to call it what is the name day 6 and the score
Exercise 2.5
I just file items not found
It was not able to find that why because the name is fruits
But if I Alicia
You'll see I already have the first file
So that's why I got created and I'm very sure
If I open it it will show me the fruits that I've added but I am going to not
Run it that way I'm going to use my code
And if you see items in the file apple banana cherry and dates
And that's the fruits
5 years
I can always go ahead
Open
And open this file
And see it has these four items that I added so you can add more items
So think of it as like if you want to build something
Video caching items
Do you have local direct your users local computer
You can call Api get
The weather for
Countries of Honda cities
Save it locally and show that
Throughout the day
So then
The user doesn't have to call a particular API again and again for something
So that's where it can be helpful now in this particular case think of it is like if you're making an application
Where you are displaying different types of recipes
No you don't want to download the recipes from the website again and again
So you do it once save it on the local machine
And then let the user see it
So I hope you were able to work with this project and a follow along
If not let me know
But there's some additional work that I can give you for practice
First try to write a program
To copy the contents of 15 to another so
You create a file
Add some data there
Read the contents of that particular file first open the file read the contents
And then write to another file
Next
Create a program that counts the number of occurrences of a specific word in a text more like a search engine
Create a file where you add a bunch of texts inside
And then search for a particular text and see how many times it occurred
Next
Write a program to log messages with timestamps into a file
So this is a little bit different where we have not looked at how to write timestamps but you can use some python built-in function
Can I let you do the research of how to get
The current time so what are you going to do is ask users some input
And then when the user enters something on the command prompt
Save them as a log message inside of a particular file and also put the time when the user entered
And then run a while loop through it and constantly lock these messages
So to recap
Today
We learn
The essential file handling techniques in Python
Including reading and writing files
Managing files
By using which statements
Handling exceptions gracefully
These skills are vital for data processing task in the AI and Beyond so we'll probably be using this quite a lot
Let me know if you have any questions or any problems and I'll get back