In this section
We are going to learn
What are the components of the AI agent
How to read an AI
That means we will need time into core component
Animal movie from the birthday of the architect
To the underground theme of the engine
To do this on Route me for this section is
Is methodical
Coconut by coconut and deep
Bill dedicate one full section
Each part of these agents anat
So we will start by the foundation model
What we can say 11 or we can call is at the brain
And continue to perception model
We can call as
Continue to Planet model
We can call it
What is the strategist
And continue to memory model
We can call as a notebook
And continue with the action model
Which represent
And continue to learn
Which is
Repeat that
And continue to communication
Which is all the
These are the seven steps for
Road map of this
So let
Let me start brief
In this section what we are going to
Step by step
So our initial lectures will focus on the
Thinking
Read the foundation
Which is the L
And
What's the trade off of choosing a
Powerful
What is a small first and local
Then we will dive into the perception
We will Define the trigger for the AG
We will discuss
Have an agent in
A normal
Messi realtor
Into a clean format
The alarm can understand
After
We will dive into planning
This is a key lecture
We will show how you pronounce
Listen to make it decomposed a goal into steps
Rather than just answer
And after that we have a major lecture on memory
Where we will architecturally comp
Play short-term contacts window memory
Persistent long-term memory like Victor data
And we will have a critical lecture on action and Tool calling model
We will look at the actual mechanism of the function calling
And more importantly
The guardrail and security Pat
What's the most beautiful
So this is
Are mean and
Thinking
Put a particular AG
After we have with our code
And we will look at the two Advanced system
First of all
The learning and adaptation
We will architecturally Define the crit
Which is the component that avoid perform
What's on the learning element
Which is the mechanism that updates
It's the agents log
And after that we will focus on the communication
This is two-part log
We will discuss the simple agent to human communication
Hobbit format tonight to clean answer
And you will intro
The far more complex top