In this video
We are going to Deep dive into the anatomy of Nia agent
And we must
Not with the single most important component
Which is the
In all architect
This is the foundation model
Almost always a large language model
What we can call Islam
If you think of the entire agent is a complete computer system
Don't remember
Will be the
And the tool model
Is the Philippines
Like the keyboard on the network
And the alarm is the CP
It is the central processing unit
It doesn't store the memory or perform the action
But it executes to log
Disconnect
Mix all other component
So now let's provide a simple and formal explanation
What is a foundation model
For all purposes
You can't take it as a universal pattern recognition and prediction engine
It has been
I think on the data
Which is Mass
Play diverse data
From the internet
Books on code
Anita's learn to deep statistical pattern of human language log
Make an event number of the topics
It is most basic skill is simple
Tubid
Next most logical word in a sentence
What we can call the next
What is we discover
When is prediction is done
It stops looking like simple prediction
And starts to look a lot of like reasoning
Uncomfortable
Is Arctic
Our job is to
Which is Rob capability
So now let's understand
How an alarm enables reasoning
This is the most critical concept to grab
How do you take
Next predictor and make it reason
We do this
Sophisticated front engineer
We don't
Just ask the alarm equation
The
Eat on how to think
The system from we give our agent is like it is operating system
Define
I think it's personal
And most importantly
It is reasoning Pat
There are two primary patterns we used to HD
These are the Chain of Thought and react
So let
Explain the first reasoning pattern
Which is the Chain of Thought Pat
The example
Please show me your work on a math problem
Explicitly instruct the alarm
Do you think step by step
These simple instructions for sale
To generate
It's on internal reasoning process
Before it gives a final answer
Look at the example we
Turn off the address
It just says
And this is not helpful
Instead of that we said that thing step by step
Restart listen
So here you can see an example of the thinking step by step
For the should I
Make an umbrella in London
After sending this
Alarm start listen
First alarm think
Do you use it once a recommendation
And this required moving to weather
And the weather in London
Light
On light rain Burns and umbrella
Therefore the answer is yes
As you can see that it
PlayStation thinking process
And for the gold bass agent
This Jenner
Make a Chain of Thought
It is multi-step learn
Later we will see debt
Beatrix button in the next
So now let's understand
How to choose an alarm
Which is our brain
Is an
Make your choice of alarm is one of the most critical design decisions you will make
This Choice defines almost everything about your agent's performance
Operating
What's under
You are always balancing in three way Traders
The first one is
Probability of quality of reason
How smart is the brain
Can it follow complex
10 step learning
What does it get confused
And the second one is the
How much does each call to the llm cost
Since an agent may make 10 or 20 calls for 1:30
These eggs
On the
Repeat or latency
What does the agent think
A 30-second delay is unacceptable for a customer service agent
You can almost
Never have all three options
You have two choice
So is our
Is Hurricane choice these things
So first of all
How we can
Is this options one by one
Are option one is
You optimized for maximum capability
You choose another like GT5
This gives you the smartest brain
The best at following complex plans
But it comes with at the high school
On the highest
It is a heavy thinking brain
And if you continue to option to which is the
You optimized for Speed and low cost
In this option
You can choose a model like Gemini flash or an open source model like
Level three
These are the Blazing fast and very cheap to
They are perfect for conversation AG
But they may make more mistakes
I can feel it highly complex 10 step
And we can also create option 3
Which is the you can optimize for
Privacy
You choose to
An open source model for yourself
This option gives you full data control
Which is not negotiable in feets
Husky or
The trade-off is that you know bare the full infrastructure
Put on maintenance cost
Which is significant
The brain you choose
Is the character of your Android agent
So is it somebody we can say that
The alarm is the
What's CPU or reasoning engine
We control this engine
When using the prompting pattern
Chain of Thought and Jack
And the choice of the alarm
Is a critical architectural trade