In this video
We are going to continue our
We are at the second step
Which is a perception and the Sens
In the last lecture
DSW
The core brain of the our agent
Which is the foundation model or an alarm
We now have a powerful reasoning engine
Which is a CPU and ready to drink
But everything
Normative how powerful is
It is useless
If it is isolated from the world
It needs a way to receive information
Now we will architect those
This component the perception model
Which is the
What's inter
Is to the river
It is the
13.4 old agent in Behavior
So let me explain perception
Is it today
We will see the agentic process is a
Including to Percy
Reason and
The perception phase is it still good that initiates
This entire SE
It is
Knock on the door
Did the next AG
And gives it a reason to think
No is our
You must understand that a perception
It's not just a user typing
A perception is
Any event
The agents known environment
It could be Drake command or it could be an asynchronous
Like an API call returning its data
Or any email arriving in an inbox
It can even be time-based trig
Like a chrome
Does big station at 9 a.m.
This model is the front door for all incoming data
And this brings us to the court challenge of this component
In the alarm is a magnificent text processing engine
It stinks in a clean logical textile circumcises
How
The real world is not clean
Subtract your
It is a messy unstructured and multiple
An input could be users chat message with typos
It could be 100 page PDF document
It could be a complex 5 MB
Jason
Clothes from an AP
It could be an image of a broken product
Or another file from a customer service call
Are elephant brain cannot understand any of these raw data in its native format
It's our job to do it tomorrow
The
What is des
So we will do this
Beat using to perception model
That
The primary function of the perception model is translation
It is job to act as an interpreter between the messy
And the clean
Do you call this process
Normalization
This model is a pipeline of smaller tool
You can see the image on this light
Which is basically
Play translation process
Handled by the perception model
So when it rece
What is anime
It doesn't test
Switch to the alarm
It was one the image through a vision model
To get a text Dez
Kitchen off that I'm
And
Next description is
What did Olympus
If it receives a hundred pages of PDF
Extraction Library
To Secretary of
If it
Is an audio file
Is it supposed to text model
To get
So
Ensures that
By the time the data reach the brain
It is the only format to bring understand which is the clean and legible
So it is important to know that llm only understand their environment
With the text input
Andy translation do by the perception model
So now let's go to some architectural examples
Is the multimodal support
Imagine that a support agent with two senses
These are the checkbox
Add an image upload but
The user perceives by typing
My knee shirt has a hole in it
You can notice the typos in here
And after that the user purchase by uploading the short photo
You can see
Play son
When is
Answer is uploading an
And the perception model
Gets
It is takes processor cleanse the type of
An
Is Vision Processor
What's the image through a model
And get a text description
You can see the
Is the typo analyze the image
I'm returning to
And finally the model freezes these input
Into a single
Clean prompt for the alarm
An airline can understand
Please text message from the perception
And the brain doesn't receive the wrong message data
And it received a perfect
Normal
Summary of the old perceptions
Allowing it to immediate start reasoning about the actual problem
So is there somebody we can say that
Perception is
The start of the agentic
And it was handled Messi multimodal unstructured data
And it is job is normalization
Translate into word into