In this video we are going to continue our road map
Which is the planning
This is straight
Are agents can now ingest
Clean and understand
The message
It has a brain
Which is the L
Uncensor
Which is the odd perception model
When can only perceive is just a sensor
It is a passive
The agency of Demands
We move from the Perce
To the reason and
So this picture is about that critical reason
But we are going to Define
Play BTS Pacific architectural output
Which is the plan
So this is the model that function
What is the AG
Strategies for blueprint generator
So now let's see the core problem
Which is the decomposing complex calls
So this model exists to solve a specific problem
Which is the comp
Doesn't give an agent simple one step command
They give us the comp
Who is the
Like book my complete trip to the London next
What are agents cannot achieve this goal in a single action
It is a great project
Is required multiple tools and multiple steps
The first thing an agent must do after perceiving this goal is to break it down
It must decompose
This complex project
Into a sequence of simple executable
This process
Is the core of agentic intelligence
And they call it planning or test decomposition
So first of all
Let's be very clear about
What is a plan architecture
Evelyn is not the final answer to the user
A plan is a data structure
Typically a list or a
This represent a sequence of future action
It is the blueprint that will be
Hand it off to the next model
Which is the action
A simple chat
He's not playing
You asked me to book my trip and it fail
What an AG
Is planet module
And generate a
You can see in here
We can send the goal as a book my trip
And this will be start listening
I'm planning and decom
Does this operation
And it will
A list of the function calls
Is intent to make in order
And this
The sequence of tooth cause
Is the entire output of this component
You can see the image this will be reasonable about this
And decompose this goes into find available flights
Find hotels
Book flight
Book hotel and Son confirmation email
Sonal let's understand
How an alarm create
This
How do we get the alarm to prod
Is this
Instead of the just a cheetah answer
Basically the instructed
Do you use the
Is are decomposition engine
The magic is in the system prom
Hear how the architect that
First of all we provide the goal we received from the perception
And after that
Do you
A list
All available
The agent is allowed to use
And after that we basically instruct to eat as a
Step by step prom
On four
We command it to produce a plant to achieve the go
Using only the tools from
By doing
Is we are using the alarm
Roll reasoning power into a structured architectural
We are forcing it to be a
So now let's understand the
Next to the
These are the turn off
And Ari
When an agent creates a plan
It can do
In two primary
The first way and the simpler one
Which is the Chain of Thought
On which we can call as a static planning
Generate the ENT
What's the plan all at once
Before it ever takes
What's the first action
This is excellent
Predictable work clothes
Like all love example
Book flight
Then book the hotel
But the more powerful and the common method is
Which we can call Dynamic planning
Beat
The agent doesn't plan the whole trip advance
Eat plants only the very first step
You
Execute that one action
On Thursday
Disney data is
Put back into the loop
On the agent
Next step two
So now
Mercedes Rock the enemy planning in debt
Disconnect is the color of modern agentic
For example if you provide a
Book my trip to London
In the loop
The agents plan is just one
Which is the flight
Is exeggcute
Is Uncle Steve
A list of the flight
On Disney information
Is FedEx to the planet model
And after that in the loop to eat three
That's based on Disney's
It is the plan
What's Austin
Which flight they
It executed
I'm in the loop today
It persists the users answer
I need three plans again
I have now the flight ID
My next step is to call book flight
This plan
Connect to perceive and replant cycle
Is what allows an agent to navigate complex
Thanks unpredictable
Ask dynamically
So now let's be extremely clear about the architectural boundary
Is the critical architectural hand
Do Clinic modules
Is the thing to generate the
It is job is not the EXE
Go on the output of this component is the plan itself
Which is a subtracted piece of data
Usually Jason that say
Here's the tools I want to call and here are the parameters
And this bully print is 100 of to the next model in our agent autonom
And this is the separation of concerns for agent
The planet model
Decide what to do
On the Xbox
This separation is
Is what makes an agent's architecture testable