In this video
We are going to continue our road
We are at the first step
Which is the memory
Play on
Do you have now architected or agents
Which is the alarm
And it is
Which is the perception
And
Which is our Clinic
Are agents can perceive the
An English
Create a multi-step
But it is still missing a fundamental component
If you have a conversation with this AG
It has no memory
What do you say 3 seconds ago
For example
If it execute step one of the five step plan
It is no way to remember the
Turn off the step
When it is time to execute the step
So this is the Groundhog Day problem
Without memory every perception
Is a brand
Contacts list event
Today we will architect the solution
The agents notebook
It's memory architecture of these
So now let's understand the most critical architectural Khan
Which is the mem
But before that let's understand the core principles of the memory
There are two types of memory
We must design for two distinct types
Just like a computer
Is the RAM and hard drive
So first of all we have a short-term memory
This is the AG
Does working memory
What
Is conscience
It basically
What the agent is thinking about right now
For example the current user query the plan is just generated
The result of the last API
It is
But it is volatile and extremely Limited in
And the second time is we have a long-term memory
This is the AG
Persistent memory or it is Library
This is what it stores everything it is
Pause conversations
User preferences
And it is entire knowledge
It is best and permanent
But it is slower to access
An agent's intelligence
Comes from
How old is
Systems work together
So now let's understand
Short-term mem
In all architecture
This is physically implemented is the context window of the LL
This is the secret we have been discussing
What's the agents personal
Assistant
The immediate conversation history
And the result from any reason to call
But this component has a famous limitation
The contacts window problem
This is the single most
Most expensive and valuable res
What's our agent
It is finite
We cannot just stop a user's
Can you check history
Or 500 page financial report
Into the context window
It won't
And it would be prohibitively expensive
So this limitation Force us to have a long-term solution
Let's understand the long-term memory
Architecturally
This is an external
Assistant database
It is rolled to store all information the agent might need
Permanent
This incl
What's all past conversations
Specific user preferences
What is for example the US
Office is in the New York
Uses
Where's the window seat
On the large knowledge bases like Auntie document libraries
And this component is
Is what sold the context window problem
The agents brain
Doesn't need to hold all these information
You just
Need to be aware
This Library exist
And be given a
This is the RAM and hard drive working together
So now let's understand
How long term and the short-term memory
Play work together
That mean
How do we hard drive and RAM work together
So these two memories are connected by a process
And the process is called
Retrieval augmented generation or
This is a critical pattern that we will see in the next section
But now let's walk through this regular clothes into our use case
Basically in this step
Do you still ask a question
Did the lights on past knowledge
Here you can see use the Santa clarity into our system
In the state
The alarm which is our brain
Short-term memory
Perceive this crazy but realize
Is leg
What's the effect to answer
And it is plan
To find them
So in the step
The agent X by using a tool to search it is long-term mem
So basically
It is integrating with the knowledge base
In order to get the long-term memory
From using the red pipeline
An Interceptor the long-term memory
Which is the hard drive
Find the one living piece of the
And this will be
Heading to our
Which means in the step 5
This small relevant fact is
Loaded into short-term memory
Which is our contacts window and
On
We will send this to the alarm and get the responds
And the loop is repeat
The airline brain is
The original question
+ 335
So it can now generate a perfect
Take please answer to the
So by following This Record
We can able to work together
Short-term and long-term memory into our
So
You will see the direct
What is in the next section
What now let's understand architectural patterns for the long-term mem
And this brings us to our final and most important decision as are
Which type of the database
Do we use for our long-term memory
We have three main pattern
The first one is
Is key volume or document databases
These are excellent for stor
What are the facts about a US
Like the preferences
And for looking to chat history itself
And the second
Is a squad databases
This is our connection to the Enterprise
This is how agent can access
Is existing relational data
Like order history
Is product inventory
Or financial records
What's the name and the most critical type
Victor data B
These do not start
Play Store
They allow an agent to search for Symantec Khan
Not just key
When the agent need to find the living Chunk from
5,000 documents
To answer the question
It is using a vector dat
This is the core technology behind the
So now let's quickly understand what is the vector database
Victor dat
Is is a specialized database
Design the
Miniature
High dimensional vectors
Pictures of numerical representations
Does that capture the semantic meaning of data
The indexes and
Victor em
Thanks for fast retrieval and similar to search
And they also enable contextual search based on the meaning
Sing behind the data
Is it somebody we can say that
Memory is essential to break the Groundhog Day problem Loop
And the most Arctic two types
Short
Which is the contacts window
And the long
Which are the vector databases
And the process that connects
Is
Which is the ritual augmented generation Pat
That we will see in the next
On our choice for the long-term memory
Victor database
Or another database