In this video we are going to continue our road
We are at 85
And we are going to learn action model representing our
So we have now architect at the entire cognitive Loop in our
Are agent has its brain which is the alarm
Which is our perception model
It's the strategies
Which is our Clinic mad
And it is not
Which is our memory
So are agent can perceive the word
Create a plan
And remember it's history
But a plan is just a thought
It is a data structure
It is not in itself an
This lecture is about the final most critical step
It's about
How we give the agent
To execute
An effective real word
This is the
Into
Percy vision ecl
This is the action model
So before we start let's understand
What is a tool in all architect
A to
Is any external function or API dead
Play the arch
Explicitly give the agent permission to use
This is the component
That gives the agent its
This is what makes it a
A simple chatbot can talk about the weather in par
But an agent will get better
Can autonomy Savage the real live weather for
The tool can be as simple as local python function or as complex as a database query
Or cold today
Here you can find an example of tattoos
These are the get rid of function
Create a database
Send
Run python Secret
Call Google Calendar AP
So could you delete the alarm
Cannot run these tools it
The brain is
It can only ask for a tool to be
Here you can see the image in our example agent
You can see that
That we have complete 11
Tools and mem
We are going to go to
Action
To change this environment
Before that let's understand the mechanism of the function calling
This brings us to do technical Hall
How does it take space brain execute
Did a python
The answer
It doesn't
It generate a request
This mechanism
Which more than alarm support
Is cold as a function call
Sing Orton
It is a three-step handle
We tell the alarm about its
And you provide a Sikkim
Like a Json file
That list the
It is allowed to use
Like get rid of function
And the parameters it takes like location
And after that the second step
When the alarm
What's to use dies
It is output is not the
It is a structure Jason OB
You can see the image on the slide this is the plan from our last lecture
For example here you can see that behaved list of the
And the tools including the tool called
Which is the function
And the arguments paramet
Including our location information
On the third step or application code
Which is the action model
Is designed to intercept the
Pacific Jason
And eat pasta salad
Pause the Jason
An execute the real function
Let's understand this Loop in debt
Victorian Thunder
That
When is we will trace this flow
It is the core of the re
Which is the reason and action
So in the first
Play The Alarm which is our brain
Reason
Set it needs data
Is eggs by generating adjacent request
Is for the good weather to
On the second step
Are action model
Which is our orchestrating
Kiss this Jason
It sees the alarm is not talking
But requesting a to
The first
The AC model execute the actual python function
Which is the gate weather including our location information
I need the first
That function runs and return
Delete status
I need the first
The action model takes these results
Converting it to a simple text ring
Since it's back to the alarms perception model
For the next
And finally
Alarm
Which is our brain
Purchase Disney data and reason again
And this morning
A picture of for example
The weather in Paris
What's 15 centigrade and cloudy
Now I can ask for the user's question
So is it remember
Designing weather agent in the previous section
We basically sound like
Is unsend gold to our weather agent
And this will be a part from the video call to the R2 Corporation
Unreasoning again and returning a final answer
Unmute following the circular Instagram
Is following our agent in
Calling to our tools and returning the alarm at 11:23
When finish this
An old dysfunction calling an extra model comes with the most important topic
Which is the security
Do you speak as the most critical topic of this course
An intersection security and guard
With great power comes with the great responsibility
The moment we give an agent a
We are giving an autonomous
Is Nan determin
A key to our house
So what could possibly go wrong
The nightmare scenario is simple
An engineered gives an agent a
Clean up the old us
Is from the test database
But the agent in its reasoning process
Forms a logical
Call the delete users Comm
But it accidentally Target
Is the production database
So our job is our
It's not just
Does to enable to
Are primary job is to design guard
Does that make this kind of failure impossible
So now let's understand
Add architectural garden
The implement this security using
Three primary architectural podcast
The first one is the principal
List three
Just like in Cloud security
Play we never give an agent a master
If it's the weather AG
The only tool it should have access to East Gate weather
You should not have
Send email function
On the
We must be extremely careful about
Read only versus
Write access
Getting an agent
YouTube like create a database
Is is generally safe
Giving it a right tool like the late record
What is inherently dangerous
On the third one leads are most important Pat
Turn which is the human in the loop pattern and confirmation
For any sensitive
Destructive action
Sending an email deleting a
Spending money
The agent cannot Act auten
It is plan is treated as a suggestion
Our system passes to Loop and presents the plan to a human operator for a simple approve or Den
This is the ultimate guard
So is there somebody we can say that
The action model gives the agent
And makes it agentic
The function cooling mechanism
Is the technical Beach from the brain to the hands
Insecurity is not a
It is the core of these models design
Implemented V