In this video we are going to continue our road map
We are
Which is the learning model
Include the feedback
So let's get started
Did you cancel that our agent has the
Which is the alarm
Which is our perception model
Is this strategies
Which is
Reasoning and planning model
And we have a note
Which is all memory module
And we have
Once these are
The tools and action model that far from the action
So that
Behavior complete or
Perceive reason
Sing an action
I know all agent can execute
But
What is 1 + 1/4
If its plan is inefficient or it's remembered
What's in its memory are wrong
It will continue to make the same mistakes forever
It is no mechanism for self-improvement
We will add a final and most advanced component
We will build a second Loop
If you'd like
Did I lost the agent to learn from
It's mistake
And get smarter over time
Can you cancel
We are going to The Learning model
To able to making some music again and again
So now let's understand
Tulip architect
To understand this we must think in terms of the two Loop architecture
In the room
Which is the performance element
Or we can
The ACT
This is the entire agent we have just designed
Which monster pairs
Reason an egg
We call this loop as a performance
And which is the act
And this job is to Simply to do things in the world
On the second
Which is the
Higher
Assistant we are adding today
And this is the learning element or the updater
It is only job is to observe and improve the ACT
This is the metal Loop that enables the self improve
So now let's understand the architectural component
Which are the
I'm learning
Delete the second
Are architecture
Specialized component
These are the
Speak and learn
Let's start with the first one which is the crit
This is the elevator or teacher
It is just to watch the October perform a
I need to look at the out
Turn on generate a feedback signal
A simple
That
Is that was a good action or that was a bad action
In this critic phase
Is the agent
Did my last action achieve its intended sub
What did it
Was this action efficient
What is action actually help me achieve the overall user
You can see the
We basically performed the crit
When the action is happening
According to outcome of these action oper
On the
Which is the learning element
And this is the mechanism or we can say engine
It received the grade from the critic
Performs the actual engine
Work of the updating the agent
So it is the company that physically rewrite the rules or updates the memory
So now let's understand and deep dive in the critic model
I understand
How's the critic work
And how
Get
Feedback sign
What's from different sources
Is are
We can get these signals from two primary sources
The first
Which is a human in the loop model
The user is the
When you click
Is September 10th
Tom Thumb on a check
You are providing the feedback signal
Did the learning element videos
On the
And more autonomous method
Implicit feed
Hear the agent is
It's on Krit
It learns from Simply observing the environment
HSI
Did that loses a game has received
Is feedback sign
An agent that calls a
And get any better
Has received its feedback
What's my action of
The tool was
So now let's understand
How's the learning element Works which is the update model
So basically
Play The Learning element
Which is the updated model
Text the feedback signal from the critic model
And use it to do modify the agents other comp
This is what learning is in an agent
So the first step is update the memory which is the long-term memory
If the feedback is the the fact is wrong
The learning element can execute a command
To delete or update the fact in the long-term memory
Which is the memory
Play and it could be a vector database
And the second update to cleaning model
If the feedback
The five state plan was very inefficient
The learning element
Can store MMO in a memory
Play the essential to the clinic module
This is a bad plan do not trade again
And the third step
Update the
What is the function
Which is the most
And in the most advanced case
Scene in agents like a Chase
Excess driving car
You can update the YouTube
What is the function itself
This is reinforcement learn
I think the agent learn
The user was unhappy with the fastest route
So I will slightly increase
Is the negative weight for to
Am I beautiful calc
The
What is the definition of
He's not changed
Let's Intimacy in an example
Our example is the learning spam filter
Which is the most intuitive example for this lecture
Intercept
The performance element
Which is the act
Has a simple
Diesel is
List the subject Kant
The movie
An interested
It makes a mist
Is spam email with the subject
Please report on
Gets into your in
But in the state today
Do feedback loop begin
You is a Critic model
Hit the market September 10
And this is the feedback signal
In the step
The learning element
Which is the email service machine learning model
Receive the signal
Eat analyze the content of the email you
I need update the performance elements log
Do you love is more n
In this case if the report
I'm not include
Dangote
The agent
Please learn from your feed
Which is not smart
This is the complete self improvement
Is it somebody we can say that
This is a metal Loop that improves the agent
And it is weird from two components
The
Speak portable
I'm the learning element
For the update
This is the most powerful but also most comp
Expensive