In this video we are going to learn
The last step of all Road
Which is the communication
I'm the
We have finished our
Including the alarm
Perception
Reasoning PL
Memory
I'm learning model
So we all have agent operations in here
All agents can execute
The complex
Monster
It can run a
Get a result
An update
What is internal mem
But this brings us to final critical question
How does the agent communicate these results to the outside world
The agents final answer is just internal structured data
This component the
Is the final translation there
It is the
What's communication Department
Before we start let's understand the audience problem
An agent
This is not one size fits all
The format
Off its communication
Depends entirely on
It's audience
Is are
We must design for two distinct
The first one is
Agent to
Communic
This is what we typically think
The audience of the end us
Who needs a friend
Natural language resp
The goal
Is help
And the second type is
Agent agent or 88 communication
This is for multi
The audience is another piece of soft
This communication must be a structured
Pre
Add unambiguous data structure like an API call
The goal is eff
Let's look at the architecture Portage
Let me die first
Which is the age of the human communication
So this is our final step of AG
Does reasoning
And it
Is synthesis called to the 11
Which is our brain
Let me explain this process
Listen to our diagram
Can you cancel the forecast
And I'm going to explain this first step into our diagram
If you can see in the picture
Basically
The person starts from the user
San Diego to our travel agent
And after
True calling and planning is
The agent internal State containers
Show me perform one final alarm call
And we call this step is a synthesized
Repeat all the internal data back to 11
But with any
And the last step is 11.0 generation this
Is the agents voice
You translate cold heart data into warm human readable response that is representing our
Can you tell the human communication
So now we can go to the second more technical type of communication
This is the voice an agent us
To talk to other AG
This is the mechanism
That makes multi-agent system possible
Let's say our travel AG
Send an orchestrated need to ask
Ask a weather AG
Specialist agent for data
The problem is
It cannot use
Which is the agent of the human voice
Sending a natural language from
Hey can you look up the weather
Is a terrible piece of engineering
It is ambitious
It is slow
Is other agent to use its own l
To understand that
The example is simple
Human talk to each other in prose
Talk to each other using
Subtracted apis and Jason
So agents when talking to each other
What's 8 like
Therefore for AG
The solution is to
It's a struct
Mission readable protocol for all agent agent communication
We are essentially defining the API for agent
This Express I say why
I'd like the model contacts protocol
Which we will cover later are so critical
They are the language of the AAA
How it
Basically an orchestrated
Need
Ask a specialist agent to do
Instead of a check to travel agents
How much is a Jason Le
Softer
The weather agent is
Is architected to listen for this exact request
It doesn't need to think or Reason about the front
It's simply pasta Jason
Execute the
On this phone
Subtract your Jason
You can see an example Jason response from the agent
This is
Cheap and reliable
We will see the details ETA communication in the upcoming
Reading this lecture