In this video we are going to design
Research assistant agent
In our last lecture we EST
Is the first step receipt for a standing and AG
It is time to move from 30 to practice
I'm with a
Functioning agent from
We will methodically follow are five step receive
To build a research
Turn on
Let's look at the love objective and the
Are task is
Research assistant AG
Asian school is autonomy St
Light a short take your report on a complex
For example
This topic could be
Write me a
What's the report on the history of
So why did an agent
The agent cannot know
Is from its internal training data which might be outdated
It must create a plan including
Search information
Android report
So now let's understand
What's the
Which is the left
We will follow these the five-step pro
List from our last lectures
These are
Step
Define the
Assistant
Step 2
Please choose the brain
Which is the alarm
Skip to the
Define the
Which is
Function call
Sing Uncle in operation
In our case we will be web search
Answer for
Architect the memory
This could be short-term and long-term memory
I'm surprised
Please write the loop the orcust
So beautiful love these step
To designing
So let me start
50 step on and set
Did Stefan is the important one
Which is the
And this is
Assistant program that we have inject our
You can see
What is the first
And this is our research AG
Inside of the alarm
Play music to start in
Do you think this system
And here you can see the system
If you read
Play some problems you can't see that
We have give a person and after that
Define the agent call
And after
If you know that
Define a guardian
You said
You must use the web search
Together information
And you must not answer from your own know
This force it to be an agent not just a check
And if
Which is the choosing to bring
Which is the alarm
This is a complex multiple reasoning
And this is not the time for a small fast model
We need High capability
Are you thinking
It is the strongest
Pink and politics instructions
So we will use a model
GPT
Equivalent like Gemini and so
So this is our choosing the alarm
Let's continue with the step today which is the
Until definition
State three is with agent
We will give it one tool and web search
Is it discuss
This is the two-part implementation
First one
Write the actual python function
What
We will make the search operation to return
Simple predictable sitting of
Is a python function
You can think this button functions represent our tool cooperation in the step 3
And after that we
Did Jason OB
Tell the alarm
You have a tool which name is
Is there
And it takes a one parameter which is the greatest thing
This is how the brain learn
What is hands can do
So if you continue to support
Staple is the memory or we can call
Secret
Is you remember that we
Play two types of the memory for the agent these are
Short-term and long-term
For the short-term memory we will use the most common pattern
A simple python
And
Is Will function is our chat history and situation
We will attend the users from
Uncritically
We will also happen to the results from our web
This entire
Is to set the alarm
Turn on the every
On the second type is a long-term memory we are not building a vector database
Are web search tools simulates direct Pro
And it is our agents function for
Retrieving from
A persist
External knowledge
But you can use
These Victor
Is for long-term memory for our
So now let's continue the last
Which is the
And which is representing our execution
And this is the rock music or orchestration code will follow
In Lupine the Asian perceives the user's
It reason
Based on the system
That is most used a tool
And after that it is 8/3
Explain is to generate a tool called
Or could be catch these Jason
Execute our python function
An
How to add memory
In route
The loop repeat
Will you call the alarm again
What is
The memory of
It contains the search results
Did anyone
Now she's the original goal and
It generates the report on our Loop is
Can you cancel
What's the
Doula
Do you provide
Assistant
Define the
And give the hands as a web search
Undefined
Short-term and long-term memory
I'm far from the loop as a reasoning
So if you look at the
Are full form of the research agent we can say that
The first of
Do you proceed to use the request
Which is the report history of
On the second step
Be reasoning an alarm
My system from
Is I must use a to
And I can't answer my
Call the web search
In the third step we called the best Search tool and reasoning about
On YouTube
Musically use memory and getting response from the web search operation
On synthesized responds
And return back to the user including the final natural language
It is
We can see real world example
Call performing to research agent
If you go to
Gemini.com
You can see this interface
So basically let me ask anything this will be retrieved from the alarm internal know
But here you can see the
If you click the
We can add additional to
For example
In our case we will select
Did res
And after surgery search you can see the sources
In this case this will be retrieving information to performing to Google search
And after that you can ask questions like research and plant
Do Japan
This will be retrieving information
First of all
Make a tool call for the Google search
On the TV information
And after that
Synthesize the data and returning a full report
Go to the user
Is you can see that agent first create a
And this will be research websites
If you click the status
This will be get information from the web and after
Change the size data
And return a final report for your planning to Japanese