In this video we are going to learn
The
Perception reason
Sing action and learn
In the last lectures we have defined what an agent is
Which is digital employee
It's autonomous and gold
But how does it work
What is the
Step-by-step process
It follows to be
The answer is agency
The agency
Is the fundamental operating
I think system or heartbeat of every agent in
We are going to
The Journey of data is
It's close to this entire cycle
Step by
To understand the process of agentic thought
So let's start with the problem
Which is the Journey of a
It is practical
We are going to today's
Single user request
I'm sorry to
We will
How the data is transformed
Is it closed around this
We start with perception
The agent
Is gateway to the
The second one is reason
This flows into reason
The cognitive core or
Where the agent sings
The third one
Is action
The output of the reasoning is action
The
Did allow the agent to have an
It's only its en
And finally the results of that action
Feed into learning or deflection
Which is the metal Loop that allows the agent to improve
Let me show you
Is agency
In a particular agent
When the
Santa
Is unfollow the unturned FL
So first of all
Do you say
Do you like
Is comes to our perception lay
Which is how agent sends the
And after that it goes
Reasoning player
How agent
Thanks ambul
And after
This going to action model which is the
The agent effective
I'm Leslie it comes to learning model
How the agent improve itself
This is the Journey of today
And the problem
The single user request from start to
Let's begin the journey into phase
Which is the perception
Is it normal that we have already seen these layers before
When we are examine this anatomy of the AG
But now we are looking for these layers
Is for the Journey of the requ
The goal of the procession layer is getting information in a clean format
And the trigger could be any event this user in
Put API resp
Or any sensor data
And the challenges
These inputs are diver
Roll
So
Turn the brain doesn't understand
Jason audio or I'm
For that reason
The key process of the perception is a normalization
So this is the translation pipeline converting 12 diverse input into clean and alarm understandable
Which is
For example
If the image is upload
This will be Santa Vision model and convert to text
If any audio uploaded this will be sent to
You should text and come over to
Please cancel
So the idea is that the output
Screen
And this is our first data transformation
And if you go to Second Step of the agency
Which is the reason
The brain
The reasoning engine
Post to normalize perception
Relevant contact
Next from the memory
So the goal is the understand and create plan
The process is
Is first
Understand
50 perception and memory
After that plan with using the Chain of Thought
And after that decide
And this is the thinking in the
Reason an egg
So if you look
Make the key output of the reasoning
Dublin is a structured object
And this is the second transformation
Creating a plan
Alarm
What is translated into machine readable format
Jason
So the next step is the action
Is the input of the action is the Jason action plan from the reasoning model
So the goal is the execute this plan and affect the environment
And this is the execution process
First of all
Will you pause the including Jason
An executed
Which is the function cool
An effect en
So this is the
Play in
Reason and egg pattern
So the critical output of the action is
Closing tulip
For example when the results comes from the tool
Play kitchen light in Jason
This is not the
This will be
Close the door
And start the loop
It becomes the trigger of the next perception phase
Which is the loop
You can see in here we will run this
And this will
Play feedback into beginning Loop
And we can say
Add these
Start
Put the per
Reason and
Which is the API
Unreasonable about the plan
Next tell the US
The next step is learn
Which is the metal
The goal is to improve the agent performance overtime
And this is the option Loop that sits on top of the
What is a problem
Learning process
Is Tuesday process
The first one is reflection and the second one is adapt
If you look at the key output of the learning
This is the adaptation process
First of all the critic
What is a feedback
And after that we start the update
Which is
Learner process
Update the mem
Play update the
An update the utility
Play did we have seen in the previous
So basically we can say that
We learned the Journey of The Producers which is the agentic group contains the process for data transformation
Restart in perception
Which is basically translate into
Put clean normalize
And that takes flows to reasoning
Which combines
Let's eat memory and transform into
Subtracted Jason plan
And that plan
What's the extra model which execute the
And get a road tool result
It's out
And that result is loop back into the perception
Starting to cycle over again
I'm finally the learning
It's over on top of these agent
And this is the problem process
This floor is a fundamental engine of every