In this video we are going to design jcpd
Beautiful living or agency
On the first step is perception
But before that let's look at the environment
In this case the environment is
The US
And after
By speaking into your phone
Drawing input
What is Audi
And the perception model first job is normalization
It immediately sent this audio to speech to text module
Because this extractor
And the important thing is perception model discard to turn off your voice
Including sarcasm and your IMM
It only is perceives what you said
Because the office of these perception model is
A Killeen Texas thing that is understandable from the llm
After that we can go to the next step into our agent club which is the reasoning
Text the normalized text and combine it with the relevant data from
It's memory
You can't remember the reasoning process
For example user want a fantasy seafood restaurant
A memory
Live in the
Please record real-time information with open arms and reviews
Is there for plan is to use
Web search
The output of these reasoning phase will be a Json object
Put the tool call
And the next phase is the action in the Atlantic Loop
In the action phase the orchestrator takes the Jason plan
Unpause the web search
But this is where the loop become obvious
The author of death
Which is the list of restaurant
Is not the
You just said immediately back into perception model
Is the trigger for Loop
In the second
The agent
Is the search
It's reason about it
And after that it is final action is to produce the helpful Texas
Here you can see the full image of our architecture of the checkup
In the first one
Which is the perception
The environment is us
And we provide a robot
Do you speak apron in your phone
And this will be converting with the perception about
Can you find me a good
Can you put restaurant around
And this is reasoning here you can see that we provide a
And this will be understand music
Fancy seafood restaurant
And my memory
Is they live in Seattle
And this record real time information
Did I don't
It is performing a web search to basically
Function call
Make using the website
That means phase 3
Is it action
The orchestrator pass the Jason plan and execute the web search tool operation
And the last step is learning
This will be provided to learning and this will be
So let's understand this operation in the real world use
If you go to the jcp.com
And come to this page and click
Is voice
You can ask about the seafood restaurant around
Let me start from
Please find me seafood restaurant around me
Is you can see
Is it going to start
This will be performing too cold which is the best search
And return back to
Can you put
As you can see that this will be powerful
Turn off the
Synthesize the response according to my and this will be returning