In this video
We are going to design
In health
Put The Agency Group and human interlude
So basically
We will use exact
Blood process
Is too much more complex
Is istick example
Which is a clinical assistant agent
For the
Turn in an ICU
Heal the environment is the patient
Can you cancel our environment is the
So the role in
What is a mass
Constantine of data
These are the
Why does
Love reports an amazing files
And the perception model is
Far more
It is not just waiting for a user
It is filtering this
Addicted to trigger the loop only when the Vital sign is dangerous
For example let's say
Heart rate over the
This will
Play trigger an event
And this will be dangerous
Play this will be take
Directions from the healthcare
Just like the check GPT
Eat Translate
Multimodal data
It might use
Like this a
To anal
Is a brain scan
So basically
Define normalize output
Send two reasoning face
Is this urgent and
Summary of the patient report
For example
New Radicals
Put left side on
After completed the perception model we can go to the next step
Which is the reasoning
Listening face text
Critical perception
An immediately combined it with the context from the memory
For example the patients electronic medical record
Especially allerg
The agents ultimate goal is to set to Patient survival
The alarm please
It is the anomaly and the allergy
It can't just
It is formed a multi-step plan
And first of
To search for information
Turn on the anomale
And
Together need information from the pass
So the output is a Jason
And perhaps
To call
Search PubMed
And the other test tool
So in the recent step we have created a plan which is EXE
Add multiple tool
For the
Add and visit AI
So the next step is action and learning
In the face
Which is the action
The orchestrated execute
Search Pub
And order the
And the loop closes that
The results of the search
Watch underneath love values are fed
Connect to the phase
Turn on which is the perception model and start to move to
And the agent regions on Disney data and
Any appointment
For example
Recommend a medication of eggs
So now it is information
Turn agent reason and
Final
And based on the loves
Search
Are you
Administrating
Medication
But this is not the
Because we have also one more step which is the learning and safety
And this is a critical
Interface for the agents final
Is not executed automatically
You know how she takes environment
We don't let the agents final action run
We use a human in the loop design pattern
The agents plan
And presented to a real doctor
The doctors Foundation yes this is correct or know this is wrong
Becomes the input for the face
Learning
So the doctors feedback allow the agent to be
Pick an adapter for the teacher
So now let's summarize Healthcare AG
Turn into agency
First of all
Are environment is a patient
I'm in the perception model
We get raw input from the white
Love
And Radiology
And is the output of this perception
You basically provide a report
To the
Listening
In the recent Pro
Does be performed multiplayer
And decided to decorate
A Json object
To execute
Multiple tools including department and visit a
And after that we perform the action
What's that
Run oldies to call
And Performing these actions
And form a final plan
Like to comment medication eggs
But the agents final plan is not executed automatically
It stopped and present a human in the loop
Which is a doctor
An according to Dr feedback
We use and
And this will be