Welcome to week 3 day 1
Today we're going to cover linear algebra fundamentals one of my favorite topics in school and I hope you
You enjoy this
First you're going to look at vectors and mattresses
Now what is a vector a vector is a 1D array
Representing
Quantities with both magnitude and direction
Look something like this
Example more like a list
Format
Can we have a matrix
Matrix is a 2d area of numbers arranged in rows and columns one of the example is this where we have a
3 * 3 Matrix
It's been here
Man its values are 2 - 3
20 - 114 and 5
It's kind of you already read it out from
Left to right
And then you go down every single row
Let's talk about the properties as I mentioned you know the Matrix is kind of
Read out as
3 * 3 or
Buy n where m is the rose and N is the columns
A vector on the other hand is a special case of a matrix with one row or column as you can
I can see about
We have a list two three and four that's a matrix with only one row or column
Let's go ahead
And talk about
Matrix operations we have addition and subtraction first
Mattress
Must have the same dimensions
For element wise operation I can give you an example what we can do is we can
Create a new file
Python save it as
Week 31 or make sure I'm in the right folder
Devin underscore samples
Here I am going to first import number
If you have not gone through week 2 I would probably recommend you go to week to to understand whatever we are doing
Will you be using them by quite a lot
I want to create a matrix here by using NP dot array
And in here I'm going to make a 2X
3 comma 4 so I have my 2/2 Matrix here similarly I'll create one more
Call
And here I'm going to add values
A little bit more than that 5/6
Seven
8 so I have my two matrices here
What is
And one is B and the values are 12345678
For these two mattresses or two variables that we created A and B
Nice I want to print
The addition between the two of them
I can directly
Say A + B because these are number is
So I can directly use that similarly I can also do
Subtraction
Bye
A - b and it does as I mentioned
Element
Addition and subtraction which means it will take each element
And take the corresponding one to it and do the operation so if I run this let's open my
Victory Day One perfect
Python
Devin samples
And it will give you the solution here
6 okay it's always good to
Put on next line so it looks much more clear
Clear it out I need one more time I have
681012 so 5 + 1
6 + 2
7 + 3 + 4 + 812
Similarly 5 - 1 - 5 is -42 - 4/6 is -4
3 - 7 is -44 - 8 is -4 and that's why we have the subtraction
Yeah I can always do other way around
So it's all positive numbers 3444444 so you can always do
Element wise operations for addition and subtraction
Next
You want to talk about scalar multiplication now this is not a matrix multiplication that's something else we will talk about but
Scalar multiplication is you multiply every element in The Matrix
Bias killer so what happens in that case is so for example
I have I want to create an idiot
Which
2 *
So this is where you give a scalar value
Do a particular Matrix and now if I print it out
Location
Slashing
So what this does is it does something similar to addition but
It will take the value to and
Multiply with every single element inside the Matrix a so if I run this
I have
24678 because 1 * 2
Is 22 * 2 is 43 * 2/6 and 4 * 2 is 8 and that's what we get in scalar multip
Another operation that we have which I want to talk about is matrix multiplication
It requires the number of columns in the first Matrix to be equal to the number of rows
In the second Matrix so because of
The multiplication works so you have to remember again
Number of columns in the first Matrix
To be equal
The number of rows in the second Matrix the reason is the formula for this goes something like this
Let it air to mattresses
And I enjoy the element of a * B should be equal to summation of n equal to
I want to play
A i k and bkj so if you see the rules and columns kind of multiply with each other that's why
The number of columns in the first Matrix
Should be equal to the number of rows in the second Matrix
If you want to use it
End lights on the way we do it is
A equal to NP Dot
What's the result
Equal to
The function is called
Dot itself
A comma
So this is what it does is it will multiply A and B together
I can say print
Matrix
Multiplication
/
And what's the result
Put on it I'm going to
Comment out the rest of them
And just run this
Also looks like I have the wrong answer here because I have said A and C let me do a and b
So it's much more visual so I'm going to go here
Clear it out and run it again
So there you go
We have 1 * 5 which is 5
+ 2 * 7
Equal to 14 145 is 19 that's the value here
Same thing so you keep on doing multiplication by Rose by columns and that's why you get this solution here
So again the first element
In the room
Did the first element in the column First Column
Second element
Times the second
In the room times column say first element
That is the first element right here so similar you keep on going through these elements
One by one and then you can do that but again luckily you don't have to do with those manually
You can just use NP dot function now it would be so much easier if it was available
When we were in school
But again
We had to learn this the hard way so next thing that I want to talk about is special mattresses so
Do you want a special mattresses
We have identity Matrix which is I
A square Matrix with ones
Or on the diagonals and 0 cell phone is represented as I * 8 equal to
The way we do that in
Here in our court
Is we say
Equal to
MP Dot eyi
3 * 3
If I want to print this
To see how identity Matrix look like identity
Matrix now again I didn't have to specify
3 * 3 Because as I mentioned it's a square Matrix so if you just have to provide
One and it will one element
Of what the rules and columns is the same as the rose
I am going to run this up
And there you go we have 10010001 and if you see the diagonal elements are all
Similarly I can make it a bigger one
1111 so all the diagonal elements so that's an identity Matrix
I am going to show you another one
Images
Zero Matrix a zero Matrix is a matrix with all the elements
Add zero so this doesn't have to be square Matrix
For
I am going to comment this out
Smoke a little bit
And a zero Matrix looks like let's say Z equal to
MP Dot and to create that you say zeros and then you have to specify the
The rows and columns so let's see if I want to create two by three
I can say print
Matrix
/
Call Mom Z
Save it go back
Clear it out
And let's print it out
60 Matrix is a 2/3 Matrix here with all zeros inside here that's what a zero
Next thing that I want to talk about
Is a diagonal matrix a diagonal matrix is a square Matrix
Where all elements
Except the diagonals are zero so it's a little bit different than identity Matrix again it's a square Matrix
But in this case
Everything except the diagonals are 0
So the way you
You create them in
Python is you say
Who's
Numpy dog
And not here I'm going to give some values
2 and 3
Endless print
Diagonal
Matrix
Slash in
Comma
Let's look at how it looks like let me go ahead and first
Common this out
Open this
Clear it out make sure it's saved run it
And if you see here 1 2 and 3 so
When you say diagonal matrix you're actually giving the values to the diagonals
So everything except the diagonals are zero in this particular case
No
How do we understand all the different types of matrices
Let's go and play around with them let's head to hands on exercises
So our first exercise is to create vectors and matrices using numpy so just
To get started with things
Are objective here is to practice creating and manipulating vectors
And mattresses first let's create
Room let's create two mattresses
What size 2 by 2 and then we'll perform addition subtraction and scalar multiplication
So let's go back here
Clear this out
I'm going to play the new file called as day one
Underscore exercise 1.3
As I mentioned first I mean we always need
Numb by
S&P and as I mentioned the first step
Is to create
Mattresses
Our first metrics is will be
NP dot are
And inside that
I'll create one comma
And 3 comma 4
Nothing special
I'm going to copy this and create another one called
And here I'm going to say 9
And 6
Guess I've created
Two mattresses now next first thing is
Addition
Deposit here and do it yourself and and then continue
Additions if you got it right
You probably did something like this but he said eh
Plus
Simple enough
How about subtraction so try to do
Subtraction
And then come back
And then next thing as I mentioned you can do a
Scalar multiplication
With the number three
For the Matrix so try that and then come back
So if you did it right you probably did print
Subtraction
Slash
A - b
Bus schedule multiplication I mentioned
The
Slash and do a multiplication of
3 * The Matrix a
So if you
Exactly like this it should show up
Something like
Let's get it out python
Devin underscore ex1 Dot py
So we'll get 1010 because 9 + 1/8 + 27 + 3 + 10
Subtraction 1 - 9 is -82 - 8 is -63 - 7 - 4
And 4 - 6 is -2 and then scalar multiplication for a
3 * 1 is 33 *
Who is 63 *
3 is 9 and 3 * 4 is 12 so that's what you should see
But as output of exercise
We have exercised too
But we will be implementing
Matrix Vector multiplication
So the objective here is to multiply a matrix by a vector
So first will create a 3/3 matrix and a 3D vect
And then
Perform Matrix
Vector multiplication
So let's see how do we do this in court
If you want to try it out you can try it out yourself
Before you look at the solution
Call Devon ex2
Dot p
Numpy as NB
Next thing is will create
Matrix
And Victor
So for the Matrix I'm going to call it m equal to
MP
And as I mentioned we're going to create 3 * 3
So I'm going to give it numbers one
2 and
Next row is
5 and 6 are next row is
78 and 9 so it's a 3 / 3 * 3
Now we need to create a vector and call it V
Equal to
NP
And my Vector is always
1.1 call
So I am going to call at 3:10
And -1
No let's do a matrix Vector multiplication
Should you do that I am going to say
Matrix
Vector
Multiplication
And here
OK Google result Matrix
MV
Now if you use the same numbers
Multiplication results should be same
Matrix
Multiplication
Slash
Wizard so let's just play it
And let's
If we have the same answers I want to clear this out
Let's say python
Day one underscore exercise 2
Dot pyramid
And our Matrix Vector multiplication
Is -2 - 2 - 2 *
Did the multiplication based on these two vectors and this is the solution
That you should be looking at if not I'll check your code again
And then go through it again
For today
Do you have an extra we have exercise three
Where we will explore special mattresses
Subjective here is to work with identity zero and diagonal matrices
So what we'll do is we'll create a 3:35 Matrix
And multiply it with another Matrix and then create a diagonal matrix and zero Matrix
So let's go ahead
And do this
Nuclear this out
Save it and create another one
This one I'll save as day one
EX3
I will create an identity Matrix
Identity Matrix
So let's let you guys do that
Next
Do a diagonal and
0 Matrix
And display them out
So that's what you have to do
If you have already done
Or not just pause it and come back so first thing that we need is import
Number is NP
Next for identity Matrix I said I equal to
MP dot i and
I will create an identity Matrix of three
It's up to you whatever you create
And then I'll create another Matrix MP
I didn't know if I want to do a matrix multiplication with identity Matrix of 3 I need to make sure the rules are
Matching with the columns
Which means I'll create the same
3x
1 2 and 3
Four five and six
At night
So I'm at 3:36
Next next to the multiplication I'm going to say
/ n
And a comma I is what I'll pass
Let's run this and check if it works
Lights on day
3.5
San Diego we have a matrix
123456 789
The thing is as I mentioned earlier
In our
Previous slide
I * 8 equal to a identity Matrix always gives you
The same result as your
Next thing that I want to do is
Matrix NP
D i a g if you remember that
And then I'll create one
7 and 9 some random numbers I'll give this time
Then I'm going to say Z equal to NP
This time
I'll
3 comma 3353
And let's print first
Diagonal
Matrix
/
Next I want to print
The zero Matrix song call it
Zero Matrix
Z I will print
Comment that I don't want to see that
So let's go ahead and print it out
And there you have a diagonal matrix 1789 the values are in the diagonal
90 Matrix of 3/3 we have zero Matrix of 3/3 here I hope you are able to follow along
Or do this on your own if not let me know and I can help you out
Our next step
Is somebody still practice for you
Try this out
First thing that you want to do is
Compute the determinant and inverse of a 2 by 2 Matrix using numpy
Try to verify properties of a matrix multiplication
Something like 8 * 3 ^ 2
Create a block diagonal matrix using numpy
Chinese
And let me know if it works if you have any questions or problems let me know and I'll come back to you
Suggest to summarize today
We learn the foundation concepts of linear algebra including vectors matrices and operations
These concepts are crucial for understanding machine learning algorithms and competition models in AI
So if you have any questions or if you have any suggestions let me know and I'll get