Welcome back to day 2
Today we're going to look at Advanced linear algebra Concepts yesterday we looked at some of the linear algebra Concepts
Let's look at something more
So here you're going to cover first
Determinants
And inverse of a matrix
Now what are the two minutes
A determinant
Is a scalar value
That provides information about The Matrix is properties such as invertibility
It is calculated only for square mattresses
Some of the key insights for the determinant include if a determinant of a matrix a equal to 0
The Matrix is singular which means it's not invertible
Videos of determinant of is not equal to zero
Then
Is invertible
Let's look at the geometric interpretation for that
So for a 2 by 2 Matrix the determinant represents the scaling Factor
What's the area formed by its column vectors
So the formula can be represented for a 2 by 2 metric size
Determinant of the Matrix is here we have a 2X ABCD
Equal to
8 * d
B * C that kind of gives you the determinant of a 2X Matrix
Now let's look at how we can implement this inside
Python
Someone start a new file python
I am going to save it inside my day too and call it stamps
Here let's start with importing numpy
Has NB
So I have that available now I'm going to secrete
Matrix MP
And then let's create a matrix here to buy two
Call it
Comma 3
Now if you look at our formula that we have given here
If I tried to calculate
8 *
328 so this is a b c and d
Add which is 2 * 4 4/8
And then
3 * 1
Which is 38 - 3
Is five
So let's go ahead and calculate that and see if it just gives me the determinant
Determine
Equal to NP
L i n a l g
Dot determinate
Okay that's what it's available
So linear algebra
Print
What is the determinant of this
I can get that to buy
Printing this out
Let's go ahead
And check it out
Lights on
Day underscore samples I forgot to put the data so as I mentioned
It's 51001 because it has a little bit of error Factor over there but that's perfect
Is multiplying by float so we get sometimes this thing but the value is 5
Now let's look at next topic which is inverse of a matrix
So the inverse of a matrix a
Is denoted as a raised to -1 that's how you can tell if a matrix is inverse Matrix
Now the product of a matrix and its inverse is the identity Matrix which kind of makes sense
A reverse of itself is identity Matrix
A matrix is
Invertible only if the determinant
Elsa is not equal to zero
Now the formula for a 2 by 2 Matrix
Choose something like this are is to - 1 equal to 1 /
Determinant of a
And The Matrix
- b - c that's how you can get a inverse Matrix
So how do I implement this in Python I can go here
Let's go ahead and comment this out
What is the inverse
Equal to NP
Dot linear algebra Library
Dot inverse
Of a
And I can print
There's one thing in words
Off
Is slash in
Call
Inverse
Let's look at how the inverse looks like
Is this out done it again
And here is my inverse of this Matrix so this is this
Times this Matrix should give us an identity Matrix
Next
Let's look at
Eigenvalues and eigenvectors
Know what are Asian values and agent vectors
Asian values and agent vectors are properties of square matrices that describe transformations
So for example if a matrix a
Times V equal to Lambda times V
Then in this particular case
The V is the agent Vector a vector
That doesn't change direction during the transformation
And lamb
Is an agent value
The scalar indicating
How we is killed during the transformation
The geometric representation of this
I can talk about Asian vectors as a Asian Vector point in the direction
Where the Matrix transformation stretches or compresses vectors
That is Asian values indicate the factor of stretching or compression
The properties I can talk about is a matrix of the size n by n
Has an agent values and agent vectors
Agent values can be real or complex
I know the property is for symmetric Matrix
Asian values are always real
Now let's see how we can
Compute agent values and agent vectors in Mumbai
Don't go back here I'm going to use the same
One I'm going
Common this out
Can say Asian
Valu
Comma agent
Vectors
Equal to
MP
Ninja algebra dot EIG
This will give me
The Asian values and Asian vectors
Matrix
I want to print it and check it out I can say print
Values / n
Call my agent
Values can do the same thing for
Vectors
I can bring this out here
Let's go ahead and run this and check it out
So Asian value for that Matrix is 1 and 5 and agent Vector is this particular
What's Matrix right here
I can give another example so for example if you create another area
MP
David values for comma 2
Speed one comma one
Now I can see agent well
An agent
Equal to NP dot linear algebra
Dot EIG
Of the
And then I can print
EIG
And for
Vectors since it's
Matrix I'm going to go to next line
And display this here
Comment this out
Cuz you want to see for be here
Get it out
And run this again
And this is my agent values and this is my agent Vector here so they are available so this is how you can calculate
Play Legion values and agent vectors in numpy
Next
I want to talk about introduction to Matrix decomposition
The first
What is Matrix decomposition
Latest decomposition is a process of breaking a matrix
Into smaller components
Do analyze or solve problems
Now before that we have
Singular value decomposition or SVD
SVD decomposers of Matrix
3 major Isis
We could get a equal to
Ooh times Sigma * 3 ^ 3
Where you is a left singular vectors or orthogonal Matrix
Sigma
Is a diagonal matrix of singular values or non-negative
Leaders to tea
Is the right singular vectors or orthogonal Matrix
No some of the applications of SVD include dimensionality reduction example in principal
Component analysis PC algorithm be used at
We also use it for noise reduction in data sets
And also sometimes for image compression
Let's look at how we compute SVD in numpy
I am going to
Comment this out
I will use my a matrix on my list
Try some code here so it's visible to you
For Sigma uses and we raise to TLC VT
Equal to NP linear
Algebra
Dot SVD
So if you see you don't have to
Write any of these Implement any of these functionalities did all available as part of the number
Library
Now let's listen to print them out
How is a decomposed of you
Is slash in
Same thing I'm going to do for
Is
We are we Trace to tease sometimes called as we transpose
So if you want
No the full form of diabet
And Es is also sometimes called as
Singular
Values so that's what it is
So as I mentioned use the left singular vector
This is soooo is the
Diagonal matrix of a singular values which is non-negative and this is the right singular vectors
Which is also called as we transpose
So let's go ahead
And clear this out
And you have your you Matrix
A singular values and the V transpose right here and these together kind of create the
No next step is to jump into Hands-On exercises
Your first exercise that we will be covering is
Calculating the determinant and inverse of a matrix we learned this in the first section today
Where the objective is to practice using numpy
To compute determinants and inverses
Orange is the instructions that will follow here is 3 / 3
And then compute its determinant and inverse so it's pretty straightforward so let's go
Create a new file
I'm going to save it as day 2 dot X1 Dot py
In here
I'm going to first import
Numpy
As n
The Green Bay Area and P dot area order
Mattress Matrix which is 3 * 3
So I will create it this way I'm going to say
456 some random numbers I'm just filling it up
Cancel this is my Matrix
How to create a determinant and say
Determinant
Equal to
It's NP dot linear
Algorithm
Indian algebra
Determinant of a
Similarly for inverse
I will say NP dot linear algebra Library
Inverse
Buffet
That's it pretty straightforward let's print them out and check it out the results
Determinant
Inver
Is inverse
Let's go ahead and run this
I'm going to say 5:10
J2 Dot ex1
Indigo we have a determinant
And we have our anniversary
Big numbers I see is exponential raised to EXO that means the decimal places are pretty low but
And we can use this
Now let's jump into
Exercise
Exercise 2 is to compute agent values and agent vectors
The objective here is using numpy to compute
And interpretation values in Egypt vectors
So we will be creating a 2X to Matrix and computers agent values and region vectors which straightforward
So let's go ahead
Create
A new file day to underscore
Es2 dot p
Here first thing is important
As NP
Next let's create a matrix a equal to
NP Dot and as I mentioned I'll create a 2 by 2 Matrix
This Matrix will have
4 comma it's a negative 2
1 comma 1
So this is my Matrix
Asian girls and aging
Asian
Does equal to
NPR algebra
Dot EIG of a
Asian values
Send out
Asian vectors
Search engine
Valu
And
Vectors
Slash in
Because it's a matrix
Sing
So I'm going to clear this out and I'm going to say python
Day two ex2
Indigo we have an agent values and agent vectors let's do one more exercise
And in this one let's perform the singular value decomposition so we'll be using the SVD function in
Play linear algebra
The objective here is to implement SVD and interpret the components
Which is the
Sigma and
We transport
Let's go ahead and call that account
Create a
Save it
Import
Numpy as NP
Next
A equal to Let's create a matrix NP Dot
I will create a 3/3 matrix here
First value is let's give some random values 3
11 comma next one
How to say -1 comma 3 comma 1
Next one I'll create one comma one comma three
Find my Matrix here I can get you
And VT
From n
Dot linear algebra
Dot SVD
Of this Matrix
So let's print them out
Print
Slash in
Bring me
Next single values so this is singular
Valu
She's diag
And that is
And this one is V
Transpose
VT
Reconstruct the Matrix and see if it works but I can do is let's say
Reconstruct because someone asked me that
Can you use all these three and then reconstruct so I can say
Show Sigma
Equal to n
Zeros
Create a zeros Matrix 3 / 3
Then I want to do NP
Underscore
Diagonal
Red Sigma
What's
So that kind of creates my initial thing then reconstructed
Constructed
Equal to you
Add the date to multiplication pretty much
Sigma
Multiply that
Will be transpose
So that should be my entire Matrix so let's print it out
Free
Tractor
Matrix
Slash n is
Reconstruct
Perfect so let's run this up and then check if it matches what we have here
So I'm going to say python
X3
OK Google our first umatrix are Sigma which is singular values
We transpose now we took the singular Matrix and then we
Added to 300 1st and then we
Who created fill the diagonal with the values that we have and then we created the reconstructed Matrix
Using the U Sigma and VT
Which is 311 - 131
113 exactly to the DOT
So there you go that's how you can
Create create a decomposition Matrix a single or value decomposition Matrix is and then
Reconstruct them back here
No for some additional practice
You can try to compute the agent values and agent vectors for larger matrices you
Can use SPD to reduce the dimensionality
Offer data set
And also try to verify the properties of an agent values you can do the determinant of
A - Lambda of identity equal to 0 try that out and let me know how it works if you have any problems
Rooms or had any problems following along through any of these exercises or any of the additional practice that you're doing
Let me know and I'll get back to you
Suggest to wreck
Today we learned Advanced linear algebra Concepts including determinants
Matrix inverses
Asian values
Asian vectors and Matrix decomposition
This concepts are foundational for understanding
Data transformation and dimensional introduction techniques in the eye
So if you had any issues or problems or have any doubts let me know and I'll get back to you