Deity
Today we're going to look at calculus for machine learning specifically
You're going to look at the derivatives
So first
We can cover
Introduction to derivatives and the role in optimization
So what are derivatives
A derivative measures the rate at which a function changes
With respect to its input
For the function f of x the derivative are also called as the first derivative of x indak
Play the slope of the tangent line at a point x
Let's look at the role in optimization for derivatives
Derivatives are used to minimize or maximize the function which is critical in
Machine learning for optimizing loss functions
Example can be the loss function
In linear regression measures the errors
Derivatives help
Find the direction to adjust parameters to minimize this errors
So let's go get some of the common derivatives
We have for f of x equal to x ^ 2
And the first derivative is equal to 2X
For sfx equal to sinus and the first derivative equal to cos x
How do we implement this in Python
Using we have some a library called a senpai
I'm going to start with the python file
Save it in RD3 underscore samples
And here I'm going to use that
Buy Library as SP
And here I'm going to say x equal to SB
Symbol
And for that I'll use x
Next
Equal to
Star star 2 squares that up
So that's a f of x equal to x squared which we mentioned right here
And now
To get the derivative
I am going to say SP
And pass it to variables f
Index
Let's bring the derivative
Save
Open and make sure you're in the right place
Python
Did three samples
Diego derivative is 2 * 6
Which is what we are expecting right here
But I'm going to leave that for you
You're going to jump into partial derivatives
Now a partial derivative
Measures have a function changes
With respect to one variable while keeping the other variable constant
For f of x equal to x squared + y ^ 2
Partial derivatives are defined as
It's partial derivative of f / partial derivative of x equal to 2X
F / 5 equal to 2 y
You also have gradient
Where the ingredients is a vector
Of all partial derivatives
Indicating the direction of
The steepest accent
Ford f of x equal to x squared + y squared the gradient is defined as Delaware for nebula of
Did The Matrix of
Passion derivative of f / partial derivative of x
And partial derivative of f / partial derivative of y
Which is equal to
2X and 2x that's the Matrix of
2 * 1
9 python how do we do Implement these
Thanks whatever we did we did the Boston derivative ingredient
So let's see how do we get the partial derivative ingredients I'm going to go clear this out
Here I am going to say
A comma B actually let's keep the
Value says X and Y only
So
Come over
We can get it by saying SP Dot
Symbols that I want to use in this particular case
Is X and Y
So that's what we get assigned here
F equal to
X ^ 2
Plus
2 is exactly the same as
The function that we have here X2 + y ^ 2 so that's what I'm doing here next I'm going to say
Equal to s p dot diff
Comma X
And gradient
Equal to
SPD
Differential
Comma why
So now let's go ahead and print the partial derivatives that we created
Partial derivatives
And I can pass grad X
And gradient
Spelled it wrong that's why it was not showing up and there you go let's run this and check out the solution
Derivatives is 2 * 6 * 2 * 5 that's
Object that you wanted to get so that's this is how you can implement this
Using Python and simple as the library
The View
Next look at
Gradient descent optimization algorithm
Now what is gradient descent
Gradient descent is an iterative optimization algorithm
Used to minimize a function example can be a loss function
It updates
Parameters in the direction of the negative gradient to find the minimum
No the update rule here is
ETA equal to 30 - Alpha Del or nebula F of theta
Bear Theta is parameters of the model
And Alpha
Is the learning rate which is the step size
Why is gradient descent important in machine learning
It's used in training models to minimize the loss functions
And find Optimal model parameters and that's why it's very important to understand how this works
No let's go ahead and jump directly into our hands on exercises
So exercise one is to compute derivative of basic functions
Subjective here again is
Use Python to compute derivatives of simple functions
First will Define the symbolic function using senpai
And then we'll compute its derivatives something that you did already but let's do it as an exercise
Follow along if you want to if not if you want to do it before me just go ahead and implement it and then cross
Somerset 83 underscore exercise 1
I wanted to make it as a
I'm going to open again
Open
And make sure
That I make it a python file
Add and open that
First import
Senpai as SP
Once I have that let's go ahead and Define a function I'm going to write comment so you can understand what I'm trying to do
X equal to s p dot screen a symbol
Suicide traditional
X symbol
Next ingredient function
X-rays to three
X5x
+ 7
So now if I want to get this derivative
It's compute the derivative
Of this that I can do by saying it's a derivative derivative
Equal to
SP Dot
F comma
And they should give me the function
So I can get
Venetian function
Function
Which is
I am going to print
The derivative
Witches
Let's look at the function and its derivatives
Get it out
Day
Exercise 1.5 and here is the function x ^ 3 - 5x + 7 and the
Give it to that is
3 * x ^ 2 + 3x ^ 2 - 5 so that's the derivative of
Pretty easy and
Python helps you makes it much more easier
Next exercise that you want to look at is Computing the gradients
Hear the objective is to calculate
Partial derivatives and the gradient for a multivariable function
What are you going to do here is we Define a function with two variables
And then we'll compute the partial derivatives and represent the gradient as a vector
So let's go ahead and implement this
Create a new file I'll call it day
Three exercise
2.5
First let's go ahead and import a senpai
Next I am going to
Define
Variable
Function the previous one we just used as this time we're going to do both X and Y so X and Y
Equal to SP Dot
Symbols
I need
And why these are the symbols that I need so that's what I specified
My function in this case is let's say x squared
3 * 5 ^ 2
Is this way and then I'll say -4
X * y Sol 4xy
F is equal to x squared + 3 y squared minus 4X y
Now let's go ahead and compute the partial derivatives
Can you say Grid or I can first write the comment
Search compute
Partial
Derivatives
And to do that grad underscore x equal to SP
Dot death and I give my function and variable X
Next for graduate
I will say s p dot diff
And that's it
Comma why
Let's go ahead and print the ingredients
So
First gradient F of let's say
The function for grad X
But it's a grad Excel keep it simple
I don't want to see a differential
Of graduates but that is grad underscore X
And I have similar for grad why
Is Brad underscore a gradient why
So there you go let's go ahead and run it I'm going to clear this out
And this is exercise 2.0
And here you go so far that function x ^ 2 +
3/5 ^ 2 - 4x why are gradient X for the partial derivative is
2x - 4/5 is -4x +
I hope you were able to do it
But I'm going to move to the third one which is Implement gradient descent for linear regression
Now the object to here is to write a python function to perform gradient descent
Add optimize parameters for a linear regression problem
So we can use number for this one because we have the solutions available for it we're going to define the gradient Dez
Make function and we're going to provide some sample data and perform the gradient descent
So let's go ahead and implement this
I'm going to say
This is exercise
And here first I am going to import numpy
As
Next the first step that I mentioned is we will Define
Gradient
Descent
Function
We can Define by creating a function called as gradient
Descent
And it takes multiple values X
We also need the theater
We need learning rate
We need iterations that are required to run through this
Malfunction
So that's what I need so I'm going to say m equal to
Length of
I'll take that
And then
For underscore
In range of
Iteration so for all the iterations
That we have I should say traditions
This makes more sense
Somewhere around through this for you for all the nutrition that are there
So first I'm going to try to get my
Predictions equal to NP dot do
And pass it accent data
For errors
Say predictions
Minus
And for gradients
I will get
1 / m
NP
XD
Transformed transfer and errors
Is what I'm going to take let's look at it perfect so that's a gradients
And then to calculate the 3rd of for it
11 recommended
Based on learning rate
Times gradient
So that will give me my data and that's what I can return after this Loop is over
Going through the iterations that
I have a specified
So there you go that's a gradient function
Now next thing is let's get some sample data to test it out sample data where I'm going to say X
NP Dot arraylist
And we also have to include the biased terms here
So for this
I am going to create one comma one the first element in the Matrix one comma
Second
And my third row I'll give
1 comma 3D simple and straightforward
Next
Concrete the Y variable
NP
And this is a
One line of a single Vector 2
2.5
Comma 3.5
This is my
Next I need Tata
Potato I will say NP
And that can be represented as we can do the initial parameters at 0.1 comma 0.
Next I will give the learning
Of 0.1
Iterations I don't want to get too much but let's have a thousand
That's how many times this will run through this Loop
Next
Let's create
Hey do the perform the
Gradient
Descent so we have the function
Why not run through it
Do that I'll say
My optimized
Theater
Equal to
Gradient descent
And now we'll get all the values that we have here x
Theater
We have learning rate
Of 0.1
And we have it recent
Please call Regions
10,000
And now let's print this out see how are optimized parameters look like
And that I can
Say optimize theater
Perfect so this is the entire function so let's go ahead and run it
Clear it out
And say python
Day 3
EX3
And I love my parameters are 1.166
300.750 * 3
Bunch of different times 1,000 times pacifically and they use the gradient descent function
To give us the optimized parameters for the theater
Next
If you want to do some more additional practice on these you can use senpai
To compute second order derivatives which is Haitian metrics so we did the first order derivatives but you
You can do the second order derivatives if you want you can Implement gradient descent with multiple learning
Patriots and compare convergence speeds
Also you can visualize the gradient descent process on a quadratic function to try this out and let me know
Let me know how it goes if you have any problems or questions or were not able to follow along
Let me know and I'll get back to you
So to recap today we explored the foundational concepts of derivatives and gradients
Focusing on their application in machine learning by implementing the gradient descent
Begin practical insight into optimization which is a key component for AI model training and will be
Using that quite a lot