Welcome back to day 4
Calculus for machine learning where you're going to cover this time integrals and optimization
No the topics that we will start with this first understanding
Integrals and their applications in them
So what are integers
Integrals compute the area under the curve representing the entire accumulation that is under the Curve
If you see a bell-shaped curve that's where integrals come into picture where it computes the area
That is covered under that particular curve
The definite integral the definite integral of f of x
From A to B
Is
Represented as integration from A to B
F of x DX this is the formula this is what you'll see probably and you've seen in school before
Now let's talk about applications in ml
We have probability distribution
Integrals
Are used
To compute the probability under a probability density function which is PDF
Also
Cost functions
Regularization terms in cost functions
Often involve integrals example
Integrating over weights in Bayesian
Models
Let's look at some examples with python of how to use it so I'm going to go back
Create a new file python file
Make sure I save it in day 4
Call
Day 4
Cool samples
And here first we used to we need senpai
SSP
Does the library will use a module will use
And then I'm going to say x equal to
Dot symbol
Are you the symbol X as before
If you have not seen the previous videos or recommend you watch them before doing this and I said my function that
I'm interested in x square
Which can be represented as X star star
No definite integral
Definite integral
Equal to SP
Integrate
That's the function
Google Call 828 will pass f
And
Comma from 0
Tutu
So what I'm doing here is I'm saying integration of x squared DX
From 0 to 2
Let's go ahead and get indefinite integral
Indefinite
Integra
For that I am going to say SP
Integrate
And here I'm going to say f
Andex
So this is integration of x squared DX
So I have that now let's print this
Definite
Integral
Is
Definite integral
Do the same thing
Indefinite integral
And the bottom variable is this one
Let's look at it
Should we are in the right folder boot camp week 3 Day 4
Perfect and I am going to run by 24
Not samples and Diego definite integral is 8/3 and indefinite integral is
Ice Cube / 3
So that's how you can calculate definite and indefinite integral
Next let's look at some optimization Concepts
So we have local versus global minim
Local minimum is a point where the function has a lower value than the neighborhood point
And Global minimum
Is the absolute lowest point
Off the function across this entire domain
So in m
A machine learning the optimization goal is to find the global minimum of a loss function but
Local Minima
Can sometimes suffice
Next next let's look at convex functions
A function is convex if I'm going to display you the
Entire formula
The f
Land of X1
+ 1 - Lambda of X2
Is less than equal to Lambda of X1
+ 1 - Lambda of FX2
For all Lambda which belongs to 021
No conflict functions ensures that any local minimum
Is also a global min
Next non-convex functions enable
Most of the neural network loss functions are non-convex leading to challenges in optimization
Next let's look at stochastic gradient descent or also called as SG SGD and
Edits videos
So first what is stochastic gradient descent or SGD
And optimization algorithm that uses random subsets are also many brackets many batch
Off the data to compute gradients
And update parameters
So why do we use SGD
Yesterday is used for faster convergence for large data sets compared to base batch gradient
What are the variants of SGD
We have mini batch SGD which
Updates parameters using small batches instead of single examples
You also momentum which adds a fraction of the previous update
Do the current update to accelerate the convergence
We have Adam Optimizer which is used quite a lot it combines momentum with adaptive learning rates
Ford faster convergence
Next now that we know the basics about integrals and optimization
Let's get into some Hands-On exercise
The first exercise that will be doing is we calculating integrals of simple functions
The objective here is to use python
To compute definite and indefinite integrals which you have seen earlier
And what will be doing is we going
Define symbolic functions using simply first and then compute the definite and indefinite integ
Let's go ahead
And I want to create a new file
Call it day for underscore ex1 Dot py
How to start with Will import the
Senpai module
And give it a list of SP
Next
Let's go ahead and Define a function
Now this function
I'm going to say x equal to
SP do
Symbol
Come on symbol
And I'll use the symbol X
Next song is the F equal to
SP dot exponential of
Minus X
So we have X and F now let's
Compute
Indefinite
Integ
No as you seen earlier
Indefinite
Integral
Can be calculated by saying SP
Integrate
And pass it fxn FNX
Next let's print it out
Indefinite integral
Call Ma
And bring the value of it
Next thing let's
Compute
Definite integral
To do that
How to
Definite
Integral
Equal to SP
Integrate
And pass it
X comma
So that's what I specify for definite integral it's a print
Definite
Integral
Is equal to
What's the definite integral right there
Some spaces that looks good
So now let's go ahead and run this I'm going to clear this out
And I'm going to say python
They underscore I forgot to give their food but
It's the same name
And my definite indefinite integral is -60 - x
So we have the values as per expected
A second exercise here
Is to implement
Stochastic gradient descent for a linear model
No objective here is to implement SGD
To minimize a linear regression loss function
What we will be doing is will be defining a simple data set
And will write a python function to perform the SGD
So let's go ahead and
Start recording I'm going to clear this out
Create another file save it as day 4 p
So first let's import
Number
S&P
Next
I need to
Generate some synthetic
Data so I will say
NP
Random
Dodge City if you remember this will make sure that every time we run the randomizer it will give me the same
Same random data as soon as the x equal to
2 *
Random
100 comma 1
So this is my future
Now I want to create a target of which I'm going to predict
So
Plus I'm just giving some random
Numbers
X +
ND
Random
Dot r a n d
Comma one
So this will give me Target with some noise values to it added to it
Now let's add
Biased
2X
Do I buy Stone what is to is let's create X underscore B
Equal to NP
Doximity underscore
An NP
Comma
2X
Now next we need to get SGD
Implementation
Create a function first
Call it
Stop casting
Underscore gradient
Underscore decent
And then this will take our usual parameters the target
Sorry the future the target
The theater that we have to give
Next episode
And then we need learning rate
And the number of iterations
A box is another way for saying
Nutrition
I'm going to first take m is equal to length of
Why do that next I'm going to run the iteration for I'm going to say epoch
Range of
An underscore epochs
I'll run this
And then again for I
Range of Em which you calculate the length of
And here
I am going to say first I want to get the
Random index
Equal to NP
Dot random
Dodge Ram integers
Eyes on the pick a random
Are index here I'm sorry not I but
And then next I'm going to say XI equal to X of
Random underscore index or depending on what index have taken
Random
Index
One
So that's going to give me extra value similarly for why I will say
Buy off
Random index colon random underscore index + 1
Next I need the gradients
For that I said two times
XI Dot
XI the multiplication multiplication here
Again multiplication
Theater
I will say
Minus equal to I'm going to decrement based on the
Learning rate
Times gradients
So that will take care of that now
Finally I can
Return
The cheetah here so that is the value of the final optimization
No next step is to resize this parameters that I want to start with
Initialize
Parameters
So I am going to create
Cheetah
Equal to NP Dot
Random
RND
One this is just give me the bias in the way next I have the learning rate
Which is 0.1 or 0.018 to 0.01 how many
Iterations I want I want let's keep it 50
Remember last score that we wrote we used 2000
Perform
SGD now and get the
So we are calling that
Function about so for that I'll say cheetah optimized
Equal to
Stochastic gradient descent
Underscore
Reduce generated above why
Anteater
And we need to pass the learning rate
And we need to pass the Box
There you go so I'll pass all these
That
Let me get the data
Optimize Theta and I can say print
Call
Name optimized
Parameters
Call Tita underscore
So this should give me so the expected results should be around based on okay I'm not going to guess even
Guess this so let's go ahead and
Run this I am going to say
Python
Day
Underscore es2 Dot py and there you go we have our
Optimize parameter 4.16
92.69 is a very close to the actual values that we have given
That's how you can perform an SGD to get the optimized data here
Now you want to do some additional work you can
Go ahead and visualize the loss functions
Surface and HDD optimization path
Also try to implement a mini batch SGD and compare it with the Vanilla Ice GT
And also finally
Use Adam Optimizer for a more complex data set and will be doing some of these in the machine learning
Videos in the future but try it out and let me know how it goes if you have any issues or problems let me know
Suggest to summarize today we learned the basics of integrals optimization Concepts and
Stochastic gradient descent by implementing these Concepts
Gender deeper understanding of
Optimization which is a corner store of machine learning training if you have any questions or suggestions
Please let me know and I'll get back to you