Day five
Probability Theory and distributions
Let's start with probability basics
And in here let's look at
Conditional probability
The probability of an event a
Given that event B has occurred is represented as
B a i b which means the probability of an event a given that even be as occur
Is equal to P of a
Divided by P
Example can be the probability of drawing a red card
Given that a face card is drawn from a deck of cards
Next we have base theorem
This relates conditional probabilities where P of
Open Event a given that even b as occurred is equal to be given
Do you say / POV
Red pill for burglary of a is prior probability
You'll be a is likelihood
And POV is evidence
We can do this bass theorem in Python by let's create a new file
Save it in day 5 as day 5
Core samples
9512387 I'm going to say
Theorems on the create a function here
And do it I'll pass the prior
The bad probability going to give it the likelihood
And I'm going to give it an Evidence
Which is based on our
Function here
Add to calculate it
You can say return
Likelihood
Probability
Divided by
Evidence that's what we did so that's the actual formula right here so that's how based theorem work
Let's save this and close it and let's go
Do the next topic which is
Common probability distributions now we're going to talk about a different probability distributions here
Starting with the gaussian distribution which is also called as a normal distribution
It's a bell-shaped curve with me and you and standard deviation with a sigma
The formula for it is f of x equal to 1 /
Square root of 2 pi of Sigma Square
Erase to -
X -12 / 2
Example of this can be modeling continuous data like Heights or test scores
We can look at a python example for that this
What I'm going to do here is
I'm going to import first
Numpy
S&P
And go ahead and comment these out
Next I want to import
Matlock
The plotter
Graph for this
Pipe Lord
So let's see if I use some new for Mew
And sigma
What's Sigma
And I said its value to 0 and 1
Next I'm going to create a variable x equal to NP Dot
Space
-4
Comma 4 comma 100
Next I will say bye equal to
1 /
It's based on the formula that we have here
And we need to pass
Empty
Square root of
And inside square root we had two
NP dot by
As you can see LNP dot p and we need Sigma Square so we'll see
Sigma
Star star 2 which is Sigma Square make sure all the brackets are closed
Dart exponential that's what we have here exponential days to minus
So that we can specify
By saying NPR -0.5
Because we have divided by 2 below so that's why I'm doing that -0.5 X
- moo moo
And after this divided by
Sigma
And then Square the entire
Think as you can see from the formula right here
So next step is to plot this
So I'm going to say PLT
X comma y
And then I'm going to say plot
Tit
Equal to
Guardian
Distribution
And then as a plot that show
If you're not seen for some of our previous videos on Matt Platte that will probably help us understand
What we are trying to do here
So now that I have it let's run it and see how it looks like
Going to open
Terminal
Make sure I'm in the right folder week 3 Day 5
And I'm going to run this file python day 5
Underscore samples
Indigo we have a guardian distribution right here so now if you had the similar graph that's
Good if not please check your code again to make sure that's exactly same because sometimes the formula can be confusing as you can see it
It has a lot of different parameters to it
Next thing we're going to look at Bernoulli distribution which describes outcomes of a
Binary experiment example you can think of it as a coin toss
So the formula for that is more on P of x equal to 1 equal to p
Baby of x equal to 0 equal to 1 - 3 this is the Bernoulli distribution and now if you
If you want to implement this I am going to
Common desert
And then
Mississippi equal to 0.6
And PLT
Dot bar diagram in this particular case
0 comma 1
Call Mommy are the two parameters
Color
I will use blue for this bar
And that's all that I need here next let's give a title
Call it
Distribution
Make sure I get the spelling right Bernoulli next I will say plot
XX
Is 01
And then
I need labels
Which is
Fail
And then I need
One for Success which is one
Is
Success
Perfect
Those are my texts and then finally
Show the plot
Save it
Go back
Do my terminal clear this out
And run this
San Diego we have our distribution for 0 and 1 based on the probability of 0.6
Next it kind of shows it properly on the
Next thing that you want to talk about is binomial distribution
Albino distribution
Models the number of successes in an independent Bernoulli trials
So this is kind of defined as you of x equal to k equal to n2k
Please take 1 - P - 1 -
Actually I want to
Show this in
Python
The way to
Broadcast Southeast from
CPI
Dog starts the slab module that will use import you need by now that's
That's where you can find the binomial distribution function
Equal to as a sign of values like 10 and
0.5
X equal to NP
Arranged
From 0
2N + 1
Next I'm going to say bye equal to as I mentioned we use binom
Dot pmf
And inside this I'll pass X
The different parameters that it needs to run the binomial distribution so once I've given that
That's not the bar
Sobriety bar X
Do I have my
What is not committed that's good eggs
Why colors equal to
Last time you use blue this time you use green
Next I'm going to see blood Dot
Title and for the title
How to say binomial
Distribution
And then PLT show
I said let's go ahead open Terminal
And make sure my
Grass from the before is closed cleared out
Run it again
Have a binomial distribution which looks perfectly fine this is how a binomial distribution
You should look like based on the values that we have provided
So if you got this that's good if not please check your values and what functions you're calling off if you have an error let
Let me know and I'll get back to you
Next thing that we're going to talk about is
Poisson distribution
No poison models the number of events in a fixed interval of
9 more space that is defined as P of x equal to k equal to
Lambda is to K
E ^ - Lambda
Gay Factory
So if you want to Define this or do this in Python the way to do it is I am going to
Comment this out this is something similar will use instead of biome will use
Voice
That's the module that you want
I'm going to say l a m equal to 3
I will see x equal to NP
Dot range
And I'll give you some zero to 10
Next I'm going to survive equal to
Voice on
And install pmf
And pass it X and value of lamb
And then
Broadcast message
It's pretty much same as before
And next I will
Give us some let's change the color this time to Orange
And next I'll give a title
This time it's p o i
SSO in poisson distribution
And show this plot
Perfect let's go back
Get it out run it again
And this is how the poison distribution looks based on the lamb and X values that we have provided for this is how
What should look for you if you had any issues or problems let me know
If not good we can move to the next topic which is applications in machine learning for all these different
Distribution that we have learned so first let's look at gaussian distribution it is used in version
Play 90s and kernel density estimation
We have but no need distribution which is used for by models binary classification problem
Example can be spam or not spam emails
We have binomial distribution which is used in logistic regression to model binary outcomes
And we have poisson distribution Which models the count data example
Can be number of clicks on a website that's what it's used for so these are different applications in machine learning for these
For the distributions that we have learned
Next let's look at Hands-On exercise so we will be doing couple of them were here first one is to calculate
Delete probabilities using base theorem
The objective here is to write a python function to calculate probabilities using base theorem
Have you learned earlier
So the example problem can be a disease affects 1% of the population
The test is 95% accurate for diseased individuals and 90% accurate for
Now what do you have to do is find the probability
Of having the disease given a positive test result so let me write it down so it's much more easier to
How to create day 5
1.2
And as I mentioned the problem
Here is let's create bullet points
I'm going to say first the problem is I'm going to give three bullets for three different
Things that we're going to Define here
A disease
Affect
1%
What's the population
Next I can see a test that is available
Is 95%
Accurate
Deceased
Individuals
90%
Accurate for
Deceased
Individual
And then the final one is
What we have to do is find the
Probability
Having the
Disease
Appositive
Test result
Because if you're not you know as I mentioned the 90% the dress is 90% accurate for non-digital
Reg
Will you will be using
Create
Function for base theorem
Which
Real probabilities
Which takes the sensitivity
And
Spacey the city
Specificity the spelling of right hopefully so the evidence
Sensitivity
Play if you remember the the formula that it had this is what it is and one
Minus
Specificity
Cancel that's the first line of next weekend calculate the
The posterior
Posterior
Equal to
Sensitivity
Times Square
And divided by
Evidence
No that is what we will
Return yes
So let's say
Based on the
Based on the requirements of priorities 0.01 which means 1%
Prevalence
We have sensitivity
Is equal to
0.95 which means 92 + 295 % as is mentions next
We have
Specificity
Equal to 90%
Percent
Prevalence
Our sensitivity as I mentioned which is also called as
Positive rate
And a true negative rate is specificity
Negative
Okay so now that we have this let's go ahead and get the value
Wisteria
Equal to base theorem into this I can pass the value that I have created here
Next it need
Sensitivity
And then it needs
Specificity
Let's print it out
No we should find the probability of having the disease given a positive test result so probability
Disease
Pause it
Is
Make sure my graph is closed
Get it out
And I'm going to say 5:10
Day
Exercise 1.5
Probability of disease given positive test is 0.08 which is 8% probability
That you might have the disease
And I hope you were able to figure out
Calculate the probabilities using the base theorem that we did here if not had any issues or have any questions let me know
Next let's go ahead and look at exercise 2
Are exercise
Is the plot and explore different probability distributions that we learned which is Guardian distribution
Open binomial distribution in poisson distribution let's look at those and how we can
Visualize and understand key probability distributions using python
And save it as
Day 5
Exercise 2.0
Not here first thing I'll say import
Numpy as NP
Next I'll get my matplotlib
Divided plot as PLT
Next import
Skypark stats
And import from this I can
Get my guardian distribution which is also called a normal distribution I need binomial distribution so that is
Are you home and poisson comes from po
I s s o n that's the position distribution so we have these
Next let's start with
Guardian distribution
So for this I'm going to say x equal to MP dot lens space
And here I'll give -4 comma 4
Call my
Next I'm going to say bye equal to
Normal distribution
PDF
And in here and give X lock equal to 0 and scale equal to
Next I will say pill
And I want to plot X comma y
Lab
Equal to
Guardian
A normal distribution what are we going to call it
I'll
Guardian
Distribution
That's
Next I'm going to say BLT
Show my blood so let's go ahead and run it
I'm going to say here python
Day
2.5
Indigo we have a guardian distribution perfect
Next
Is binomial
Normal distribution
And this I can say n comma p
Equal to 10 comma 0.5
We have x equal to
NP dot range
And pass it zero comma
N + 1
And why equal to Bynum
Dot PMS
Needs
N&p just like how we did earlier so these three parameters
Next time we'll see plot dot bar is the bar diagram that it gets so just give it X comma
And label equal to
Binomial
Next I want to say title
Intitle will be binomial
Distribution
And finally let's show this plot
Perfect I am going to comment this out
So she was only one right now
Close this previous one
And run it again
And they going both of them because I still have the using the same variable here
So I'll just go ahead and
Comment this
And close this and run it again
There you have a bar diagram
You can always make something like this it's interesting to have bar and the blood
Put them together
Display here
Next one that we have is poison
Poisson distribution
And for this
New Salam equal to so we need lamb and XY name equal to 3
X equal to m
Arranged
0 to 10 next I need to give by equal to
Play song
Dot pmf
And this needs X and lamb Valley Street
Perfect now let's get the bad idea bar chart
Does The X comma y
And I need label
Equal to
Poison
Perfect next time I need to give a title
I mean I don't need but it looks good
Distribution
Next let's show the plot
This is bad minimum you can always give X and Y axis in all those things but I like to keep it as simple
Is it possible I'm going to close this binomial distribution
Clear it out and run this one
And there you go we have a voice on distribution displayed here on the grass perfectly
So I hope we are able to follow along if not
Go through this and let me know if you have any issues or problems
For additional practice you can look at creating and visualizing a multi multi
Tell me a distribution for multi-class data you can try with the comparing gaussian and uniform distribution
For continuous data
Also try to
Use probability distributions to simulate and analyze real world data sets that are available in different websites
Today we explored probability Theory and its applications in machine learning
My calculating probabilities using base theorem and visualizing distributions we gained an essential understanding of
Probabilistic modeling and this will be quite helpful in future videos as in we go along so if you have any questions or problems