Day6 statistics fundamentals
Today we're going to look at
Measures of central tendency and dispersion
What is central tendency
Central tendency has mean in it which is the average value of a data set
It has median
The middle value where data is sorted
And the
Where is the most frequently occurring value
Does she want to kind of look at these three in Python we can probably start a fire
Save it as
Day6 underscore
Samples
And here I will start with for some data
Equal to let's say
10 comma 20 comma 30 comma 40 comma less than
50 so we have some data
No mean
Is equal to
Sum of
Data
Divided by
Length of
This data
That's how you calculate mean let's print it out
Comma
If I open my
Nancy python
Day6 dot samples San Diego mean is 30
Of this data set 1020 30/450
Let me know what here is
So that's how you calculate the mean
Now let's need let's look for median no median
As you familiar with or for not need sorted data so I am going to say sorted
Data equal to
Sorted
And sort the data that we have about
Next to calculate median I'm going to say median
Equal to
Sorted
Underscore data
And in here I'm going to say length
Of data
Slash slash 2
Data
Of
Mode of
Is not equal to zero
Next line
When I say
Sorted
Underscore
Dat
Length of
Data
I'm in the right place flashlight
2 - 1
Plus
Sorted
Data
Length of
Does the Slash
And then
I will say close clothes
/ 2
So that will give me the median for this entire value
So to calculate to actually print it out I'm going to say
Sprint
Median
Immediate
It's already sorted so you don't have to sort anything let's go to
Here
Print it out
There you go my mean is 30 million is 30 because it's a pretty uniform data that I have here so that's why it calculated
Is it and give me that Med
Next that we have is more
Nothing more we need something from a library I always like to put my modules up here and say
Statistics
I need
More
So for more now
Very simple I'm going to say Sprint
More I wish everybody had the libraries but there's different types of libraries available for doing this
But I can say from statistics I can just say more of data
And then go ahead
Clear it out
Enjoy it again so mean is 13 million is 30 more than this particular case from the
Next let's look at dispersion
So we have variance inside here which is the average squared deviation
From the mean
And if you want to calculate variance
In here you can
Varian
Equal to sum of
X this is the function for it this is the algorithm for this
What's the formula for this
X
Dat
Slash length of
Data divided by length of data so this is what will give you variance
Now if I want to print this out and print
Variance
Comma variance for the same data that we have let's look at the differences clear it out
Put on We already know the first and the variance is 200 for this data that we have
Make sure everything is Right x - mean
Schedule for X in data length of perfect so that's the reason that we get
Next thing that we can calculate is standard deviation no standard deviation is the square root
Obedience indicating the spread of the data so we already have variance so I can do
What's the √ STD
Deviation standard deviation equal to variance
√ 7306
Square root of 0.5
This will give me
Standard deviation
Comma STD
Sunday school death let's go ahead
And print everything together
Do you know my standard deviation is 14.142 133 whatever the rest of the values is but
And those are the difference
Basic measures of central tendency and dispersion that we have
Next
Let's look
Hypothesis testing
What is hypothesis testing it's a statistical method
To determine whether a result is significant or occurred by chance
So the steps that we follow for this is first we formulate the hypothesis we have two different things here one is
Add hypothesis and the other one is alternate alternative hypothesis null hypothesis you'll probably already always
Who is see it as defined as h of 0 and alternative hypothesis is defined as h of a
No not hypothesis assumes
That no effect or difference is created
Where does alternative hypothesis
Hypothesis assumes and effect or difference exist
Second step is to calculate the test statistic which quantifies the difference
Next determine the p-value
Which is the probability of observing data as Extreme as the test statistics
And finally we interpret the results
Where we check if the probability is less than Alpha which is a significance level example 0.05
We reject the null hypothesis which means it has some significance example for this can be comparing
Sing mean test scores of two groups using a t-test
Next let's look at the confidence intervals and statistical significance
No confidence interval
It's a range of values
Within which the true population parameter is expected to lie
The formula for this confidence interval is CI equal to X bar
Plus or minus Z
X / √10
X bar is a sample mean
Z is the z-score example 1.96
495% confidence
And we have es which is standard deviation which we already learned how to do
If I want to do this in Python
Let's go here and comment everything out so all the way to the top
And here
I am going to import something from
Start
Stats
So from the sea pie we got stats from there which has all the different methods
Available for statistics
What does it mean equal to mean sample mean equal to mean
Next I'm going to say
Z underscore
Equal to
1.96
Now where do we get this mean from we got the mean from here so I'm going to get this
Dat
Right here
Okay so we have a mean we have a z-score
Which is 95% confidence level now to calculate CI
We can say
Sample mean
Minus
Z underscore score
Standard deviation stand STD underscore
Deviation
Divided by
Length of
Data
0.5 now that
We need most of this looks like so if you need the
What's the STD deviation that is coming from here
I'm going to take this and for that I need variance
Which is sum of x - mean
And we already have means I'm going to take that up here
So we have variance sum of x minus mean
And I think I have I don't need to print this need the standard deviation for this perfect so I have
So next next thing that I need is comma not here
Comma and I need
Sample mean
Z-score
That's what are the formula that we saw
STD Dev
Divided by length of
Data
Square root
0.2 ^ 0.5 so that should be perfect so this will give me print
Percent
Confidence
Interval
Is at is the CI level so I'm going to
Display that
Let's go ahead
And run this
Confidence level is 17.60 comma 4 2. 3 9 9
95% confidence level that we have
Next
Let's talk about statistics significance
A result is statistically significant if the p-value is less than the significant
Level which is Alpha equal to 0.05
Completed some of the basics and some understanding about confidence intervals and statistics significance let's look
Play two hands on exercises
Our first exercise is to calculate mean variance and standard deviation
So if you already done the
Followed along you don't you can skip this but the objective here is to compute the basic statistic measures for
Lower data set
So I'm going to go ahead and use some shortcuts this time I'm going to go back here
Create a new file
Save it as day 600 score exercise 1.3
And as I mentioned I'm going to import
Numpy as NP
Let's call the data set as data equal to I use the same data
Use before 10:20
40 and 50
And then I will
Calculate the stats
First album mean then I will do
Variance and then I will do
Standard deviation
So if you know the formulas go ahead and write it and pause it here
If you don't I am going to do it here and follow along
Data
I can say NP
Dot variance
Data
I said shortcut
It's easier to just write it instead of writing the formulas because these are available through some of the modules
Add python provides
Inside number so we have already available here I am going to say print
Is
Next I want to print the variance
Call Ma Varian
Next I want to print the standard
Deviation
Which is STD
Underscore Dev so I have these so that's our exercise let's go ahead and run this
I want to clear this out and say python
Day underscore X1 looks like I missed the D6 again but
Here's my mean variance and standard deviation looks exactly the same as what we got from using the
Delete formulas earlier
But now you have NP dot variance in Panama
To do all these things for you
Next a second exercise
To perform a t-test
No I will perform a t-test to compare two sample data sets
Let's go ahead and first have those sample data sets I'm going to save this
Go next and save it as
Day6
Dot EX
2.5
What does underscore
And from first I need Syfy
Stats from there I can import
The t-test
Individual here this one
And I need my sample
Data sets for that I'll create
Two groups one is Group 1
The data of let's give some random numbers 2.1 comma
2.5 comma 2
3.0
And then I'll create a group
Two with data sets
1.8
I'd say 2.0
2.4
2.7
And you 2.9 some random numbers
Next next
Perform
Dirty test on this video sets
So for that I need I'll get the stuff
And p-value
From
Speed test
Underscore IMD
Where I can press group one and pass through
So this is a straightforward is that and here the t-stat is my T statistics
So that is
Statistics
Start a stick
And that I can display by saying tea
Ghost
Similarly my p-value
Is this
Can print that out
Netflix also do the interpretation
Inter
Asian the statistical value for it I'm going to say Alpha which was over if you remember in
In the previous slide with a statistical significance if in statistical significance
The result is statistically significant if the p-value is less than the significant level which is
Alpha is 0.05 so let's go ahead and do that I'm going to say Alfa
Equal to 0.05
Now I'm going to check if P value
Is less than Alpha
Which means
I'll print
Reject the null hypothesis
Which means it's
Significant
Difference
I will say print
Fail
Reject the
Hypothesis
It means no significant
Difference
Give me some random numbers so let's see how does this act you can try out with different
Values I'm going to say python
Day 6 underscore ex2 dot pyramid answers
To reject now the handle hypothesis no significant difference because the p-value is
To where is so
P-value which is 0.2
Is less than 0.05 and that's why it failed to reject
Are greater than that that's not hypothesis because there's no significant difference
So I hope it was helpful to understand whatever we learned to implement in the code if you had any problems or issues
Let me know and I'll get back to you for additional practice you can try to visualize the distribution of data
And highlight mean median and mode using matplotlib
You can perform hypothesis testing on real world data sets example comparing
Exam scores of two groups you can get these data from different websites
And you can calculate confidence intervals
Proportions in a data sets
Suggest to summarize today we learned statistical fundamentals focusing on central tendency
Dispersion hypothesis testing and confidence intervals by performing calculations and hypothesis testing we
Find hands-on experience with data analysis and decision making techniques and these are very important for
Some of the things that will be doing in the next few weeks