Day 7 Mad River mini project or linear regression from scratch is what you're going to do
So tell me three different things that we need to learn before even starting this
First is
Applying linear algebra
Calculus and statistics
So for linear algebra linear regression aims to fit a line
Are hyperplane
To minimize the error between predictions and actual values the mathematical model for this is
Makeup equal to x * thet
Where X is the feature Matrix with bias term
Data is the parameters which are
Weights and bias
And white
Is the predicted values
For calculus
Optimization of data
Involving in which involves minimizing the loss function that is defined as J Theta
Equal to 1/2 m
Summation of I equal to 1 to M for
White Cap i - Yee squared
And also the gradient of J Theater which is dead or nebula of J equal to 1
Switch to 1 upon MX ^ 3
X * 10 * -5
Next we also need statistics
Metrics like mean square error MSC and r-square
I used to evaluate the model performance so you don't look at each one of them in more detail
The first is
Using gradient descent for parameter optimization
Are the gradient descent algorithm goes something like this where iteratively updates Theta using
Data equal to Theta -
Alpha times Del of J
The alpha is the learning
The date and that controls the step size
The key steps involved
Initializing the parameters using Theta
Then we have compute the gradients which is Del of J
And update parameters
Using the gradient descent rule
Finally let's talk about evaluating the model using the statistics Matrix that you mentioned so we need
Which is MSC which is defined as 1 ^ 1 m
Salvation of I equal to 1 to m
Why can't I minus why I squared
Which measures the average Square Diner
And then we have r squared
Which is a square equal to 1 - SS / which
How well the regression line explains the variation variance in the data
So let's go ahead and do our hands on Project based on whatever you have learned
On linear regression from scratch
Will be following three different tasks task one
Is the implement the mathematical formula for linear regression
Next will use gradient descent to optimize the model parameters
Third task is to calculate the evaluation Matrix
So for task one so let's go ahead and first create
A project I'm going to create a new file
Save it in my D7 and I'm going to call it Mini
Project
Which is linear regression from search
From scratch
So first task as I mentioned
Ask one is
To implement
Mathematical
Formula
For linear regression
So this objective here is to create a function to compute the predictions so let's go ahead and write some
Code for that for that I'll say import numpy
S&P of course we're not going to do all the work here Will
Use some of the libraries that are available
And I
Create a credit function which will take the X which are are features and the
And will predict
By returning
NP
And here I'll pass X and data so that will take care of predicting for me so this
But that's all we need to do for task one or task to
Is
Use the gradient descent to optimize the model parameter so use
Gradient
Descent
To optimize
The model
Parameters
So here's the objective
Is to implement gradient descent to minimize the loss function
The examples of code can be returned something like this where I can say
Gradient
Decent
And it takes as
We've done before XY
Learning rate
And it relations that are required
To get optimized solution and I'm going to say m equal to
Land of why
And I'm going to go through each and every iteration here for underscore in
Range of
Iterations
I will go ahead and get the ingredients first gradients
Equal to from the formula that we saw one divided by m
NP
X dot T this is the summation thing that we did NP
Intuitive pass X and
And I'll put this entire thing
Inside a bracket
Say minus all right
Kia NP
Minus why
They close all of them properly no one more so yeah that's
My entire formula for that
Next I need Toyota
8 - 8 equal to
Learning rates this will give me the optimized value
Times gradient
And that's good and that will
Return back finally the Theta value
So I have that and finally
August
3 is 2 hours to I think
Look at it calculate evaluation Matrix so I'm going to say
Evaluation
Matrix
The objective here
Is to implement functions to calculate MSC which means whatever and r squared
So the code for that I can just
Underscore
Square underscore error
Which will give me
True Values
Why and why predicted values
So I can calculate the mean square error from there
And this will return
Underscore true
Minus
Why underscore bread
And square root of
√2
That's what I'll get here
And next for our
R squared I'm going to say
Define
Squared
Why underscore true
Call my wife
Corporate
Read this I need SS rest first
If you remember the formula from before
And this will be a sister is equal to NP
Why underscore true
Why underscore red
The squared so that's what I'll get next I need access underscore
Torch which is
MP Dot
And this I'll give the same values actually by underscore
Do it needs but
It will be
NP
Why underscore true
Sears Square it
That's the store now
To bring everything together 1 -
Asus underscore Aries
Divided by SS underscore
Cute little space
And that was our formula if you remember
From here 1 -
SSS upon as a store so that's the r squared so that's perfect
To put all of them together
Let's start from the top I'm going to generate some synthetic data
Sunset
Data
MP dot create a random seed
My favorite number 42
X equal to
NP dot random
Dot r a n d
100 to 1 237 random values
Y equal to
4 + 3
X +
Some bars m
Random
1000 comma 1
So there you go so we have that value
Next I want to create a advice term to the feature metrics
Feature Matrix
And that I can do by creating a variable X underscore b equal to NP Dot
Underscore and here I'll say NP
But once
Como one
Comma X so this will add bias term to our feature Matrix of x
Next let's go ahead and initialize the
That I can I need
I need a learning rate
And I need
Iterations
They started iterations less 2000 iterations learning rate let's 0.1
And for Theta
I will use NP create a random one dot
Random
And pass it to comma one
So that initializes my
Parameters now next step is
Actually we need the credit function so we have which we already have
We have the gradient descent we have the mean squared and r squared so let's go below
Perform
The perform the gradient descent
To do that you've done it before
In the previous videos
Cheetah optimized
Equal to call this function that you've returned
Classic X underscore B
Plus why
Pause theater
Will pass the learning rate
Angry pasta iterations
So that's what our function
Needs the gradient descent needs and that's what we have passed
So once you pass this okay I think there is some problem here
I called it iterations and iterations
So we just Studio code kind of
Shows you what is issues you have before even you there's any problems so that's good next one I'm going to do
Predictions and
Evaluations here
So to predict I'll create white bread
Equal to
Call the credit function
Classic X underscore B
And will pass the data optimized
Next MSC to get the mean square error
Since you have a vibrate now I'm going to call the mean square error
Pastor original Target values and the predicted values
There you go
Next to get a square I'm going to say are two equal to
Are underscore squared call that function that we wrote earlier
And password
Perfect
Now finally we can print all the three of these I can see a print first one is
Optimized
Parameters
Which is
Set
Is
Optimized which we get from line number 44 right here
Next I want to print
Let's see what is the mean square error MSC
Which I can get from MSC
Next I want to
Turn the r squared
That is
Comma
So that will give me my
So let's go back here
Clear it out
And say python
Project.com
And do you have an optimized parameters which is as long as it's between 4 and 3 that's good so
0.2 and 2.77 I mean square error is roughly
0.80 and 0.76 which is pretty good
So by completing this project we have gained a thorough understanding of linear regression
Ingredient decent and evaluation Matrix we also learned how to implement
Machine learning models from the first principles
Using python
So we did everything from scratch which is pretty awesome and I hope you are able to follow along
If you had any issues or any problems let me know and I can help you out if you have any
Suggestions or anything let me know about them too and I can add that to my videos
So I hope you were able to finish a week
Ford with all the different projects that you have done if you have any problems
Or any questions let me know and I'll get back