Hi
My name is my mother's day and welcome to my course
Identic architectures with Pat
Dream
What's an MC
In this
We are going to design an integrate
Multi agent system
Into our Enterprise applications
Using the AI AG
Identical
Agentic design patterns and frame
MC
Play Asante
An agent development life cycle
Enable design
Multi agent systems
What's for real world eShop micro
Let's look at our road map
Restart by building the found
Pictures of the agent
We will answer the fundamental question
How do
An AI AG
What are it is actual components
We will discard
A simple
Andrew agentic a
To understand the critical difference between
Play a tool and
We will download
The heartbeat of every agent
The Agency Group
We will trace the Journey of data through perception
Reason
I'm learn
To deep understanding of the AG
Internal philos
Once we understand the agent
The skate up to the system level
How agentic architecture work
And we will Deep dive into malt agent collaboration
Learning how to organize
Teams of agent
To solve a complex call
We will Master identical
Who's company major architectural
Like orcust
Kitchen and choreograph
We will survey
Unskippable of the agent framework
To choose the right foundation
Weather in San Ramon
What is all the Microsoft agent framework
Vivo dedicate a message
To understand AI agentic design patterns
These are reusable blueprint
That you will use to solve recurring problems
For example
Here you can see the planet but
We will see this pattern to understand
How an agent can decompose
A complex
Is the smaller manageable steps
And here you can see the reflection pattern
We will
How an agent Krispy Kreme
It's on
I need to cancel the
Add compound
And we will
A reason plus X
Combine in
To accomplish a goal
After understanding this pattern
We move to the Enterprise Integration lay
We will evolve traditional wreck into agency
Building
Since that can actively research and reason over your data
We will tackle the biggest challenge in the industry right now
Agent communication and protocol
We will deep dive into MC
Play the model context protocol ACP and a2a
I will explain you through
Is step-by-step going to MC
Show me how to build server
Did expose your ex
Can you sing AP
To any agent any
We will also Master contacts engineer
Which is the nearest city
Simple prompt engineering
With robust information are
Finally we look at the life cycle
Google define a agent develop
And the adrc
Since agent development life cycle
We will cover the heart Enterprise Department
Including the security
Evolution and operations
And we conclude with our
Steve Capstone
We will take everything we have
What does protocol spring
What's on life cycle
And we will Design and integrate
A multi agent system and agent regular application
Puerto Rico eShop Microsoft applic
So by the end of this course
You will not just be able to write an agency
You will be able to R
Integrate and
Which Android AG
What's for the Enterprise
You are about to make the transition from
A traditional developer to an agent architect
I'm incredibly excited to take this journey with you
Let's get