In this section
We are going to understand
Agentic design
This section will cover
Reflection Pat
Real composition
An introduction to multi-agent patterns including the router special
Is
Group chat today
Suburban and human interlude
Music play we will understand the way of the agent examples
And they have learned The Agency Group
Explore the system level architecture
I'm just completed a deep dive into major framework
Also we have mastered tattoos
Which is the home of boiling agent
Love you must Elevate our thinking from a developer to an architect
It is time to learn the bullet
What and why of agent design
This section is the game of 4:48
And we are here to
A form
Play for Designing global
Security
Unusual agent system
For the last few
The focus has been on prompt engine
This is a
But it is a tact
It is about crafting the perfect
Clever
Put a single
The problem
Is this approach is frag
Is Architects we cannot build an enterprise system on a clever prom
The most beautiful is a straight
Design a robot system of component
Agentic design patterns are
They are the standard Bruins strategies
For Building agentic Systems
Detachable testable
Unspeakable
Moving cars from the front engine
So now let's understand the
Why
Who's the Supreme Court versus batam
This is the most critical concept to understand in this
What is the difference between the Frameworks we have just learned
And the patterns we are about to learn
If it is a to
It is the
It is a concrete library of
Including Lion King landcraft
Microsoft agent frame
These are your
Where is empower
Appleton on the other
Is a blueprint
It is the
And
It is a conceptual reusable idea for solving
A common problem
For example the reflection pattern
Which is the idea of an agent critique
It's on
Isabella
You can Implement that bully print using any frame
When is all the framework agnostic
They are the pure architectural knowledge
So now let's understand the volume of agentic design Pat
So why do we dedicate an entire section to this
Portrait specific high volume
First one
Please put on give us a common VOC
This is essential for our
When I am in a design meeting and say
We
Use a water pattern to delegate to 3 specialist agents
You will know exactly what that architecture is
Second these are pro
Tested soul
You don't have to guess how to make an agent crit
It's on work
Reflection Pat
Is it
Proven bulletins for this
And finally
They are reusable bullet
Don't know that you gain here is not tied to one Library
You will be able to design and Implement these patterns in any framework
Making your architectural
Is too really portable
Let's understand our pattern catalog
Which is all Road
In order to guide us
I have organized this entire section
Is a formal pattern catalog
Which we will explore
Lecture by Le
What's in the part 1
We will establish the foundations by learning to call agentic Design principles
Did Governor old Pat
Done in the part
We will Master the core agent
The blueprints that Define
When have a single agent thinks and
Vevo DED
A full lecture to each one
Reflection
Andrea compound pattern
So after that in the party
Play music scale up to Malta agent pattern
Analyzing to blueprints for building teams of collaborating Agents
We will cover delegation patterns
Like rotten special
As well as the advanced collaboration patterns like
Group chat and Suburban Pat
Done in the password
We will cover what is for Arch
The most critical group
The control and safety
This is what we will learn how to make non-deterministic agents
Say for production
Focusing on women in the loop