In this video
We are going to learn
Agentic design princ
That
We must first understand the fundamental
Before learning to design
And these are the identification
We will
14 principal in this lecture
So these are the
Go Direct
Real
An auton
So let me
Stop the first one
Which is the gold
In this principle
The agent is defined by its purpose
A traditional program is instruction driv
You must delete exactly what to do
What an agent is gold
You give it a high level objective
Do you like
A 3-day trip to London
And you are not providing the
You are providing the destination
The agents primary function
Use its reasoning capability to discover and execute the steps
Required to achieve this
And for us is archit
This
The goal is the single most important input to our entire AG
And we can go to the second principal
Which is the react
An agent must be reactive
Does Drake
Steps to the perception
Please off The Agency Group that we have studied
Being reactive means
The agent is not just running
Explain blind
It is constantly pursuing its environment
The environment includes the user
But just as importantly
It includes the results of its own action
If an agent calls a
And get another
A traditional program might
Reactive agent persistent
On Disney information trig
What's the next reasoning
It might reason that
It needs to try a different tool or ask the user for a clarification
These reactive cycle is essential for robust
And the next principal is
State
An AG
Must be stable
This is the memory component of our agent an
State is the glue that connects One agent to the
We thought
Every user message will be day
And the Agents would have no
Dissipate includes the original
The church story
A look of all postal codes and it is internal
Secret of thought
For us is Arch
This is a critical design point
State Management
What is a core problem
The most
Listen to design and build a memory system for our agent
Whether it's a simple object or the complex database
Is the purses
Close this reaction
And our final principle is autonomy
What's
It is not so much separate principle
Is it is the emergent property of the first three principal
Because an agent is gold Direct
Its destination
Because it is reactive it can see the road
The inner obstacles
Because it is state
Where it has already been
When you combine these three
You get the system that can
Is on to make progress
It can drive the car
We thought you touching the City Link bill at every
Turn on architectural responsibility here is to give the agent agency
Which is the actual formation and capability to execute its own decisions
Is there somebody we can say that
No principle exist in isolation
The goal defines the
Reactivity
Wait what
State Prov
What happened before
An autonomy is the
Which is the ability to execute the decision
These four principles
Form the engine of our