In this video
We are going to learn
The tool used Pat
If you look at the typical agent
Another
Is the brain of the
Set another alarm is just a brain in a jar
You can't think
But it cannot Act
The tool used pattern is the architectural blueprint
For giving that brain
To interact with the
Do you understand this button
You must first appreciate the core problem
A large language model
Is a text in text
It is effectively locked in a box
It cannot produce
It cannot clear your companies in Metro database
You cannot even tell you the current date or
It is entire reality is the text we
So the fundamental
What's the question is
How do we connect
Is this powerful brain
Do a real world cup and data
The answer is the tallest
Which we will also hear referred as a function call
The tool used pattern is a three-part architect
It is not just one thing it is a system
First we need a Sikkim
This
A special machine readable description of Art
It is
What is
On what parameters
Second behavioral alarm itself
Which X is the chooser
Based on the user score
The alarm be the reason and decide
To answer
The gate weather
On the third one we have the orchestrator
This is our own code that manage this Pro
It takes the alarms decision
Execute the actual python function
Get the result
On
What's the status back to the alarm for
Did you cancel the image on the slide
Sigma alarm and orkest
We are listening to
Who's the Jason responds
And in the Atlanta
We selected
Who's going to Define and reasoning
I need the
Is 330
Musically execute the function
Listen and get the result
Return back to the alarm to generate a particular resp
So now let's look at the each mechanism one by
The first and the most important part of this pattern
You must make our quote visible to the alarm in a language it understand
We do this by defining
Open the Json object
It is passed to the alarm
Assistant prom
DC camo mask contain three
First is the function name
Stream like a weather
2nd a description
This is the most critical piece
A crystal
Natural language description of
What the
Description is what the alarm uses to decide
If this tool is useful
On the third one is a list of parameters
Including today's type and description
This Sigma is essential
Are two for the alarm
Now
Let's look at the part
Which is the LSU
The alarm at 6:30 or router
Is internal thought
It receives the user
What is the weather in London
Second
What's a candle list of the
Mickey Mouse we provided
It
Do you say school is about
I see a tool called gate weather
Whose description
It is for this exact Purp
Deadpool record
Is City paramet
Do you just call Merchant lond
Therefore I
How cold is
So this is the
What time is action
And this is the key
It doesn't respond to the user
It's action is to out
Play special Json object
That represent it is decision
Here you can find example of Jason
Including the function name and the argument
This is the function called behaving talking about from the alarm
So the last part is orchestrated role or we can
Executor
Which is the final part of the pat
Is the orchestrator
And this is the code we are responsible for writing
The orchestrators job is simple but critical
First it received that structure Jason to call from the alarm
Is it supposed to Jason to get the tools name and its arguments
Turn it maps that name to actual real python function we have defined in our code
What is executive function
For example it calls or get rid of function with the argument as a lond
Finally it takes the return value from that function
Let's eat big to the alarm is the input for the next reasoning group
The Island Building perceive Disney information
And formulate the final answer to the US
Is there somebody we can say that
Please put on including Sigma 11 and orchestrator
And this pattern has major architectural indication for us
First the description field in your two Sigma
Is a form of front engine
ABC design description
When is the 11 will fail to use your
Second is the security
Dorchester must be a security gate that will
Is all parameters coming from the non Dieter
Finally error handling is a part of the
Should return descriptive error messages as a set