In this video
We are going to learn
The planning Pat
In the last lecture we learn to do this but
But what happens
What's going to use the school is not a single query
What a complex multi-step project
For example a girl
Research the
Play sci-fi books from the last year
Find a
Unset the final
List to my email
Disconnect be sold by a single tool call
Please record a seconds of action
This is where the feeling put on become essential
You need to cancel that we will first and make a plan
And this will be
Several
Ask that we are going to EXE
Repeat one by
So let's understand what is the planet pattern in here
The planet is formally defined as the process of using the alarm
Reasoning capability
In order to decom
Does a high level goal
Into an explicit order list of the executable steps
This is a critical shift in how we use the alarm
We are no longer just asking it for the final answer
You're not using it as a
We are asking you to think
First and create a to-do list
That it will follow
So this plan is just dat
It can be a simple number
What is the old
Why should Jason a ray of tool
How do we get to LA
Turn to generate this
Do you use anything technique which
Chain of
Not an instructor
Step by step
So instead of just giving it
We give it to gold
What's an instruction like
First grade AP
And then execute the first step of your
So after that you can see the alarm
Internal monolog
This will be
Play Tuesday
And after that execute this plan step by step
So now
See this cleaning pattern into gemini.com
If you go to gemini.com
You can come here and open the front window
Basically I have selected the thinking
And I'm going to write to
Research the top
Is Skyfall
Then find a
And understand
List to my email
So you can see that the front design for the Chain of Thought and if
Do you click the song in the
Is you can see
Please set alarm
Start with planning
That's enough to that EXE
Please play mama
If you expand this process you can
This will be starting to
Including
Determining top titles
Sing two limitations
Listing relevant book
Discover
Disconnect my favorites and so on
This is the
And Chain of Thought internal monologue of the alarm
Before responding to
So basically
We will follow
Chain of Thought and cleaning Pat
And this will be returned
The final response including the old
Books and prices
Does Inkling
The final answer
So
In this button with Clinic button
The orchestrated which is the alarm
Resident Evil
So we can say that Disney hotel
Is all orchestrated
Isn't even more complex row
It can no longer be stateless
It must now it is a state machine
Where is my sister the full plan the llm generated
Typically in the agent's memory
Second it must take the agent's current progress
For example we are on Stephan of
Eat execute only the current
What's the steps result on feed
For the next
Set the alarm 10 perceived this new information
Play its plan and
Okay Stephanie is complete now for Step 2
Diesel plan
Make OB
Continue playing is the foundation of the advanced agents
And the plan
What's the store in the agents memory
Sona we should understand
And healthy design planning process is Arch
Where's our system from is no longer just about
It is about the process
Music the instructor AG
To break down problems
How to create
And
Please plan management
Any required capability
Are orchestrated must be stateful
Unmanage the plants life cycle
And the third one is hunting failures
This button introduced in
What is Stefan suc
What's the two
We should manage these hunting failures
Is there somebody that we can say that
If the tool used for 10 years or agent hand
Underpinning button
Change the agent an internal mon
It is the
Play to drink before it acts and decom
What's a logical intersection of the small manageable actions
This is the difference between
Reflective AG