In this video
We are going to learn
The reflection pattern
In the last video of we have learned to planning but
Which gives our agent an internal monolog
To create any multi-step
Hollywood
It's to any more subtle architectural problem
What is the agent follows the plant perfectly
What's the result is simply low quality
Do plants
But the output is
Incomplete
Whirlpool little
How does an agent
Its owner is any
So is the solution we are going to learn reflection Pat
Here you can see that after generating the first responds
We are going to reflect
Play NCR
This is
And create a new Loop into here
So now let's consider a scenar
We give our agent a
Write a 500 word block
About the benefits of the microser
And the agent create a simple plan
Search for the benefit
And second right to
Is ex
Use this plan perfect
But the problem is the resulting blog post is bad
It is repeat
It
Play key points about scalability
And it is Stone
But as far as the agent is conc
Is follow the plan and produce the out
It will report success
This is a quality blind AG
It is no mechanism for self-assessment
This is what the reflection pattern
So now let's understand
What is the reflection
The solution is a pattern based on the human concept of
Metacognition
Which simply mean
Thinking about your own
The reflection Pat
Is an
Speak to the blueprint
Did Force the agent
To pause after it generate an
Eaton initiate a second
Separate Pro
Who's on the job is to critique that output
Against the original
And a set of quality criter
This
When is the agents internal quality assurance
It is the mechanism
Achieve the agents
Did I complete the
Is to die
Play at the gold
This is the blueprint for self correction and iter
The most common and effective implementation of
Off this button is the writer critic model
This is a simple two-part workload
Do you have the
This is the agent we have been designing
It is the door
Increase the plan and generate the first draft of the output
Second do you have the
This is the key to the pattern
The critic agent is a separate subsequent alarm called
It is given a different specialized front
It is prompt is something like
You are an expert editor
Review the text draft
Which was written to achieve this go
Is it
Is it complet
What is specific feedback for improvement
So the critic agent is essentially just another agent
But one that is specialized for reflection
So this writer critic model creates a powerful Network
An inner loop of the self improve
Hear how it
Basically the writer agent produced the draft
And this
Is not sent to the user
Instead it is rotten to the critic agent
And after
The critic AG
Review the draft
And produce a crit
Are orchestrated than read this
And this will be start from the secret
If the critic is not completed
So if the critic
Is the draft is excellent
The orchestrator rods into the user is the final answer
Into critic ident
What's the orchestrated
What's go to original
And the new critic back to the writ
Vietnamese instruction
Please revise your
Based on this
You can see the image on the slide
This is the
Are deflection
We are going to start
With the writer agent
And this will be
Create a draft
And this will be go to the critic agent
Provide a feed
And this is the inter
They provide to excellent answer and
I want to do
So that
This cycle can repeat a loving the agent to iterate and refine its
From the draft 1 to 12
All before the user
And this is the inner loop of the self-improvement
So now let's understand how to design reflection process
This is
Is are
Makes the most understand the tradeoffs of this Pat
First this button is expensive
It is powerful but
Is it
Each reflection Loop is by definition
At least one additional full alarm call
This will significantly increase your token
And your overall
Second floor orchestrator must be able to handle this complex
Play a simple dinner chain can't do this
You need a state overclock engine
That can
Make the Cy
Is rotting output from a
First Step which is the crit
Back to another
Play which is the writer
This is exactly what Frameworks like landcraft are
Finally your front engineering
Just expand
You know how to design and maintain multiple personals
A writer
Focus on a
An acoustic Plan Focus on High level objective review
Is it somebody we can say that
The planning pattern gives the agent an internal mon
Reflection pattern gives the agent an internal Krit
To improve the quality of
Play spin output
This is the difference between
A first draft AG
And the final draft agent
It is a foundation pattern for building
Sing label high quality