In this video
We are going to learn
Connect compound Pat
Do you have learned the reflection pattern
Change
An internal critic for cual
No we are going to see
What happens when you combine
Link and tools into a single
Powerful
This combin
Which is not any idea
It is a formal pattern you
You see everybody
Moon is
Here you can see the image on the
Light basic
Play the music sound equity
It will start listening
I'm creating plan and step
And after that it
What acting
Basically
Play EXE
Read the task using the tools
Enough
It will start to observing
According to observing this will be repeating disease
Again started listening and creating plan
This is the red button
Reason 8 observed and repeat
So now let's understand
Not the core problem
Why this pattern is required
So now
What's the ark scenario
Which is the goal of the point is the top three sci-fi
Is it normal that we have seen this goal in the
Anything
It's a full master plan up front
For example
Search for the book
Email
But this
A significant architecture problem
This plant is beautiful
What happens if the
First Step which is the search
Face or return
What's 0 results
The
Light the following it
Is static
Will proceed to step
And try to email an empty
It is Faith the users in
Even
Give it full of teeth
So the core question is
How do you create a pattern that is more adaptive
How can AG
Route to the result of each
The solution is the red butt
Which stands for the reason plus Act
It is a compound pattern
Meaning it is built from other patterns we have already known
Is simply Intel leaves planning and acting in a very tight continuous
Instead of the making one big plan of
The agents logic looks like this
First reason
The agent generates a
A tiny plan for just the very next
Second
The agent immediately execute that one step using a tool
Turn off
The agent perceives the result or error from Deadpool
And finally repeat
It fits that observation back into the reason
Is to decide
And this is one fundamental shift from the plan then execute
Play continu
Put on egg observe
So now
Deconstruct
Israel
Direct pattern is not Magic
It is just a clever combination of our existing patterns
Air Force by a specific
Home structure
The reason
Where the alarm Jenner
Is simply are planning pattern in miniature
We are asking it
Sing step by step
But only for the next step
The ACT face by the llm generates an action
Is just our tool use Pat
It is the structure Jason output for the function call
Direct AG
Is simply an agent who's
Horses eat to always
Is output its response in a thought and action
This makes its internal monologue explicit and machine readable
What's today's this entire flow in a simple example
Do you
What is the weather in London
I'm in Loop
The alarm
I need to find the weather
And
What putting a call to cold weather London
Are orchestrated execute this
And get the result like 25 centigrade
In route
Are orchestrator takes these observation
It's it's big to the alarm
The 11
It reason
I now have the information I need to answer the US
Ethan X by generating the final human readable answer
So this is why we call
What is a compound Pat
It is the architecture of glue that holds the other patterns together
It is simple red meaning
Planning
Tool
And repeated in a
But we can also add our reflection pattern right into the same
In advance that group might be
Most recent about I will write the book
Acting by calling the right will look for function
Turn observe it on draft
Reason which is the reflect
This route is
My next action will be to call the critic drive to
You can see that
What is not a single pattern
But the operating system or engine that allows the
Sing tool
On reflection
Do all work together in a dynamic and adaptive C
Is are
Next the three dogs here are critical
First read is slow and expensive
Every single step of the
On every tool
Record a full round trip and alarm
If I Stay plant is
Is 5:11
But the benefit is
What do you buy for that
Does Rob
Because the agent reason after every observation
You can handle failure
If a tooth
It doesn't just
It knows it
I can try a different approach on the very next
This also means are orchestrated code is doing the most work
Managing this complex group of parsing executing
I'm feeding database
This is the agent executor USA in framework
Is there somebody we can say that
That is not an import
And what a compound of the planning and
It is Magic is the orchestration loop that fits the observation back to the top step
Dis
An Adaptive
And that can react to its environment
What is better