In this video
We are going to learn
Multi-agent design pattern
Do you master the car pattern
That make a single agent intelligent
We thought it was used
To create
An even to reflect on
It's omberg
What is a problem is too big or too complex
For one
If we need teams of Agents
Did specialize in different tasks
Is it considered Behavior complete the court agent Pat
And we are going to start multi agent
But before that
Let's understand
Why we need multi agent Pat
And this leads to a natural architectural question
If one agent is good
Is one
Super agent even better
Should we try to do it
On monolithic agent with 52
The temperature
And the ability to do everything from
To Res
To customer support
Is are
Is vino immediately
This is a bad idea
This is the morning design trip
I need space for AG
Just as it
What is for software
Tonight
Is a single super agent
Is an architectural anti pattern for several critical reason
Prompt complex
The system
Unmaintainable monster
In worst
You will get prompt delete
Where conflicting instructions like
Be a creative copywriter
NBA precise a square WR
Did confuse the
And the
It's perform
What's on
The second important consideration is
Contacts window limit
Did Jason sakima for 50 different tools
Good cons
30,000 to
Before the user has even tied a single word
Third one and the most important thing for an Arctic
It creates a mercy single point of fail
If tomorrow at 6:00 agent gets conf
The entire system grinds to
Debugging be
A guessing game inside a giant
Non-deterministic Black Box
The solution of course
Is the same one we
In all other form of the complex engine
Decomposition
Turn on specialization
They don't do it one more
Play super agent
A digital
A system of multiple similar
Specialized AG
Dead collab
This is the definition of
Multi agent architecture
Do you stop thinking like a plant engineer
Trying to beat one perfect work
Restart thinking like an archit
Designing an organization
This immediate results are problems
Each agent now has a
Simple Focus
Each agent has only two or three tools it need
On each agent becomes a small testable
And replaceable component
In a larger
So one of the first and most important reason to use a multi agent system is
Specialization
Dismiss each agent in our system is designed
I'm too late to do one thing perfectly
You would win a research AG
That only has a search
And it is Pronto to be
Play through an objective
You will have a separate copywriter agent
This is no tools at all
What is Pronto to be creative and
And you will take a legal AG
And that is prompted to be precise and risk averse
These benefits here is a massive increase in quality and reliability
You get the best of the worlds without the prom
Heat of a monolithic agent
The second reason is
Polarization
If a user's request contains
Two or more
That do not depend on each other
A multi
System can
I'm concur
Imagine a go
Research on top three compet
And also find the latest tech news
Demolition will have to do this sequentially
First it research to competitors
Which takes 10 seconds
Then it finds
Which takes additional 5 Seconds
And the total time for the user is
What is 15
A multi agent architect
Can have these two independ
Ask to do two different specialist AG
And random in parallel
For example agent
Researchers competitors
What's on at the same time Agent P find the
The total time for the user is now only 10 seconds
Which is the time of the longest task
This is a huge performance
On the third major reason is debate and crit
We have already learned about the reflection pattern
What an agent tries to crit
It's Amber
But a far more powerful implementation is to have another
Specialized AG
8 is the
This is the writer critic model we have discussed
One agent the writer agent produces
A first
The system that passes this
Talk to the different agent
Which is the critic agent
Who's the only job is to find the floors
This feedback is the best back to the writer agent for revision
These team-based reflection is a Cornerstone of
High quality agent system
And it is a direct result of multi agent design
To summarize these three powers
Specialization
Polarization
UND
Are the
They are the reason we accepted complexity of a malt Asian architecture
That
Is the patterns we are about to cover in this section of the house
So we will learn
The specific architectural blueprint
Let's make this collaboration possible
Including the router and specialist pattern
Hand off but
Group chat about