In this video
We are going to learn
The router and special
In the last lecture
We learn the voice of the multi agent
Renault face our first practical architectural problem
Behave
Is a team
Specialist
One for customer support
One for the rez
When an interview is the request comes in
Like when is my order
How does our system know to
Let's talk to the support agent
Nothing in Montreal
This is the rotting problem
The solution is our first multi agent design Pat
Which is the router
How special is
This button is a delegation model
Not a collaboration
You can think of it as a manager worker relationship
It is composed
Two very different type of the AG
You have your specialist AG
These are the work
These are the AG
Does behave already
Like a support agent or inventory
The key is
Which one is highly specialized
It is a simple prompt focused on one
Up and only the tools for the
Second you have the router agent
This is the manager of traffic
The AG
It is job is not to answer the user's question
It is only job is to analyze the user's request
Classify its in
I'm done delegate to
Ask to the
You can't see the image on the slide the user credit accommodate from the router AG
And then this will be classified
An assigned to
I appreciate specialist agent
So now let's look at
Specialist
These are the worker agents that is simple pho
System
The support agent
Assistant problem
You are helpful support agent and it only has access to the get older status and process refund
The amount of the agent is a prom dress
Your animal to EXP
And it only has access to the check
Look and get product details to
This specialization makes them highly reliable and easy to
They cannot get confused and try to call the wrong tool
So now let's dive to the lottery
Here is the name and the most important
Which is the weather
It is only tool is a simple function
Something like Road
Which takes the chosen destination is an R
These agents system plant is completely different
Is explicitly
You are a router you must not answer the user's question
Your only job is to classify the users intent
And choose one destination from a provider list
Including the support
Inventory or general fold
This phone for State alarm
To act as a simple
On first classifier
It is not reasoning about a complex star
It is just categorizing
Let's trace this workload
Don't start to
I used to ask
Do you have the new
6000 laptop in
And this quick
Go to the rotary agent first
Are the rotors and alarm is called Peter from
To Simply classify this
And the alarms output is a tool
Broadcast
Destination inventory
Are orchestration called catch the
It sees the destination is inventory
Ethan forwards the user's original quitting
To the inventory
The inventory agent wakes up for the first time
And it sees the query and begins its own red
Thinking
I need to check stock for the
6000 product
And I'm calling
Next talk
The daughter it is Justin is now Idol
This is a clean beautiful separation of concern
So now is archit
We should understand the implications of these architecture Pat
This is the microservice architecture Pat
But for the agent
It gives us the incredible maintainability if you need to add a new billing capability you just
Read any isolated billing AG
It's on
The only other change you make is adding billing to the rotary engines
List of the body destinations
No other agent is
This is the massive architectural
Second this button is highly efficient
The first router
Is extremely fast and cheap
After
You are only paying the expensive token and latency
For
What specialist AG
And this is actually needed
Finn
Specialist agent can be a unit tested in complete isolation
Making your system for more
Is there somebody we can say
This is the fundamental pattern for delegation in multi agent system
It directly implement
The specialization principle
Underwater which is the
Cheap classified agent
Special
Focus libel and worker
This is your deaf
Go to pattern for building any complex multifunction AG