In this video
We are going to learn
The hand of Pat
In our last
Should we have
Route
This is a powerful delegation model
But what happens when a user stick
Isn't a single
What if it is a multi-step process
So now let's understand what is the hand of Pat
The hand of
When is best underst
What is the assembly line pattern
It is a multi agent architecture
What is
What's through a
Play determined seconds of specialist agents
Do floaties always go with the agent
PNC to the final output
Change this will be
On hand of the
Ask AG
Put on hand of the task agent today
So the core mechanism is the hand of
The final
Bluetooth off the agent
For example a list of the search results
Is captured by the orchestrator
And becomes the primary input for the agent
For example the text to be some
So the key distinction from our last picture is
This is not a dynamic choice
The pattern is not about classification
It is about formalizing a process
So how does this
Does actually work
It is not
It is
Explorer orchestration code
The orchestrator uses a workflow state or
What's the secret
To pass the dat
First orchestrator close to agent
Play with the initial user credit
An agent a runs its food
And eventually returns its final answer
Let's say call it to the result a
The orchestrator catch this result and
Can you eat to the
And then orchestrator immediately
Was agent
Using the result
Is the name in
An Agent P
Finish
And returns to
Result
Is Kohl's return pest cycle continues until the last agent in the assembly line is
So now let's trace a complete example
Write a blog post about the future of AI
We can design a three agent chain for this
First the research AG
It is input is the topic
Is Ross it is red
Search the
And is its final output is just
What's a 500 word block of Road
Next on the
And the second one is the drafting AG
Dorchester hands of that road
Today's AG
It is input is the output from the research agent
It is front is you are a writer
Turn this road text into a fast structured blog
It is output is a formatted
And the third one is the editor AG
The orchestrator
Hand of the draft to this agent
It is front
You are an edit
Proofread this post for grammar and
It is output is the final
Police article
Which is the return to the user
This is a clean simple a powerful assembly line
Did you can see the image on the
User Center
Write a book
And this will be accommodated by the research AG
What's the date research agent performed their
And hand of this
Let's do the drafting
I'm dropping agent perform their tasks
And after
Handle the task
Go to the editor AG
An 87
And perform the task and return results to the US
Is Arch
Is we should understand the trade-offs of these hand of
The primary benefit of this pattern is liability and determin
Because the pet is
You know exactly what is going to happen
In what order
There are no surpris
This makes the hand of Pat
The perfect choice
For automating no stable business processes
It is also simple to breathe and test
The trade off of course is
Is rigid
Do pattern is brittle by Design
It is 0 Flex
If agent a face
The inside is tender
Can grinds to a
Or
Is a different agent
Is my solo
This is fixed
Is there somebody we can say that
The hand of the time
Next sequential pets for a
It is the second
80 Thomas the civilization principal in a chain
The core mechanism is the output to in
Put hand of via the orchestrator
Use case perfect for
Stable
Benefit
Is reliability and three dogs