In this video
We are going to learn
The group chat debate
In the last lecture we have
Turn water on hand of
Rodger butt
A miniature delegate
Hello but
An orchestra
What's through
A sandal
In both of these pattern
The agents are Sill
They never talk to each other
They only report back to the orcust
What if the problem is too comp
Next for a simple hand
What is the best solution
Isn't known in advance
What if
Needs to be discovered through discussion
Critic and Deb
This
Has any architecture
Nothing is under
Find what a digital meeting room
This is the group chat debate Pat
Most famous intimated in Microsoft autism frame
So now
It's clearly
Understand what is the group chat debate
The group chat button is best understood
Is a digital Round Table
We are no longer defining a fixed technical path
We are creating a virtual meeting room
An inviting a team of Specialists agents into
So this is a multi agent Pat
There are two or more specialist agents
What initiate conversational context
A chat room
In order to collectively solve a problem
The goal is no longer
To just execute a predefined process
The goal is to discover the best possible solution
By 112 agents
To talk to each other
In each other's
On crit
Each other's flaws
This is a fundamental shift from a fixed workflow
To a dynamic conversational Loop
Where the final solution emerged from the interaction
So now let's understand the core components of this Pat
This button introduced any critical component
To prevent total cost
First you have
Specialist AG
These are the participants in the meeting for example
Call our family
Research AG
Write an AG
Critique AG
And maybe I could write to the
Second one you have the
Can you chat
The state of the World Cup
The whiteboard in the meeting room
Every
Switch from every agent is posted here
So old
You can see the full history of the conversation
Turn on the most important one
You have the group chat manager
You can't just let all the agents talk at
The manager
What is the modulator
It's the entire church history
And it is only job is to
Change the turn taking
Etc
Okay based on the last message
Who is the next agent
So now let's
Is this debate Loop in practice
Basically a user ask for a 3-part new marketing plan
And after that the group chat manager
Start the
It says n
Planet
Said you're up and create a
And the planet agent
Write a drop
Including the social media email and
So this message posted today
And the manager reads
And it is internal logic decided
A draft EX
It must be
Music
Review this plan
And acoustic agent
This plan is to Jenner
Unlike debt
Enough to that manager
What's the crit
Undecided
A Critic exist
The original
Master device
So it says again
Calendar AG
Dubai is your plan based on this feedback
Entrepreneur agent writes draft
Which is much more detailed
And this
What's critique and revise
Continue
Old moderated by the group chat manager
Until a thermostat is
For example
If the critical agent finally says that
This plan is
Then this result
This comes to the end
So this is the reflection pattern
What's supercharged by multiple distinct agents
Is Architects we should understand the architectural implication of this
The benefit is incredible
You get a video high quality solution that emerged from the debate
Because the loop is flexible
It can
What do complex or poorly defined problems
Detergent of button would instantly fail
So now let's understand the disadvantages
This button is expensive and slow
Every single turn in that debate
Is there a full alarm
Is that
Turn alarm
Furthermore
It is non-deterministic and can be a cop
You risk AG
Sing stuck in
Those can be arguing forever
This lick off the control
Is it very difficult to
Call any significant risk for production systems
Is there somebody we can say that
This button en
Does through Dynamic collaboration between AG
Eat
Please play with a moderated conversation Loop
And the key components are
Specialist agent
A group chat manager
Which is the weather
Which state
And use case perfect for complex
Play or fully defined problems
Is that equal
Play is the number one priority
An example of this pattern could be designed a new software product