In this video we are going to learn
The Swamp Attack
You know last text
We learned group chat but
Digital meeting room
Design for Creative debate
It is powerful for improving quality
But it is fundamentally sequential
Are agents speak at a time
It is
Deliberate
An exp
But what if our problem
Isn't creatively comp
Next bus just massive
What if
You're not trying to design any marketing plan
What if artist
10,000
Article published yesterday
You don't need a debate for this
You don't need a handle
We need an army of Agents all working
At the same time
This is the Suburban
So now let's understand this one pattern in debt
This one pattern is based on the
Put is a beehive or an anime
It is an architecture but a central Queen
What is the poor
It takes a massive
List
How's life process 10,000 of these file
And decompose it into 10,000 small
Identical soft
Ethan's Farms or em
Thousands of worker agents
To execute all these sub
What's in peril
The entire goal is
Is achieve a
Can you speak
On what we call in computer science
Listen to parallel problems
Tusk that can be broken up and required no communication between the workers
The golden
This is the map red
Design pattern applied to AI Pat
So now let's understand
The mapreduce architect
This button has two distinct
Is both managed by our Queen
The first is the map
This is decomposition and distribution
The queen agent
Takes the large
Like 1,000 report
What's a
Is iterates the list and spawns one worker agent for
The broken agents logic is simple
Summarize the one report you are given
The second is the reduced
This is aggregation and synthesizers
Do queen agent wait for all a thousand workers
To finish and return their individual summaries
Ethan collects all these results
Finally it reduces them by performing One Last Action
Such as writing a metal summary of all the individual summaries
Into a single final output for the user
This is 1.10 in
So basically our task
Summarize a thousand articles in this folder
First of all
The queen agent EXE
Is the Memphis
It doesn't read the articles
It's simply
Decomposed the list into
1,000 individual subtask
And
The worker agent execute in peril
Are orchids
What's 1,000 instance of our so many agent
And this might be massive a single import
Or it could be 1,000 separate serverless Cloud function
Each worker receives one document
And some r
And return to the result
On the third
The queen agent begin
Is the reduce phase
What is 4000 parallel process
To complete
Ethan
Call 1,000 individual summ
Into one Mass
Finally
The queen agents synthesizes the result
It
Is one final alarm call
Feeding it all it doesn't summaries
Video front
Write one page executive summary of
What is 8,000 some
And this final aggregated answer
Is what's returned to the user
And is archit
Is this button is a classic
The benefit is obvious and singular massive speed and
It can be literally thousands of
I'm faster than trying to Pro
Is in a single circulation
And the limitations however
What are
It only works for
Embracing the parallel
The workers cannot talk to each other
If they need to
This button
And doodles are also important for this one but
Is profoundly expensive
8,000 parallel workers
1,000 simultaneous API call
Provider
You are trading time for money
And most importantly for us
This is an orchestration night
This is not a simple for Loop
This is a complex a synchronous parallel
You must design for
What happens if work
532 pill
Does the Hole Cafe
Do you retry just that one job
What about API rate
Kids can you make a thousand
Advance
This is a significant engineering challenge
Is there somebody we can say that
This is important is want to end parallel processing
It is the mapreduce architecture for agents
The components are a queen
Which is the decomposer aggregated
Underwater executed agent
Use case perfect for Mass
List
Independent
Example of
Analyze a thousand of document
Process a thousands of
Play-Doh
You
Is it cost and complexity
What is repeat