In this video
We are going to learn
Control and save the pat
What was the last several Le
Behave design AG
Reflect and Tool
We have architected multi agent systems
Dead can delegate
Run assembly lines
Change creative Deb
Forms of parallel work
In short we have unlocked the immense autonomous power
And that take the
Should make any responsible software architect extremely ner
No we must address
The Mercedes that comes with this
This brings us to the Enterprise logic of agentic design
Which is the control and safety
We have finished the foundation
Call agent Pat
Is a malt agent pattern
Now we will
Turn control and save the
But before
Let's understand
At the core problem of the danger of the non determinism
Traditional software is determinist
The same input will produce
Is the exact same output every single time
It is predictable
What is antique AI is non Dieter
We can
What is prawns and pattern
But we can never 100% guarantee
What it will do or say
This is the
For the first time we are Building Systems
What college component
Is unpredictable by Design
And this unpredictability
Create massive business
So now let's understand the real
Put Enterprise
That means we will make
Switch to concrete
What happens when
What's the best
Is is catastrophically wrong
What about the financial
An agent misread a typo in a user sequence
An issues
100,000 ref
Instead of the
What about the data integrity
An agent is told to clean up old users
An
What's 93.6 wisdom
This means deleting all users
Including the active paying customers
Or what about the security
A username
Ask for my customer data
And the agent hopefully provides the data
Put a different customer also named John
Also there is a reputational
An agent goes
And send offensive
Manchester message to your client
So that means we can never under any circumstances
Give a non deterministic agent
Put on check control over the production enterprise system
It is simply not an option
But this situation
Prevent us Vita dilem
Do you want the auten
Is magical problem solving power of the agent
But we cannot accept the
Switch off it is not determin
The wrong solution is to
This
Removing all its dangerous
Clipping its abilities
Is enforcing it to only answer simple questions
This is
But it also destroy
Play all the volume we have been trying to build
You are left with just another simple chatbot
Direct
Turn the architect solution
East
Play Guardian
Delete the agent Drive
Barbie movies
Deterministic
If the system around
The Arctic check
Is an overrides into the work law
Our goal is not to prevent
Add autonomy but to enable
In order to achieve
We will master
Two most important safety patterns in all agentic design
First the human in the loop
This is the are you sure but
The Egyptian or custom logic Pat
This is the stop button or the Escape