In this video we are going to learn
Human interlude
Do you know that
The non-deterministic nature of the alarm
Create unacceptable
Including Financial
Operation and reputational
No we will architect the primary solution
This button is your are you sure but
It is the copilot model
Where the agents suggest an action
What a human must approve
This is the human in the loop pattern
And it is the foundation of the building
Responsible AI system
Now let's see this pattern in debt
Human in the loop at 10 is not an error or an
It is a deliberate design feature
The metaphor is the are you sure button or the copilot confirm
It is an architectural pattern
Barbie intentionally engineer
A pause into the identical
Disposed or checkpoint
Is triggered by the agent proposed
A high risk action
And wait for
6% human April
Before Pro
The goal is simple
We are introducing deterministic human judgment
Right before
An invisible action occur
The agent suggest
And the human app
Just give us
The agents problem solving power
We thought it
Unacceptable
This is not a failure state
It is a design picture
Can you cancel the
Is your mom
Let me hear our doctor agent use
And basically agent examine the
What is an image for patient
And you come out some medicine
But
And get real human doctor approval in
So now let's understand the checkpoint architecture
The problem is
How does an agent
When to ask for
A common mistake is to try and from the agent
Ask for
If something dangerous
This is a terrible idea
Is it relies on the non-deterministic llm
To be its own
The correct way is to build this as a hard Cod
Deter
In all orchestrator in our workflow log
Here you can see the
First of all
Agent
It reasons and generate a plan
Like a Json object
Call the
And the second step
Is orchestrated
Inter
What's this
Before calling the to
What's the orchestrator
What's a simple
Determine
Make each statement
If the two name is refund customer
And the amount is greater than or a thousand dollars save the threshold
The first step then the orchestrator
What does the word
And transition to a bait for human April state
It might send a message to select Channel or the dashboard
If the rule is not met
It just proceeded
So now let's see human in the loop girl club in action
We will see this example
364 with all 10,000
Did you find example
First of all is he can see that
Do you just send an email message
I want my money
Second
Reason about
Define the order
Decrease volume is 10,000
And this
Call the refund
For 10,000
It is only
I need the Third
Are orchestrated inter
What's this
It is deterministic Rule
Is the tool named customer
Is the
Greater than
1,000 Dollar Tree
Then the workflow
What's the a human operator gets an alert
Desi
10,000
They can investigate the order
And the users complaint
And then they click the April but
So after that in
The orchestrator receives the approval signal and resumes to work low
It's not execute the refund customer to
That means in the first
The agent execute this
Musically the age of 10:46 the result of the tool called which is the success
And Jenner
The final and helpful resp
Close to the user
And the agent has no idea it was even
The orchestrator
How does the entire safety check
And this is a simple refundable cloth with human in the loop
So now let's understand the architecture implications
The benefit of this pattern
You get the best of the both world
You get the agents autonomous problem solving and determinist
Accountable Judgment of a human
This is how you
69 determine
The trade off of course is latency and
This button is intentional slow
You are injecting human scale de
Minutes or even hours
Into your software
It also doesn't
It requires paying a human to be on
To approve this a
Your key architectural decision is the threshold
If you
Play too low like
Your human operator will be polluted with Al
And your labor
Clothes will be too
And if
Set the traditional to
Like 100,000
You are accepting too much RIS
Defining this threshold is a critical business logic deck
Is there somebody we can say that
Who won in Delhi
Is the workflow pattern
Did fossils
It's for human approval
And it works by orchestrator intercept
Is an agent's
And check it
Deterministic business rules
And we will use this pattern for any high risk or irreversible
The court principles are the agents
Is the human deck
Use case including
Financial transaction
What's data delet