We are going to learn
The Egyptian custom logic Pat
In the last lecture we
Human in the loop
Which is our first
But what happens
What's the agent is not working corre
What
When
Is the stock up in a
Pro
Anything to use
Or when the users simply
A post button isn't enough
We need an escape
We need a hardcore that deter
Did over
What's the
What is autonomy completely
This is the ejection Pat
So now
Let's understand this button debt
The Egyptian Pat
When is executive
Repeat sounds like
It is the escape page for your work
Did you find it as a deterministic
Ruby's but
Dead by
What's the time
The
When's the entire non-deterministic Loop
Is this function is
Instantly transfer control away from the agency
Which is the alarm
And handed over to a simply predictable
Deter
Music system
Like a live chat or just a simple goodbye
This is a hardcore that custom logic over
It is the deterministic rule that trumps the non determin
Music agent every single time
You can see the image on the slide
Typical agent and this is the Atlantic group that we are going to follow when a user send a
But intimately with the ejection Pat
Create an escape
B**** and be great stop button
In order to leave
Stop this agentic
So now let's understand
Why we need an escape
And also it is critical to understand why this is different from the human in the loop
Human in the loop
Is for when the agent is working correctly
What about to do something dangerous
It is a collaborative pause but
The Egyptian pattern is for when the conversation is broken
Turn on undesirable
The agent might be failing
Stuck in a
Or the user is simply done
Discover critical Celsius
First
Is the user can be frustration
So do you just start frustrating
Sing and say that
You are useless I want to speak a human
Or in the second
What is which is the user termination
It also handled simple termination
Like stop or cancel
Uncritically
Eaten
Save the policies
Like ejecting to user if they become AB
So now let's understand how the internet is ejection pattern architecturally
Architecturally this is the most important
This logic cannot be part of the
You cannot just tell the AG
If the user says stop
Please set
The non-deterministic L
Might ignore it or misunder
Instead this button must be implemented as a simple
Determinist
Play check filter
Once before the agents main dope is even trigger
Display filter could be a simple statement in your
Need to cancel the image on the slide
Your application received the user input
Is it runs it through this ejection filter
It takes for your keyboards
Like human
Stop and cancel
If there is a match is found
Eat eggs immediately and Rose to the different deterministic function
Only if the input pass this filter
We do
Hand control over the AG
What's perceive reason a
This is the agency
And the
Never even sees the Egypt
So now let's see a classical use
Listen to ejection pattern
The most common use case is the live agent ejection
Local
If the user's message contains
Is human or agent
It immediately calls a function to transfer to your live chat system
Passing the station history
The stop ejection is for task termination
Your code check
Don't stop or cancel
And if it is point them
It terminates the agents workload and send a confirmation
And the police ejection is your safety
You run the
Go through a simple moderation function
If it is prop
In or Violet's Pollock
You don't send it to the alarm
You just returned a hard-coded safety
Is there somebody we can say that
This is your Escape
Which All Star but
It is a deterministic
Did all
What's the non-deterministic agent
Eat breakfast The Agency Group
It doesn't pause
Architecturally implement
Is it is a play check filter before the alarm is called
This is not negotiable this but
Is essential for any user facing production system
To handle the frustration