In this video
We are going to learn
Pretty Ricky
Tools and resources for the course
Let me start YouTube playlist
Discourse assumed that
You have very basic programming skills
Weather in python.org
Similar TV to
We'll also
Since we will explore
How to interact with the alarm AP
What is an AG
Mainly we will Design enterprise software architect
With integration of the AG
So it is good to know basics of the software architect
Fix the Coors Light
Each lecture comes with the
Summarizing the key
What's uncle
And these lights are available for download in this lecture resources section
That you can see on the slide picture
How you can download from lecture resources from the ud
I highly encourage you to download and review them as you progress through the
I'm finally a very important request from my
Is you go through the
If you are planning to content valuable and it is helping you learn
Please consider taking a moment
To leave a comment and a five star review
Your positive reviews and constructive feedback
Are incredibly motivating and important
They encouraged me to continue creating