In this video
We are going to learn the course project
We will Design agentic AI architecture for eShop micro
Is are
We need to solve Enterprise scale problems
Are Central case studies
To build a comprehensive agentic Ali
On top of a river
EShop microservice application
So we are going to take
Make a standard positive e-commerce platform
And transformed it into the ACT
Intelligent and autonomous system
So let's
What did all
We have a standard Microsoft architect
An identity to microservice for users
Decorative microservice for products and search
A basket microservice for shopping cart management
In order to make microservice for order replacement and
Currently this system is positive
It is for API call
That
Is if a user want to find a specific red running shoe
If it is in
And buy it and the US
What is the power from 10 different click
Please answer on the web U
Make an API call
So that
Is the burden of reasoning is on the human
So are
Is it called is to design an idiotic layer
It's on top of these microservices
You can see the image on the slide
We have microservices and we put the agency player
Between the
Under Microsoft
In order to provide these application and until
And we will design a system
What a user can simply say
I need a pair of running shoes
Snooze for my Marathon next month
If you find a good one
Buy
And this record to powered by mCP
To connecting agents to microservices security
I'm powered by the contact
Using the user history
Navigate to personalized action
And powered by the collaboration
Do multiple agents working together
In order to achieve
Is we will need to apply
Play every major Topic in this course
Including
Play Atlantic world
Design pattern
Is protocol
And the agent development life cycle
So let's look at the specific use
We will architect
What's the intelligent shopper
We will use the router and specialist Pat
Is Central water agent
Wheel analyze the request
And delegate it to the catalog special
We will Design This specialist using the agency
It won't
Search key
It will reason about Marathon shoes and look up the technical spec
And will apply contact
Next engine
To ensure the
Automatically knows the US
Does shoe size
From The Identical microservices
Without
Let's look at the Second Use
Which is the autonomous checkout
Once the shoe are
The agent must buy
And we will use
Tool use pattern
The agent calls the basketball scores API
Play an ordering API Direct
Here we will focus on the protocol
We will Design MCPE servers which are the model contacts protocol
Did web
Legacy microservices
A living or a
To plug into the basket and organic Microsoft apis
In a standard
What is unsecured
But also an AI agent spending money is dangerous
So we will also implement the human in the loop
We will architect is safe to Guardian
What's the agent to pause and request confirmation
For how will you transactions
I need to cancel the another use case
Which is the customer support
So what is the user
What is my order late
Beautiful design
In a support agent
Using the rear compound
In this pattern the agent
Reason about the users frustration
Add to buy checking to order service
And move until it find the root cause
And we will also use the reflection pattern
Before replying
The agent will critique its own draft
To ensure the tone is empathetic
And if it
We will design a handle of pattern
To transfer
Which state to a human
So by the end of this
You will have a complete architectural blueprint for this system
You will have a design to mCP interfaces
Make the identical clothes
Selected the right framework
Unify the security guard rail
On this project is your sandbox to master the agentic architecture