In this video
We are going to see
Play the rabbit evolution of our industry
Is moving from simple generative a
Play tutorial agency a
No
Move from the micro to the
To understand this shift
We need first understand the three
Mission of our entire
Has gone through in just a few short years
These are the
Dinner today
AA
An
This is the journey from A Simple consultant
Do the entire Factory
So are Johnny begins in the phase one
Which is the generative AI
This is the Paradigm we are all now deeply familiar with tools like the JCPenney cloth and Gemini
Architecturally
This is a simple one
Reckless response model
The user provide a prom
And the alarm generates an answer
And the process
The system is entirely possible
Eat weights for a user
You forget the introduction immedi
It is
And it has no persistent memory of
What's the interaction
Outside
What is provided into the prom
And we call this is
Expert consultant model
It is a magnificent tool for answering questions or generating content
But it has no agency
You cannot
It cannot do
We can go to the second phase
And this first major Evolution Leaf belongs to
Space
The AI
And this is the leave from a positive expert consultant
To activate work
The achieve this by making two critical architectural Editions
We gave the alarm
What's on mem
And this is the active system we call this
It is Pro
And it can initiate the action
It is multi-step
It
Does a person
Reason an egg
And it is also stateful
It maintained
An internal memory of its plan and its history
You can see the diagram on this light
Do you say no longer provide a prompt
They provide a
The agent is active
East
What's the step
Play achieve dead
And it is also set
It remembers the result of
It's too cold
And this is the powerful component
It is
Just one component and just one
And this beating us to the second Major League
On the subject of this section
Which is the phase 3 Atlantic AI
This is the leap from a single worker to entire
What
When a goal is too complex
Thanks for our single agent
What if it require
What's the coordination of Sales inventory and shipping AG
We don't need one God like agent
Be with an
Picture of multip
Specialized agents that collab
A user
What is a complex called to the system
And the system works today a team of agents to solve it
You can see the image in here
Laser
Add a complex
And this time
This will be handled a multiple
Collaborating agent
That means this is a collaborative architecture
The primary engineering challenge
Is no longer just task execution
It is the system wide orchestration and communication
In this model we have specialization
We don't have one agent
We have water agent
Did X is a foreman
A shopping AG
Next to
Is special
Any support AG
Put this to Logistics special
These agents collab
Play hand of
Ask a debate Solutions
This is an architectural of the AG
Is an example we can give our eShop example
We can send the request to Rotary AG
That can collaborate with the shopping
And the support
So now let's see the table
Summarize this entire journey and comp
Here you can see the interface
Turn on in the generative AI
We have a
That answer from a prom
And it is a positive expert consultant
In the face to be basically create an air agent
Did adding the tools and memory to that plane
In order to create a ag
Which is a worker that can achieve a goal
This is a single octave component
Interface
Resume on architect
To connect multiple workers
Into a factory
Which is an adjective
That can collaborate to
A complex
Each phase will open the last
Moving from a simple tool to single actor
I'm finally to a collaborative Society
As you can see that we have no trace the full evolutionary
From a passive generative AI
To proactive collaborative