In this section
We are going to learn
What is agentic AI
On multi-agent architectures
This section covers
Are agent versus Atlantic AI
What is agentic architecture
How agentic AI works
Real world examples and challenges of agentic AI system
As you can see that
When evolving our identity a
We have finished the general today I am finished the AI agent
Which is a single AI AG
That sound a goal and returning exact with running the agency
I know
Focus on the agentic AI
But before that let's understand what is wrong with the AI
So what is the problem of the AI AG
The problem is the limit of
Single work
All work
Which is the AI agent is powerful
But it has limit
What
When a problem is
Watch two complex
Distributed for a single AG
In that
Is you don't need 1 billion journalists work
Instead you need a team
This is the next level of the abstraction
We must
Stop thinking about willing to work
I'm still thinking about designing the entire Factory
Please bring us the formal definition of the agentic AI
And this is the key distinction for this entire
The first one is a ag
An air agent is a component
It is the worker
It is an actor defined by it is autonomy
Memory and
Agentic
Play is the system
It is the architecture that contains
Change
One or more
It is the factory that employs
The work
This section is no longer about the worker
It is about the factories bully
We are not designing a system
All architectural Focus must change
Our previous sections were study in Asian psychology
How does one agent
How does it
How does it remember
This section
Is yesterday in agent sociology
We are now asking
How does a group of Agents inter
This introduced
A complete the new set of engineering challenges
How the agents communicate with each other
How do they coordinate their actions to avoid conflict
And how do they collaborate to achieve a goal