We are going to learn
The critical differences of
A agent versus agentic AI
First Define the AI agent based on everything we have learned so far
The best example for a single AI agent is
Security Lance developer
The soup is that of a single component
When you
Play if you didn't
You are concerned with their Anatomy or their
Do they have a good brain
Do they have a good memory and a toolbox
Can they do the job
Therefore the primary engineering
Switch off a single agent is
Give me this
Can this one agent use
To produce the correct
This is the entire focus of our previous
So now let's understand the
Authentic AI
The example here is
Is not a single freelancer
But the entire software company
Did employ
Is a team
Mitsubishi lights 50
The ZIP code is that
When you breed a company you are no longer Focus
Who's on one person
You are focused on the companies architecture
How does the team
Direction together
What is the communication protocol
Is it select email or for us mCP
What is the air coordination pattern
Is there any project man
Play or we can call an orchestrated AG
Do they have a shared collaboration go
So this primary challenge is no longer task execution
Assistant orchestration
How do I get my billing agent and my shipping agent
Each other
To solve a complex customer problem
So is it somebody we can say that
When you are building a single AI agent you are focused on implementation
And your questions
What tools do I need to write
How do I perfect the system
How do i r
Play its memory
But when you are willing and a Genting are
You are zoomed out
You are focused on interaction and integration
Your
What is my internet communication protocol
What is my coordination pattern
And how do I