In this video
We are going to learn
What is
Is a multi agent system
And what is agentic architect
A multi agent system is a system composed of 3 key ingredient
The first one is obviously multiple autonomous AG
On the second one is
Is it environment
Did they all operate between
This could be your company's Network a set of AP
What is a database
And the third one is a common go
This is the most important part
They are united by a common goal
The entire system is designed to solve a problem
This is too large or too complex for any single agent to handle on
So this is the fundamental difference between building 1 Mega agent with a thousands of
I'm designing a modular system of many specialized AG
So now let's understand
What is agentic archit
It is a system design
Did integrates
One or more ought
When is AAA agents with data sources
And communication pathway
Keep complex
High level goals
An identical
Is what provides the answer to
System level questions
Including
How is the state man
When you have thousands of agent
And how does
Is new agency player
Integrate with
Non-agent micros
This is the domain of architect
So now let's understand
One of the most powerful and common pattern
Which is the agent as a service
This is the architectural con
Did an agent isn't just
Play secret you
It is a dep
Add long
Sing faithful and audible service
In this model
Allegiant has a unique endpoint
Just like a micro
It might be a rest API or
It might be a
Speak on a message
Other systems
Who's better they are human users or other agents
What's old percept
Distance by calling these
This agent is a service model is what makes AG
When's the first class citizen
Within a modern
Distributed architecture
Andy's architecture app
Bring us to the Y
Why can't we
Stepping up if you see
Why do we need to think about
Formal architecture
The answer is simple
Building one agent as a demo is easy
But reading an Enterprise System of AG
What is
We need architecture for scalability
How does your design
In hand
10,000
Running concurrently all detail on State and memory
We need it to for liability
An agent
Is mandatory
It can fail or get stuck in a loop
What happens
How does your architecture ensure the task
Recovered and complet
And we need it for manageability and govern
How did Montour and the
A black box
How do you apply security
How's it going
It's action and
Is operational cost