In this video
We are going to learn
How agentic AI work
In a system level architectures
How do we actually design a system where multiple autonomous agent
Can work together effectively
We will answer this by exploring
The two primary architectural pattern that enable agent Cooper
So now let's remember our core problem
We have multiple autonom
On each one is
Is capable of perceiving
Reasoning and acting independently
And it is almost
So the challenge
How do we prevent this from becoming call
And how do you answer
These independent Act
Work together
So we need a defined mechanism for decomposing the main
Is Sonic the sub
Communicating to Pro
And synchronizing the action
So there are two primary architectural patterns we
Who's the oldest coordination problem
The first one is orchestration
Is centralized top down the
Similar to having a manager or a conductor
The second
What is choreography
Is a decentral
Is bottom-up approach
More like dancers reacting to music or AG
Reacting to
What's on the shared message bus
These patterns represent fundamental different way
To structure the interaction
Is between our agentic AI system
Let's an
What is each one
The first one
Is orchestration
This is often more intuitive
The core principle is
Centralization
One agent is
Is designated as the orchestrator OR manager
This agent
Is the Hollywood complex called from the user
It is job is not to execute
What two minutes to work
It us
What does it's spinning mod
To decompose the goal into a sequence of sub
Ethan dele
Each other to the appreciate
Specialist AG
For example
Telling the inventory agent to check
Done telling to billing agent to process payment
The orchestrated
It's
Special
To report
Synthesizes the results
And then decide
Next step in the plan
It is a classic top-down
Command and control structure
A project manager
Is signing
Ask the team members
No let's see an example of the orchestrated
The customer service agent
A customer service system
Perfect example of the orcust
Do you still ask a complex two-part question
User goal
What is the status of my recent order
And can I add
So the customer service AG
Acting is the orchestrator
Receive this
And it
What's 50 planning
And eat plants the two steps needed
The first step is
Interrogate Step 1 by making
Is the struct
828 call to the order agent
It waits for the resp
Done it all
Make the step
By calling to shipping AG
Eat weights again
And finally it's synthesizes the results from
Specialist and formulates the final answer
Search for the
You can notice that
How's the service agent
Music the control
Who's the
Where is UNF
So now we can go to the next
Which is the choreography
Is a decentralized event room
There is no Central manager
Does all agents RPS
How do they coordinate
The internet
One agent performs an action
And this action is the Polish an event to a shared message bus like Kafka or reputation
What time is area code initiative
Other agents in the system are
Independently listening for
Specific event
State
Data related to them
When they hear something interesting
Play performing tears on action
Which in turn my telegram yet another AG
It is a chain reaction
Like
What does responding to the music
Each other's
Let's see an example about the choreograph
Is supply chain is a classical example of the choreography
Goal is the fulfill any customer order
There's no single manager agent coordinating the whole process
Did the order agent
60 / 6 in order
Next by confirming
Publish
An older confirmed event
The inventory event
Which is independently listening for that event
Books by the Romantic stock and Publishing
It's only
After
The shipping event listening for that event
Relaxation by deliver
Each
And only knows about its own small part of the process
Next to the
It's care about
The overall fulfillment happens emergently from these independent interactions
So now let's understand
Turn off the choose the right pattern
So which pattern should you
As always in architecture
It depends on the trade-off
Orchestration is
Is generally simpler to design and understand
The entire world
Is in one place
Making it easier to debug
However
It creates a single point of failure
And can become a button
It is also less flexible
Adding any step requires modifying to Central orchestrator
Choreography is far more flexible
Skill level and resilient
There is no single point of failure
And you can easily add new AG
Listen
Does without changing the existing
It is much harder to Monitor and Deb
The overall system behavior is emergent
Making it difficult to trace a single request