In this video
We are going to design
Orchestration
And choreography of the agentic architect
DS
The two fundamental architecture pattern
Orchestration which is the central manager pattern
On calligraphy
Which is the decent
What is event
On this buttons are the blue
How agentic AI
And you will see exactly
What is patterns are applied
Some complex problem
So now let's see some of the real world examples
The first one is
The auton
Bishop example
Arsenal is a customer inter
Next weekend online stores support
And our
What is the handle complex request
Is item
Mix in
Is so place an order using my safety
Is an
Play my loyal
So this is too complex for a single agent or a simple chat
The solution is orchestration architect
Do
Put on the
What's the single customer service AG
On this agent
What is the orchestra
It doesn't know how to check stock or process payment it
Instead 8
It's a team of the specialist AG
Including
Inventory
Order agent
I'm building
Each with their own specific to
So here you can see the shop orchestration flow
First of all the user send the gold
Is eggs in
If
Order it with my discount
And after that the service agent which is our orchestrated
Receive this goal
And this will be for my plan
And this will be delegate
And after that wait for the response and Performing this operation in a
And the service AG
Is 8 is the central brain
Coordinating the simpler hands
Specialist agent
Let's see on the image this
Do you
Send to some comp
Next school Beach
Place an order
And after
Are customer service agent which is our orchestration
Handle this complex
And make a
After that delegate this
Turn with delegate
Inventory agent for
Delegate to order agent for place an order
Put with items and attributes
And delegate
Blink agent to apply this discount
And after that these orchestrated
Synthe
And this one's back to the US
And test us
Does items
And your order is conf
Don't be the discount app
So now let's go to the another
What example which is the disaster resp
Arsenal
Is coordinating Emergency Services after a major event
Like earthquake in London
And our goal is assessed to
Image locate the victim
On this page
Efficient
Again a single agent cannot handle this
And the solution is
Is an orchestration Pat
Here you can see the image
Basically we have a coordinator agent to manage overall resp
Which a team of the highly specialized agent
Satellite agent for analyze the image for the
Play social media agent
Chickens for the district school
Unbearable
Logistic agent to manage emergency vehicles
I'll be here also simulation AG
My predict the after show
Cancel
And this demonstrate how orchestration can manage complex
Philadelphia
So now
See another example real word example
Read choreography example which is
An alternative
Supply chain agent
Imagine a coordinating inventory between a manufactur
Multiple supplier
What is shipping
These are open independent entities
Is centralized orchestrator
Might not be feasible or desirable
Are gold insured product
Are automatically restocked and
I'm here we will
Is Corgi pattern based on reacting to Shared events or dat
Is a natural
So we have peer agent
Elementary agent at the manufacturer
Supplied agent
Make this apply
And a
At the Shipp
There is no Central manager
You can see the supply chain for Griffith
First of all let's trace the event living FL
We have an event
Which is the inventory agent
Montrose the database
Don't stop drops
Is eggs by creating a purchase order
Publish an event
Which is the new purchase order
Unbelievable event
The supplied agent
Is the supply company is independently listening for this event
An Easter eggs by confirming to order
I'm publishing
It's the only
Which is the older conf
Event
Play the
Music agent
Is shipping company is listening for the order conference
I need drugs by scheduling to pick up and Publishing the ship
What's scheduled event
An event
Even the original inventory agent might be listening for
Chipman schedule
So it can update
Its arrival forecast
Now let's see this events into our electronic architecture
First of all we have an inventory agent
Publ
Sing me purchase order
And this will be subscribe and consume from the supplier agent
I'm
Which event to which is the order confirmed
And continue with the log
Get angry bird
And this is the continuous loop basically
It continues to Montero stock
What does and continue to all
Distance in order
So notice that no agent
Any other agent what to do
The complex workload emerged from
Is simple independent reaction
To share event
This is the power and
360 off to choreograph
Is there somebody we can say that
We have gone to orchestration
Which is ideal for the work
Recording to central control
Planning and synthesize
And we have learned the choreograph
Which is ideal for the decentralized systems
Why do component