In this video
We are going to learn
The challenges of the Atlantic are
In the previous lectures
Is Bill
How to coordinate comp
Textiles in areas like
E-commerce disaster resp
And Supply Chain management
However
Disney
A single component to a distrib
Bluetooth system
Introduce an entirely new class of the architectural challenges
Is Arch
We must approach this month
With a clear understanding of
Hot pot
Add to flight anal
Is challenges for our agentic air system
On our first challenge is
System
Light obser
Debugging a single agents internal monologue is already difficult
But what happens when they
What is not happening in one br
What is distributed AC
What's a team of
What's 510 collaborating AG
It must be
Extremely diff
If the final result is wrong
Tracing the root cause becomes
Exponentially hard
Did the orchestrated agent make a bed
Turn on the internet fail to execute
Is tool correct
Or did the billing agent
Simply misinterpret the message
From the orcust
And the Chain of Thought is not fragmented for the distributed agent
So that means we must design robust distributed tracing and Central
Is logging systems
Specifically for the agent interactions
Just as we do for Microsoft
But with the edit complexity of non Dieter
Is the reasoning
After that our Second Challenge is unique to complex system
Is emergent Behavior
Images of
When the interactions of many simple agent
Is lead to comp
Unplanned behaviors
Is it the system
This is both the power and the danger of the Atlantic a
Play what happens
What's 1 * 380
On each for living to simple Rue
Interacting innovative
Accidentally crashes the market
What if two agents in our supply chain
Get
In an infinite
What's the ordering and cancel
Add to same it
So the system's Behavior may become something
There's no single agent planned or intended
Architectural challenge is in
How do we design system that allow for beneficial emergence
While preventing the harmful emergent behaviors
Please open invoice extensive simulation
Careful agents rule design
Assistant white Guardian
So
Next challenge
Intel agent communication
Where did we use orchestration or choreography pattern
Are system depends on
Successfully sending and receiving messages
Did the lights on stable Communications
Translate MC
Play or Define API Conte
What's between as
This communication fail
Is great
Play like protocol mismatch
API
Is a network
So all
62 challenge is to design for resilient communication
Andy's in
Standard distributed
System techn
Careful API listening
Robust error
Retry mechanism
And the patterns like circuit breakers
To prevent cascading playlist
When one agent becomes
What's undas
Our final major challenge
Is gold conf
And resource location
This is the classic concurrency problem now apply to autonomous AG
What happens when two different agents
Operating independently
Need the same
Bluetooth resource
Imagine two separate travel AG
Both trying to book the very last
Put on a flight to New York
At the exact same millisecond
Who
Or considered AG
What's with conflicting
Most saving AG
I decide to Optimal action is to shut down another useless
Write an uptime agent
Simultaneously
It needs that server as a backup
This is a classic concurrency problem from Des
Are architecture challenge is to implement mechanism to resolve this conflict
This might involve establishing clear prioritization
Implementing locking mechanisms for critical resources
Or even building
Negotiation protocols for agents can beat for a resource or compromise
Is there somebody we can say that
The challenge of the agentic
Play all fundamentalist system
We must design for System Light observability to debug the distributed reasoning
You must manage emergent Behavior to prevent harmful outcomes
The most
Brazilian communication
My system business
And the most intimate mechanism to resolve