In this video
We are going to learn
AAA agent frame
We will explore AI agentic Frameworks
Including the land chain length
Llama
Microsoft
Agent for the
Unclog agent
So we have with sophisticated multi-agent workloads using to code first framework
And the important question is
What tools did they use why did we use them
And what are the alternatives
So we could do it everything from
Making grow API calls to
Manila passing to Jason outboard
And handcrafting a state
But in an Enterprise environment
This is a receipt for on maintainable
Beautiful
We will be remarkable
I need the section we will learn framework landsc
To help you choose the right foundation for your business
So now let's understand why we
Use a friend
An agent has a simple
When you try to implement it
Your breath in the boilerplate
And it is hard to connect everything
For example let's think the tool Cooling
Portugal
You have to format a complex
Is Jason Sycamore of your available tools for the
Then you have to pass the alarms function calling responds
Which might be malformed
Then you have to execute the correct
Second function
Victor correct argument
So all these operations are error from operations
That you can't handle by yourself
And another reason is
State Management
How do you enable a place to chat history from one turn to the
And also how do you perform the red Pipelines
To connect to data Chang
Sing Everything story and repeat the documents
And how do you manage to
Templating managing and changing to contacts
For that reason we have to use frame
Books When developing or agentic work
So now let's understand the categories of
The AG
Music AI framework Market
Is fragmatic into three main categories
This is your Workshop
If we set up the low level to
Did you let the word anything you can imagine
But you have to assemble
The second is
Specialist train
Like high-end Philippines
What mission is designed only for advanced
Another is designed only for the multi-agent collab
That one is the minutes platform
This is the full service Factory
You don't lose anything
You buy the finished agent as a service and configure