We are going to learn
The journalist framework
Which are the launching and land
In our last lecture
We met the entire premier
Landscape into 32 degrees
These are the general
Special
Is unmanageable
We begin with the general tool
Which is the framework that in many ways created the entire engine develop
Which is the line
Solange idea has always been to provide
The low-level components for building any kind of the alarm applic
So to understand the Lion King
You must first understand it is called philos
Which is the composability
The entire ecosystem
Is weed on the idea that
Application is just
Turn off standard comp
So these components are the model
LeBron temp
The tool definition
And the output
But the magic of the Lion
Its core Khan
Which is the glue that holds them together
This is the line chain expression language or we can call a seal
You have also seen
Is pipe samb
Let's to change component
What's together
So now
Let's understand the core component
Fast forward 19 agent
Two critical comp
First the tool decorator
This is an incredibly useful utility
You just decorate any python function
19 autumn
Can you convert 1822 complex
Set the alarm
Function calling API require
Richard piece of the bowler play
On the second component is
Play with agent executors
These are agent in
Book Solutions
You can import a great function calling agent helper
Give it to your model and your list of tools
Can you run a complet
Play real good for
This is the fastest way to get a simple agent of and
So now
Let's understand the architectural limit
Lights off these executors
However is architect
You must immediately recognize the limitation of these executors
The executors are black
They run a
But the logic of that Loop is
You cannot change it
What happens when you need to implement our magnetic router Pat
What if you want to do it the
Group Chatsworth
We just got
What if you need to pause the agent
And ask a woman for approval
Before executing a dangerous tool
Do you play with agent executor
Cannot handle
It is designed for one simple
And that's it
It is not a true state will work love
This black box
Is it great for quick prototype
What is face
When we need to build custom enterprise-grade are
So is the soul
Then we can use land crab
So this imitation is
Precisely why landcraft was
If the old executors
Where's the black
Length is The Voice
Lens
How is the
Is formal engine
For willing to
What state
Cyclic work
We have been designed in this course
Minecraft forces you to
Exclusively Define
The Three core components
These are the state object
Which is our workflow memory
Which are workers or agents
On
Are routers that control the
This is no longer an agent in a
Next
What is the video on agent architect
It gives you the power of the luncheon component
What's the full control of a state machine
Also if you look at the official website of The Lion King
You can see the engine
They're offering to open source frame
Books including the link chain and land
And also they have agent engineering platform
Which is the last minute
For providing observability Evolution and deployment for unturned workload design and development
So now let's understand
When to use
19 and landcraft
Now you need to
Is nonstandard customer Club
Also when your agents recent log
Is your intellectual property and cannot be a black box
And when you need to integrate
Get many different models and data sources
You can choose the 19 and then grow
So why not to use 19 and land
The trade-off svfc is comp
This power
Is it the cost
City Line
Also you are responsible for all the architectural operations
Which
Is writing more code and managing more complex
Is there somebody we can say
When is the workshop of low-level components
Minecraft is the word
That lead to assemble those components into any custom state will cyclic agents you can design
And you can use for the maximum flexibility and custom logic
And be aware of the high comp