In this video we are going to learn
Loma IND
Is an agent framework
Is you can see that we are 82nd
And
List all
Just do the special
What is categ
Play to solve one specific problem
Which is
Reading powerful
Data intensive agents
Easter luncheon is the generalist Workshop
Llama
Next is the special
Is data science lab
We are moving from an application first app
Do the date of first Airport
To understand the llama
Is the most
First understand the problem
We have all seen simple
You find if you live in Texas
Stop them into
And get some
But what happens when the problem gets harder
What is the answer require
What is comparing two different annual
What if you need to
Who's the first look up the user's ID in SQL database
And then use that idea
To find the support
In a PDF archive
Under summarize the findings
This is no longer simple rake
This is Agent
It
What's an agent that can create a multi-step plan
Create a multiple data sources
Un synthesized the result
This is the core problem Loma index was
So now let's understand the difference between
In Loma
Mix on the line
19 is application first Airport
It focuses on the agents work
What is execution
Your data is just another tool in the agents to
Butler
Next is data first approach
Eat Focus
What does obsessively on the data itself
Is primary strength is building
Incredible index of your data
The agent is a 10 reason player
What's on top of this powerful
This is the key takeaway
You choose the Lion King for comp
Next agent log
You choose the number index for comp
Next data interactions
So now let's understand
How long are index is working
Solomon index architecture is based understood
Is two distinct pip
The first one is the injection pipeline
How it gets data in
It starts with the data connectors
These are pretty Integrations that load data from virtually anywhere from the PD
Play
Sales
You name
But the real magic is in indexing
Llama
Alexa doesn't just dump the dat
Play into a vector
It intelligent is struct
It can create a stand
What Victor store
But it can also create
If somebody
Optimized for the summer station
Keyboard table
What's the temperature at metad
The result is a rich motivated index
Did understand
Does the structure of your data not just its cont
And the second pipeline is for retrieval
How it gets the data out
Once you have your IND
Next Prov
Creative
This is a simple high-level interface
Is to ask questions
Behind the
The credit union
What's the best way to retrieve dat
From the
Next track
But it is real power comes from the red Pipelines
Llama index allows you to
Music to customize the retrieval Pro
For example
You can receive 20 documents
Has done it already
Wingstop to find the
And then
Response to the
Do intelligently wave those five answer together
This is how you
An industrial
We will see details of the agency
Like in the next section
If you putting it all together we can ask that
Where does the agent come in
The lumber index agent
Is a reasoning play
Built on top of these powerful query engines
This is the key
You don't just give the AG
Add a simple tool you give the agent multiple
Specialized Credit Union
When is exit
For example
You give your AG
To
Which is equity engine for
2024 Financial PD
Until 2:40
In Polar Express sales database
After
When a user ask a complex question like
Compare our sales from 20
Weather for today
Elections in the financial report
The agent can reason
It will create a plan
Call the Esquire tool to get the sales data
Then call the PDF tool to get the projection
I'm finally
Synthes
What is a complete answer
That is true agency
So is it somebody we can say that
Lower
Next a date of first framework
What's the thing is building rich in Texas
Key features is informatic agency click that can reason and synthesize the data
Unused for the advance