In this video
We are going to learn
Turn Microsoft agent framework for multi
So you may hurt about
Two popular Microsoft Project
What
Which was brilliant at multi agent collaboration
On semantic Kern
Which was designed for Enterprise
Most unsafe agent
Is off recently
The teams behind both
Have United to
Is the official success
This is the Microsoft agent fr
Or we can
So this
What is the name next Jenner
Location of the
What are John and semantic Journal
It is designed to be unified Foundation
For building
What's on the Microsoft
So to understand the architecture of the new Microsoft agent framework
You have to understand
What it was created
For the past years
Architects face a choice
Do I use AutoZone
It was fantastic for quickly prototyping complex multi agent collaborations
It is conversation first model
On group
Was simple and Powerful
What do I use Symantec
It was good for the Enterprise
Middleware for safety
Play answer
What is State Management
Microsoft agent framework
Was Bluetooth antis d
It is goal is to be the best of both
To combine the simple powerful multi agent patterns of Auto
Video production lady Enterprise great features of semantic colon
So now let's understand
Are the call capabilities
On the first capability is the foundation
Which is the individual Enterprise agent
Which inherits the best part of the
Dismiss
Every agent
It comes with the Enterprise features
List all of the
It is also a middleware system
Open court
I love you to intercept agent actions for security
Play Loggins and Authentication
It is a formal agent today
For
Which state management
Which is critical for long-running tasks
And it is also native support for
Why the light off the model
I'm very important
For the model context protocol
Which we will discuss later
It is sweet
First class Cit
With the mCP Integrations
And if you look
Is it the second capabilities
Which is about the work
The second probability is what is Agent relations
And this
It's evolution of the auto
Monster agent
This is the name extraction for Monster agent collaboration
Instead of the only lying on a conversation on group chat
Math introduced
Graphics workload engine
This is a forum
Graphics workflow engine
Very similar in concept to do landcraft architecture we
This is the key
Who's from the hotel James emerging collaboration to exquisite
Addicted Corp
And this workload engine
Include the critical Enterprise future
A type is routing for predictable control
And you
Next door close inside
Add other work
Can you
Checkpoint
So you can say a long drink workload and resume it later
Can you
Human in the loop pattern
Is the first class feature
So an agent can
And ask for approval before
For taking a critical step
And this is group chat all grown
So we can say that
The Microsoft agent framework include an embr
Most simple conversation first abstractions
This is what so powerful
It gives you the architect a choice
What does that
Repeat from the em
Turn back and forth debate
Like brainstorming or simulation
You
Stand up a simple autism style group chat feature
But for your mission critical multi-step business processes
You can use the new formal workload engine
To create a process
This is ex
Predictable
Robust and Save
By this way you get the best of the both world
So now let's understand
When to use Microsoft agent frame
You choose this framework
If your primary goal is building
Enterprise
Multi agent system
It is the framework designed for when you need both multi agent collaboration
And production levels Rob
And it is the Clear Choice for state
Long running agent
Because of it is native to the checkpoint
And human in the loop capabilities
And of
It is the premiere
First party
If you are a developer or heavily invested in the azure
When not to use Microsoft agent framework
And the Traders
What's the date
It is a brand
Play so the community
Play City growing around
And it is opinionated
It is designed to lead you to
Mississippi Street Global architectural pattern