In this video we are going to learn
The minutes platform
As you can see that we are at the Third
And we are going to learn
Turn the clock AG
In the previous lectures
We have learned the code first frame
Looks like 19
Llama
On the Microsoft agent frame
These are the toolkits you use
Then you need
Maximum power flexibility and control over your agents architect
No
Ask other critical question
Did Ariel Arctic
Should we breathe
What should we buy
This being
Minutes platform
This is the agent as a service model
Over it by the Victory Club providers
Including the Amazon
Microsoft and Google
This is the by decision
Anita's profound architect
Spell implications
So now let's understand
What is the agent as a service model
And what do you mean by agent as a service
Architect
Play this means you are no longer responsible for writing or managing
The aliens execution
You don't put a Minecraft state
You don't manage to python runtime
You don't worry about the state persist
The cloth provider
Host and
The entire
Your role as an R
Shift from wheeler to configurator
You declare what the agent should be you provide the to
Play it can use
Typically by uploading to open API
And you write the high level instructions
Do Platform done automatically Jenner
Ask
Is Agent for you
Simple API on
So now let's see this Victory manage platform
Is you would expect
Each of these big three Cloud providers
Is a major first party opening in this
Amazon offers Amazon Bedrock AG
Which is designed for
Native integration with the AWS ecosystem
You can give an agent a lot of function as a tool
An Italian
What's all the permissions
What is an execution
Second is Microsoft
Microsoft Office azure
Next video
Names of the other are Foundry
Which is
It's next Generation platform
For building and managing
Including the agent
It is the minute counterpart to the built solution we discuss
Microsoft agent frame
And the third one is Google
Google Cloud also off
It is Agent build
On the vertex AI platform
Which Prov
What a unified way to build agent
That can tap into the full power of the Google services
Did architectural goal is sing
To make it incredibly easy to
Is it an agent that uses
Delete all the cloud services
No I'm going to show you how do I find
But before
Let me show you the simple agent plan
Did we have seen in the last section
So basically we have a research AG
Memory and to
In the first step
Be injected system
And after that we have to find the llm which is our
And after that we have to find the tools including the Integrations about the other systems
Un
Long-term and short-term memory
Reasoning about this Pro
So let me show you all
If you go to the other air fund
Play ungrate any agent
In our case I have created a travel agent
You can see that first of all
We select another
Which is our
And after
We are injecting our instructions
Assistant interaction
Represent our agent
And after that you can see that
The other steps and
What is including one we are defining energy
Under the
Microsoft phone
Did you cancel that I had to find a
Adding items for different
Who's including the fire
Search
Web search computer use and so
Enough
Play Weeknd inject knowledge and mem
Play these are represent
Short-term and long-term mem
For example
Turn on Eden
Connect to
Foundry I
Which is the local
Enterprise
And you can inject a memory
You can add a memory to your AG
I
Play we have a guard
You can Define the guardian
In order to Define
Find the security and
This is a simple interface
That you can't find
Since with using the clock minute services
Which is Microsoft found
So now let's understand the architectural trade
Benefits and drawback
If you look at the benefits
Number one advantage is
These agents are fully managed and
You have zero infrastructure overhead
The technical Advantage is
The Deep Club integ
Giving a quote First agent
Secure access to your history buck
What is specific School dat
Is managing the keys rules and permissions
A picture of agent for example can be given and I am role
Just like any other AWS
The platform handle
The cred
Executed for you
This leads to incredibly
Repeat the market for simple task
And a building security and complies
That is
Is it difficult to replicate from
How
Discontent
Architectural price
Now let's see the drawback
The single most critical drawback is the black
You have no control over the agent
Is internal reasoning
You can't see it is metal prom
You can't custom
What is error hunting
For example
If the agent
What's the stock
Use a tool correct
The book
I think it is an exercise in frustration
You can only change the instructions
Turn on Hope
Second this is the definition of
Off the EXT
Weather
Your agent is
Play proprietary API
You cannot move it to another club or on premises
And finally
You have limited flexibility
Play all those powerful custom workflow patterns we design
The group chat button
The reflection
You can't put
You are limited to the simple package single agent model
The old is bringing us to the final decision
How do we is Arch
Choose buy or build
You should choose to buy and use a minute platform
When you're talking simple well-defined an internal facing
The primary value you are seeking is not normal reasoning
But simple integration between existing cloud services
I need you to create an internal database
Is it perfect example
And you must choose to be with the framework
When your
Huskies complex
Custom or non Dieter
You choose
Why
Did any of the advanced multi-agent platforms behave disc
What about the agents recently log
Itself
Is your intellectual property
If you need a random natural solution
What is your own opinion
So as you can see that we have all seen these three Kate
Is When developing our AG
The lion
Loma index Microsoft agent frame
Look for code first Airport
Unmanaged platform