Welcome to day one of week 2 where you going over introduction to numpy
For numerical computing
Today's topic first we will be looking at
Understanding the role of number in data science ndi
What is numpy
Numpy or
Numerical python
Is the foundational library in Python for numerical competitions
It provides a fast efficient way to perform
Operations on large data sets using arrays
And supports Advanced mathematical function
Now why use number anyway
First because of the performance
Are more efficient than python list
He's a fuse
Built-in operations for mathematical and linear algebra functions helps you easily implement
A lot of different mathematical and linear algebra functions
Integration
Book seamlessly with libraries like and Matt Platte tensorflow and pytorch that's
That's why we're using numpy in AI
Next
Creating and manipulating numb Pirates
First let's look at
How to import
Library
Python file
Save it inside our week
Two in this particular case
Devon
I'm going to create a file called as
Day
Number
Basics
Dot py
I'm here to import numpy as I mentioned
Import
Numpy
Next
Creating a race
Know there's different ways of creating a race one is from
A list so from a list how do we create another so let's look at an example here
And give it the list that you want to do give
And if I print this area
I will see
Python
Day one
San Diego 12344 so from a list we have created a numpy array
Next is using
Building functions
Are there some built-in functions for example
Beehive that's greater variable zeros
Zeros
And I am going to say three comma three
What this does is it will create a 3/3 matrix of zeros
We can bring that
Just to check how it looks like
Lego 3 x 3 area of zeros
This is the first one that's why it was still showing but I'm going to
Comedies out
Next
Once
I am going to create NP dot once
You probably already know what it does but I'm going to say 2 * 4 so this will create a 2/4 metric
Off once if I print it
San Diego 2 * 4 Matrix of ones
Next one I'm going to say
Equal to NP
Arrange what this does is it returns an evenly spaced values within a given interval so for example
Cancel I want to get
1 to 10 numbers but interval of two
So if I do this
I will get
13579 so what it did was it went to 1 to 10 with evenly spacing of two
It skipped one
Then gave me three skip one five skip to 17 so every
It skipped and went to the next one to one
Skip to 1 2 3 4 1 to 5:00 so that's what this does if I give it
Spacing of 3 and 1/4 and 7 1 3/41
Skip
5 and 6317 then so that's what it gives me if I give
A bigger number
801 skips 2 for skips 27 keeps on going all the way till 97 this is how it can
Next one that I want to show
Is Lynn space
So I can just say
Lynn space
Underscore
Equal to
Lynn space
0 comma 1 comma 5
So what linspace does is
It returns evenly spaced numbers over a specific specified interval so if I say that I want
From 0 to 1 with the interval of 5 inside there
So what it will give me
0 0.25 0.5 so it gives an interval of 5 and gives me that
Insight between the two numbers
So let's look at this
60 0.25 0.5 0.751 to these are 12345
Different numbers evenly spaced in between this if I do this one to 10
2.55
7.510 evenly spaced if I say 4 since then it'll probably give me whole numbers
7903.33 6.66 * 10.43 it will give me 0
510 so even this paste with whole numbers in there
Next
Let's look at manipulating arrays so we can
Do a bunch of different things like changing the shape of
And we can also add Dimensions to an area so let's look at those examples I'm going to go back to the same one
Get rid of everything I'm
Clear this out too
And here
I'm going to start first area equal to what I have
Remove the
Import statement to San Jose area equal to
NP
Erase so if I want to create an array from my list we already saw how to do that one
5006 this time
And then I want to share this area I'm going to call the reshaped area
Equal to
Reshape
And say that I want to reshape into 2 by 3
Matrix
Let's print it out
So instead of
Unit 1 single Dimension is going to have 2 * 3,500
I have one two three four five six seven and reshape that I can also do 3 * 3
Elements here are 2/3 or I have three by
2606 elements
Are you going to 3456
So I can give any of those combinations if I add
8 and 9
And now to 3 / 3
It will give me one two three four five six seven eight nine
I can create whatever multiples that is available based on these nine elements
The different Matrix
Next thing is to adding dimensions
Now that I can do by saying NP
With one comma two comma three
So this area let me comment on these things
When I when I have it already I'll say
Banded another object
Social add Dimensions to it when I say NP
Dot new access
So let's look at it how it adds a new dimension to this
Expanded
And you see one two three
Has added new access for each and every elements inside not given a dimension here creates three different dimensions for
Each and every element in
So this is how you can manipulate a basic arrays and create like reset them or ADD
Directions to
Let's look at some basic operations on array
So we look at element wise operations
And we look at mathematical operations
Let's jump in here
I want to create an area equal to NT
And inside that I'll add three elements
1 2 and 3
And then I'll create another
Holiday
Mt dot array in this particular case I'm going to give numbers
Four five and six so I have this address now
To do element wise operations let's say I want to add these stories
I can do print
A + B that's a good thing that you can do with non-payers where you can add this will give you an out
Put off based on this Edition 4 + 155 +
27 and 6 + 3/9
If I
Want to do let's say multiplication of these areas
8 * B
It
Give me 4 * 1/4
5 * 2106 * 318
I can also do division
Divided by B this will give me 0.25 for this
5 / 0.4
90/6 is 0.5 so that's what
It will give me let's go ahead and run this
Let's clear it out first
And I don't care about so I have 5789 for Edition
Multiplication I have 410 and 18
And for division I have 0.25
0.4
And 0.5
41 / 42 / 5 and 3 /
Sexy respect
Let's look at some mathematical operations so I'm going to say
Equal to NP Dot
And I'll create
1 comma 2 comma 3
I just use the previous one but that's fine and here I am going to do a square root
So I can say NP
Dot square root
So that's so you can always make it
A better example I can say for
Let's see how it look like
And here it is 24 and 5 so it looks √ of this and give me a new list with square root items
I can do
Np.sum of
I am sure you got what it does I'm going to clear this out
NBC 45 which is sum of
All these three numbers
Next I can do
I can do a mean NP dot mean of all the numbers
Internet
And mean is 15 for these three
Next I can do a Max also I can just copy this
And say Max of this particular area
Clear run
In the max is 25 as you can see 416 and 2525 is the max but if you have a bigger array or list
You can kind of find Max in that particular list
Next
Let's look
Any indexing slicing and reshaping
Where you can get an element
For a particular index then we look at slicing where you can slice an area into a smaller area which are
On the list before in Python last week
Where we can reshape a particular area which we have seen earlier today but let's look
Forget how this can be done again
So first as I mentioned indexing very equal to
NP dot array I'm going to create an area and probably try to use to use this one
10 comma 20 comma
Comma 40 comma 50 to 1050
Next I want to print a particular object in this area
So I can just set it at item number two it will print me 30 because this is index is zero
Now if I similarly in what we did in the list
You can also use negative numbers for example minus one
Will give me the last element because this is zero elements if you go behind this is -1 -
So that's how this works let's
Check it out
Could you give me 30 and 50 + 34 index 2 and 54 index - 1
Next let's look at slicing so I can do slicing similar to
What we did before
You can say that I want items from one to four
In this case I will get items
2030 and 40 because one is this
The
Three and doesn't include the last element
So index 1 to 4 - excluding the last element
And similarly I can do array
Call Ma
So what this does is it will give me
All the numbers
Before until 3:01 012
Starting from the start all the way up till 3:10 you can do the other way too
You say that you want everything starting from 3
So that will give you $40 and 50 012
And
Next is reshaping what you've seen earlier
Where I can see reshaped
Equal to array
Reshape
I have one two three four five elements
460 just so that
I can do a
Audi shape of
In this particular case 3 by 2/3
Reshaped
So she just saw this earlier
3350 from one by one by six
Shipping
Next
Based on whatever you learned let's do our hands on exercises
Are flushed exercise is to generate an array
For basic mathematical operations
Here's the objective is
Practice creating arrays and
Performing operations
Of size 5
Using NP dot range
And then perform addition subtraction multiplication and division on those
So let's get started it's pretty straightforward
I am going to call it day one underscore
Exercise
Here as I mentioned I'm going to create two ways and P Dot
Arrange first of course remember to import
Numpy
As and
And then arrange
1 comma 6
So this will create an area of 1,345
I'm going to get another area NP Dot
Arranged
And this one I want to create
6 comma 1160 + 678910 that's what it's going to create
Let's do a Edition operation
Which
A + b
What I'll do a subtraction multiplication division
Someone says sub
Multiplication
And Division
Division
Multiplication
Subtraction
Clear this out
I said python name is
Day one underscore
Ex1
And there you go we have the addition of the two
Where is Richard
If you want to see how they look like before I print them I can say print a
Anne Frank
Go ahead clear it out and run it again so A and B so addition 6 + 17
15 subtraction of those multiplication of it
And division of those
Exercise one that we generated ready for
Basic mathematical operation
Are exercise 2 is to create a 3/3 matrix and perform operations
So the objective here is
To work with a multidimensional arrays and perform basic operations
So
Create first create a 3X using NP dot are
Then we will calculate its transpose using dirty
Perform element wise addition and multiplication with another Matrix
So let's try this out so first
Let's create a file
Quality one underscore ex2 Dot py
I'm going to create a matrix
Equal to NP
And since it's a matrix of 3/3 I said
So create first one
Call Ma
789 so I have this Matrix
What's 3 * 3 a recreated
Of course I need to import
Numb by
As NB
Next I want to
Print let's print this
Original Matrix
So we can differentiate
Call
Matrix I'll put it in the next line
Say slash
Next to do the transpose operator operation
To do this what we'll do is we'll create a transpose object a variable
And say Matrix that we created
That's all you need to do
The transpose of this
Slash
Transpose
Let's try it out
Get it out
This is
Day one underscore EX
2.3
Original Matrix
And here is a transpose that you can see 1 2 3 1 2 3 4 5 6 4 5 6 7 8 9
789 in this particular angle
Theater transport
It's pretty much
Reflecting the rules and switching The Columns and rows
You're one by one was changed to one by one one by two
What's change to 2 by 1 so that's why two is here so it kind of switches the rows and columns
Is Alexa so let's create another Matrix
I'll call it
Simplicity another Matrix
Empty
And this time
I'll create
Comma
I can even use the transport to do the same operation but it's more fun to
Create
A completely opposite side
Matrix 987 654 321
Simon and The Matrix
I want to say print
Now this first one is element wise addition
Slash
And I want to display
Matrix
Another Matrix
I also do
Multiplication which is much more complicated in Matrix
Clear this out
Let's run it out
So we have the transpose and then here
We have the Edition because it's all
Opposite numbers it should give you a matrix of 10
And then for multiplication
We have this output here
Multiplications of 9 * 1 is
8 * 2 is 16.7 * 3 is 21,000
Girl got element wise
Arithmetic here
So I hope you were able to follow along and build both these exercises exercises one and two
If you had any issues or problems let me know in the comments and I'll get back to you
And for some additional practice you can create a 4 by 4 metric
And calculate
The sum of it rows and columns try that out
Next you can write a program
Which means scaling the values between 0 and 1
And then finally
Try to generate a random area
And find the minimum and maximum values
And do this using NP or Not by library and not just the basic list so it's
One day one of week 2
We learned the basics of numerical Computing with numpy focusing on creating manipulating and performing
Operations on
The Hands-On exercise hopefully will ensure practical understanding of mathematical and
Stereo operations if you had any questions or problems let me know and I'll get back to you