Day
Advanced number yesterday
But today we're going to look at some of the advanced number of operation that exist
So first
We're going to cover
Broadcasting in number
Now what is broadcasting
Broadcasting allows numpy
To perform arithmetic operations
On it
Of different shapes
Smaller areas are automatically expanded to match the shape of larger address
Some of the rules of broadcasting include
Dimensions are aligned from the right
And a dimension is compatible
It matches the other arranged dimension
One of the dimension
Is
So let's look at some examples for this
So first I'm going to import numpy
And then we'll do some errands scalar broadcasting
And then look at edit broadcasting in detail
So for this I'm going to create a new file
Why do python 5 save it under my
Week 2 day
I'll call it
Day to underscore
Samples
And start with
Importing
Numpy
As in
Next
Let's do some
Add a comment here are
Scalar
Broadcasting how does this work
So first of the area equal to
Eddie song theater
From a list
1 2 and 3
So this is my
No I'm going to say print
So this will
Guess what it does is it adds
10 to each and every element in here
If you want to see an example
I'm going to say
Clear LS
And I'm going to say
No I said day samples instead of the
3D 2 samples but that's fine
I'm going to say python
Day samples
I have 11 12 and 13 so 10 was added to every single element so it kind of broadcasting the number to each and every
Clean scale armor scale Lottery
Broadcasting so I have a matrix
Equal to NP Dot
And this one I'll create a 3 2/3
Matrix
1 comma 2 comma 3
And the next element in here
Alarm for comma 5 comma 6:00
Straightforward one
Social create me a matrix 2 by 3 which is 1 to 3 and 4 * 4.56
Activate a vector
NP dot are
Call at 1 comma 0 comma 1
Okay so there you go that's a record
No I am going to say print
Matrix
Plus vector
So the output for this will be based on the values that we have here
It will give me
Below it will be 5:57 because it kind of takes this factor and adds it prop
Delete each line of the Matrix let's look at the output
And we have 224 because 1 + 1 + 2 + 0
Two and then 3 + 1/4 that's what we have the next line
4 + 155 + 0
And 6 + 1/7 so this is how
Edit broadcasting Works where you to take a vectors here with single lady and then I am
Broadcasting it to the entire Matrix here
Next that we're going to look at is aggregation functions
No aggregation functions
Comput
Summary statistics for Aries is pretty helpful in AI world
So let's look at some of the common functions that are available in the aggregation functions
I am going to remove everything
MP
I actually I'll create a matrix here
It will be
A matrix of
Need to fix this okay
Matrix of
Comma
45 and 6 so I have this Matrix in which is 2 * 3
Next
Let's look at some of the functions
First I want to do the total sum of all elements
Someone call it some
And I can use NP
Dodson this is the function that you can use
This will give you the total sum of all the elements in this Matrix up here
I can say print
I can see what is the mean of this particular
Matrix that we have you can say NP
Dog mean
And pass the
I can also get the max
Similar way Max
Comma
Antidote
And pass the array to it
Similarly I'm going to just copy paste this
I can get
Max so I can get men
Save
Next
I want to get the spread of the data how is the standard deviation
Standard
DB
For that I just called the function STD and password
What else can I do
Next I can
Get some along the rules for sample road so that I can say some
A long rose
For that I can say np.sum
And then I give the area
And I said access equal to 1 so it
Take one single access it will give you
Same thing you can do
Call him
Where you can I see columns
Npd.com
Nexus is 0
So what access is for the row and
Phil Collins axis is equal to 0
Go back here
Let's run
And you'll see some
Is 21 if you had the 6 + 5 + 4321 is 21 mean is 3.5
Max is 6 minus 1
Standard deviation is 1.707
Some along the rules is 615 634 560
And 6 + 5 + 4 is 15 somewhere along the columns is 1 + 4 is 57 + 5
72 + 5 is 7 and 3 + 6 is 9 so that's how you can use the aggregation
Functions that are available
Let's look at
Boolean indexing and filtering now what is Boolean indexing
You are you you use bouillon erase
Or conditions
The filter element
Promenade
So let's look at some examples of Boolean indexing
What I'm going to do here is
I am going to get rid of everything
I
Create an area
A single
Accessory 1 2 3 4 5
And six I have this available next I am going to filter all the even numbers so to that
More I can also use more operator
Equal to 0 what this will give me it will print
2486 so this kind of filters even numbers
Separ
So you can check that out
Next is modifying the elements based on a particular condition so for example
That is greater than 3
Equal to zero
In this case if the values are greater than 0
It will make sure that it will change that
Values into 0
So I'd say modified
Let's open this and check it out
So to get the events 24 and 6:00 I've created this is more of a filtering option here
And then to modify elements based on the condition if you see this one to three zero zero zero
So if any value is greater than
Three inside an item
It will change those values into 0 so this is kind of very helpful when you work with data sets and you want to
Change volume specially when you are creating models or trading models
Next
Let's look
Random number generation
And setting seeds we already did something random number generation in Python now let's see how we can do this using
So first for random number generation
Vampire provides the NP dot random module
For generating random numbers
Let's look at some of the common functions
For
Go back
Do this get rid of
Everything
And I am going to first generate
Random numbers so I am going to create a random array
Equal to NP do
Random
R&D that's what we use
So this will create a random array for us and the uniform for the uniform distribution of 0
Number one
So if I bring this you can see how this looks like I'm going to say
Random
Remove the area to the next line so it's more clear
I want to call it random
Go back
Clear it out
And run this and you see you have a random area of 3/3
Which are the random numbers with uniform distribution
From 0 to 1:00
I want to show the general integers instead of the
Numbers that you have created so I'm going to call it random
Integers
Equal to NP
Random
And it's very similar until here
Acceptance
Say
Call Martin
Comma size
Dub
So this one as it says here
That it will return you in a matrix of 2 * 3
With numbers from 0 to 10 which are integers
So if I want to print this I can print saying
Random
Integers
Slash
And that is my random not area that is my previous one random integers
Let's go ahead
Near the South and I will have two different
First for the Grand Am
And then next is random integers
If I don't need it again
If you see every single time
Give me different
Numbers and integers are integers based on
What is generates
Next thing that I want to talk about is setting random seeds
Now this ensures reproducibility
By fixing the random sequence before what happened was
Every time I run it
I was getting different numbers every single time
So what I can do here is I can
Say NP
Dot random
Dog seed I like my favorite number 42
And then
Now when I
Use the random numbers output will always be same so if I
Go back
No matter how many times I run
The values will be the same because I've set up a particular seed and this is very helpful in some of the models Where We Are
Training the data set and picking like
I'm picking a particular data set for training and we want to make sure that every time we run that
Run that training set it uses the same
Training set and testing sets for our models so that this is very important to know about setting the seats
Now that we understand understood more about advanced
Let's get into some Hands-On exercises
My first exercise is broadcasting operations you've already done this but the objective here
Is to perform operations on arrays
Of different shapes using broadcast
So first will create a 3 by 3 Matrix
And then we'll add a 1 by 32 to The Matrix
And then multiply the matrix by Skiller
So let's get started
Create a new
Find save
SD to
Core exercise 1.5
Not here let's create a matrix
Equal to okay I need to import numpy
S&P
And then NP
Eddie let's get this area of as I mentioned 3 by 3 so that I can do by
Sing one two and three
Comma next one I'll say for 5 and 6
The next matrix it's very easy to guess what I'm going to do 789
I want to see the vector which is 1/3
And here's the vector I'll give it this time I say 10 and
Minus one
Let's bring some negativity in the vectors
Broadcasting Edition
You seen that I'm going to say a result
Addition equal to
Matrix
Vector
So this will give me Edition so let's print it out just so we can
See the results of course I like to keep it clean the court
Addition
Is common result at
Next I want to broadcast the scalar multiplication to do that let's say
Result underscore multiplication
Equal to Matrix
Times
Multiply
Kitchen
And here I'm going to say
Result
Make sure that it's on the next line for both of them
Cleaners Resort
Results should be based on addition of these two so let's look at it
Clear it
And the core College python day 2.exe one so there you go that's our
Addition first where we took this one two three one zero - 1 + 222
45610 - 1 + 55555 and increment
Recommend and it was 888
Now multiplication for my Matrix which is this area
I multiplied by 2 that's why every single number 246-810-1012
141618 is twice what these values were initially
Where we did the broadcasting operations again
Second exercise
Is to generate
Add filter a random data set we already did this but again this is an exercise that you should probably follow along
The objective is to generate a random data set
Filter elements based on conditions
And calculate the summary statistics
So we will create a 55 Matrix of random integers between 1 and 50
Filter values greater than
25 and replace them with zero
You saw that but we'll do that again
And calculate and print the sum
And standard deviation of the modified Matrix interesting enough
Let's go ahead and start it
McClure this out
I am going to create another one
Save it as
Exercise
And yeah
First
Is import
Nump
S&P
Next Step
Agent
The random data set so I am going to say data set
Equal to NP
Dot random
Dodge Ram in as I mentioned you know I want a random integer today
Into this
I am going to sit and says 1 to 50 song this is one comma 51
And then size
Equal to
Bye bye
5 minutes that's what I want to do so this will give me
Matrix of 555 of random integers between 1 and 50 The Next Step
Is to print this so we can look at the differences
Original / n
Call Ma
Data
So display the data set out
Nashville Next Step as I mentioned filter the values greater than 25 and replace them by zero
So let me add comments here so we know what we are
Generate
Random
Data
Next time mentioned was we will
Try to
Filter
Values
Greater than 25 and
Replace with
And finally we will
Calculate
Somebody
Stats which I will do the same mean and standard deviation
So now to Filter part
Data
Greater than
Data set where values of data set
Are greater than
How to replace them by zero
As simple as that
You'll bring this
Modified
Data
Slash in
Call Ma
Data set
Three places the existing data set with the new data set
Now calculating the summary statistics of the new data set that we have
Everything
Should be n
Got some
Of that entire data set
Next I want to as I mentioned I want to do mean
And next I want to do the
Standard
Deviation
Now mean was
And standard deviation was STD
So I have this
Let's go ahead
And print it out and Lucas it looks any good
You can I'm not set the seat here you can set the seeds every time the output is same but I'm going to run it just one
Somerset Park Sunday 2:30
Don't underscore
It has some numbers which are about 245 so those are for example this 40 is set to 0
What is 34 reset to
So this is the modified data set with values restricting up to 25
The sum of this entire data set is 182 I'm not going to do Edition manually I trust the system
The mean is 7.28 in the standard deviation is 7.7
It's pretty good compared as a since I was going from 02 so you want to
95 in this particular case and we have reduced all the higher numbers to 0 so there's much more flexibility towards the
And that's why the standard deviation and mean
More inclined to the Lesser numbers if I don't do this here
It will be much more higher
Can you get it 5 8 4
What numbers towards the higher end
Hope I see this
Want to go back
No let's talk about the next step so we have some additional practice for you
You can create
A 3D random area
And compute statistics along specific access we did that previously where we specified
Axis equal to 0 or 1 depending on if you want to call them or no
Then you can write a program
To generate a data set
Of random floats
And normalize the values between zero and one
You did something like that
Some examples we have so you know
And finally
Implement conditional replacement
To create a binary mask for values about pressure
We did that in our exercise is so
I hope that is helpful if you have any problems or questions or need help on these
Let me know
To summarize today
We dived into advanced numpy operations
Including Broadcasting
We looked at aggregation is it filtering and random number generation
Now these concepts are foundational as I mentioned for efficient numerical competition in Ai and data science work
How close is very helpful specially for training a model and testing those models with data
Let me know if you
Want any more explanation on these or had any problems or questions
I will always get back to you