Deity
Introduction to pandas for data manipulation we already completed number and some Advanced number
Now let's look at
The second favorite
Library which is pandas
First we're going to look at introduction to pandas data structure
Where we going to talk about what is pandas
Pandas is a powerful python Library
For data manipulation and Analysis
It provides a easy to use data structure
Which is series and data friends
Let's look at those pandas data structures
First series
Series is a one-dimensional
Labeled
Capable of holding data of any
And we have data frame
Data frame is a two-dimensional labeled data structure
Like a table
Let's look at the Syntax for both of these
I'm going to go ahead
And create a new file python file
Save it on my day 3 I'll call it
Did three underscore samples
Let's start with
Importing pandas to import you say import pandas as
Edie is what it is with use
Is equal to
BD
And to this
I'll pass
Convert 20
Comma 30 list of three items which is 102030
And I'm going to say index
Equal to
So now if I print this series
How does it look like so this will create kind of like a dictionary where each one of these is indexed at
What kind of converts
You can think of it as
List
Into a diction
So let's go ahead and run this I'm going to go ahead here I mean week 23 perfect
Say python
Day
Diego
Is 10 East 20 C is
So that's how the series work at one dimensional labeled array capable of holding data
The data in this particular type you can see is integer 64 it also specifies that
As I mentioned date of frame is a two-dimensional label data structure
Like a table
So for that I am going to see data equal to
Create a dictionary of name
Is
Create a list inside the names actually Alice
And Bob
And I'll create
Another key
And this age
A list of numbers
Which is the richest 25 and 30
Now I can say DF
Equal to
Data frame
This is how you create a data Frame data
And
DSLR comment this out
Cuz you already saw how
How's the series looks like but
How does
Adidas frame look like so I'm going to clear this out
Run
0 and 1/0
We have named Alice and Bob age is 25 and 30 so it's kind of creates a two-dimensional lab
Play data struct
Which looks like a table
Next
Let's look at loading data from CSV Excel and other sources the kind of pandas is
News for that quite a lot
And it automatically converts them into Data frames
So first Common data loading methods is
First we can look at how to do this from a CSV file
We can see from an Excel file
And you can also do that from a dictionary
You already saw a dictionary which is right here
But we have a dictionary think of it you have a bigger dictionary with all the different things and you can pick
Adidas from there
If I wanted to
Big Data from Excel I would probably say let me comment this out
The way to pick from a CSV
Is data frame equal to
CSV that's the function that we call
And you give the part of the file
Well that CSV file is so I'm going to say CSV something like this
Next if you want to do similar with Excel
Google read
Excel
And then
You give your XLS or xlsx file
What are the days you give that part here so these are three different ways
You can
Load data from a CSV file directly
All from an Excel file
From a dictionary that is available we look at them in our hands on but for now this probably is very helpful
And it's used quite a lot because there are a lot of different websites these days like hugging face that
Flight to data sets that are available
And you can use those data sets
Do I get the CSV file and import them inside here Direct
Next
We have
Saving dat
Now we can save to CSV and save to Excel how just how we loaded
The data there are similar functions so for example if I
Loaded this I read this files now if I want to save it
You
You will say let's remove this
Since is the date of frame that I'm saving not so I said DF data frame
And then I'll say two underscore
CS
So this is how you can
Save the file
Adidas or CSV save the data
Frame into a CSV file
Similarly
I can just say DF Dot
Underscore
EXC
To save the data frame into an Excel file that you have
Also if you don't want the indexing because it also has index of 0123 in the data frame
You can set index equal to false and it will not add that
Additional
Call me if you've seen this column is 0 and 1 if you don't want that you just say index
Equal to false
Hey this is how you can save it now
When you
Imported download the data from a particular
CSV file you can you can load it the similar way and it will automatically index it for you
So next
Basic data frame operations let's look at some of them
We
First viewing data so if you want to view the data
I am going to go in
Common Dez
So I'm going to stay here
Data to do that
Let's say you have a data frame
And if you want to see the first five rows
You call a function called a DF dot head
It's a
Give dot head this will print
The first five rows of a particular data set
If you want to see the last three rows or more
You can always say DF Dot
Tail which will show you last few days but if you specify how many you want
You can see the last three rows of a data set
You can also get information summary of a data frame
By saying print DF
Info it will give you a complete information about the head the column that uses some statistics that is
It will give you that but if you want to get details statistics
You can use DF Dot
Describe function that will give you statistical summary this will give you summary of the data
This will give you statistical summary of the date when will try these out when we work with some Hands-On
Later on today
We have selecting an indexing
Now if you want to select a particular column
You can directly use
Data frame
And then give for example we had a name
Similar if you want to select multiple columns you can say DF
Red double square brackets in here so this will give you
Multiple columns which is name and age in this particular case
We can also look at it so that's for selecting columns now if you want to filter
Few rows
We can do that
By saying print
Alarm inside my data frame I want to filter rules for age is greater than 25
So I can do that by saying d
Is greater than
So this
Delta Rose where AJ's greater than 25 so you can get a particular data set
From a bigger dat
Know if you want to next thing that will look at is
Selecting by a particular position you can
But you can get let's say for first Real by position if you want to get a data
From the first drawer I can just say print
DF
I
Call Zito
So this will give me the first row by position
If I want to get the First Column by position I
DSi lock
Call my Z
This will give me
The First Column by position so the first item that is available First Column that is available by position
That's what this
Next
Let's look at selecting by label
So I can do that
Bye let me
Sprint DF dot history of
It's locked this will give you the first row by index label
And now if you want to get my name column I can use the same thing
As before you probably guessed it you just
So this will give you the name column data it
In this particular case
So that kind of summarizes a lot of different basic data frame operations now we want to see them in action so let's go
Let's go into hands on exercises
My first exercise
Is to load and explore a sample data
So the objective here is to load a sample data set and explore the structure
So we are going to get
A data set from get up data structures
You're going to get the iris data set from there
And we are going
Use Pandora to load that CSV data set and print the first
And the last
Funeral
Somebody information and statistics
So now to get that particular
Data
The URL for that is let's go here
And create a new file
I'm going to call it
Exercise 1.5
The URL for that is this one
I am going to open a chrome
Wasted
And you see
This is the data set that we have about Iris which has the
How about Irish flowers simple and simple words simple
Petal length petal width and species of flower that it is
Which is Sentosa
Or versicolor
Are virgin
So this is a simple basic data set
That is available
So I am going to use that
As I mentioned
The first
To import
Pandas PD so this is the English that we're going
Next I want to
Load the data set so for that
I am going to press the Lord data set
And inside here once the data frame equal to
Read underscore CSV
Now this part doesn't have to be local but
I can give this URL that we have
And it will read that CSV inside this data frame
Next
I am going to say
Explore the structure
Have you find all these things but never saw
Any of these in action
So I am going to say print
Five rules do you remember
How do we get the first five rows
If not
That's DF data frame
Dot head
Will give you the first five rows so we already saw the data
Let's look at the data again
I am going to say let's make sure we're in the right folder yes we are
Python
Did three door underscore X underscore 1 Dot py
It's going to download the data set and it will show me the first 501234
Rose from the data set because I called DF Dot
Next I want to do is
Last five rows now if you remember
That is still
And we have the first five rows
Find the last five rows right
I am going to comment desert because it's going to just keep on growing
Next thing I want to do is I want to get the information about
What's the date
Said that we have and we mentioned we just we can just say DF
To print it out
Get it
And here you go we have the information about it it says there are
5 columns supplement separated
Memory usage is this much and it tells you what are these the 150 non null
Count items data type that it saves
Fluid 62 where is the last one is an object because it's just texting so it kind of gives you an expression
Explanation about that
Next thing I want to do describe
Which gives me all the statistical information about that data
So I am going to say
And it says
Shuffle land is 150 which we know all of them are 150
Mean for each one of them what is that
Standard deviation minimum 75% of 25% of 50% of the data
75% of Max of those that gives you all this information
From there by just calling the description you don't have to specifically go and find me and Max
Standard deviation it does give you all the information in one single place
Next
Let's look at exercise 2 are exercise to is
Select specific columns
End filter rules
So we'll use the same data set that we used
Will practice selecting columns and filtering rows based on particular conditions
So we select specific columns in this case will use
Species and
Set alarm
Will filter Roosevelt length is greater than 5.0 and species is
So I am going to just work with the same data set so I'm not going to create another
Exercise
But here I want to select some columns so I'm going to say selected
Columns
Equal to if you remember how do you say
Square brackets
And here I am interested in species if you remember
We have
A species which is the last column here I think we did here species
Is the last column that's what I'm going to
Call always copy pasted because it's easier to
Make sure that you don't do any mistakes simple length is what I'm going to select these are the columns that I'm interested in
And I am going to print next
Selected
Columns
Slash n
That is
Selected columns let's see how does it look like
And here is my species and simple length data structure
Which selected columns have just that nothing else so this is my new data frame which
Only the two columns in there so I can play around with
Now you can think of it as
It can be used for
Data data modeling
You can take all the lens
All the different columns except for the ones that you interested in to predict
And train the model with
So that's what this can be used for
Next let's filter the rose so to filter Rose
I am going to create
Filter underscore Rose
And I would say DF
Now in this case
Settlement
Simple length
If that is
Greater than 5.2 that's what I was interested in
And I use
Download bracket because I want
Another condition
Which is DF
Species
Is a particular type
In this case I am only interested in I think the first one which is getting Sentosa
So I'm only interested in
She's greater than 5.0
I can go ahead
Did I make sure to close everything and
Printed out
Filter
Slash
Filtered roast
I'm going to
Comment this out I don't need that
Clear it
We have 0510 1415 these are the ones that simple length is greater than 5
And the species is to do so these are the
All the rules that are available
Weather filtered items that we are interested
So they go this is pretty awesome
I hope you are able to follow along with both exercises that we've done here if not if you had any
Problems let me know now you can always look at
How this is useful
If you've never worked with the data modeling or AI projects before this is probably new for you but will be using
Describe the Lord
When are in our later weeks
The additional exercises for additional practice that I have for you is
You can load a local Excel file and explore its structure
And then you can create a data frame from a dictionary
And add a new calculated column to it
Also try to
Save filter dat
To a new CSV file
Lay down with this and let me know if you have any issues or problems and I'll get back to you
Suggest to summarize
Today we learned the basics of working with pandas including data structures
Loading data sets and Performing essential operations on data frames
These skills are crucial for data manipulation in data science and are workflows so I hope you are able to catch up
If not I would say repeat these functions and learn them again and again try with different data set
And make yourself more
Comfortable with using these functions if you have any issues or problems or questions let me know