Data cleaning
And preparation with pandas
Today we're going to look at how we can
Make sure that the data that we have is clean and is ready for pandas
So we can run different statistic models on
So first
Is handling missing values sometimes you get the data but there's not
All the columns are all the rules have the right amount of data right data in there or has missing
Buy handle missing values
Missing data can affect analysis and model performance
Pandas provide powerful tools to manage these missing data
So let's see how we can handle these missing data so there's different methods
To handle missing data
First
Dropping missing values
By drop any
Function
We also have
Still missing values
With felony
Also we can do linear interpolation that based on the data that we have
We can fill data which is on a similar lines to that particular data set so that's what interpolation means
Let's look at some examples
I'm going to go ahead and
Start a python file
Save it in my day for call it day for
Underscore samples
In here
That's if you have a data frame DF
Now this year if I want to
Rose with any missing values I can say DF
Drop any
And what this does is drop in a drops rose with any missing values
So if there is like 100 rows
10 of them don't have any values in particular rules it will drop those
Another way is to drop columns with missing values
So we can get rid of some of the columns altogether because that might cause some issues or you don't even need those columns for
Example if you have a data set for
Property values in California
And you have some columns over there
Which talks about weather now that doesn't
Change the value of price because all the houses are in California and if the weather data is missing we don't even need that
So we can say
And in this case
Access
Equal to 1
So what this does is this will drop columns with missing values
Next time you spoke about is
Sitting missing values
If you can't drop some but we need those values so for example the same data set that I give example of California houses
Now it has salaries
People who are living in
Monthly income is available in the data set but
We have 90% of the data and 10% is missing
So if you want to fill that with
Let's say a zero amount so you can always say
For example whatever the column name is
So let's say in this case is salaries
I can say
Column name I'm just using generic column name
And I can say Phil
1207 of value
In there which is 0
Which doesn't make sense to your salaries but will look at interpolation for that but
You can if you want to just enter some value
And it doesn't matter if it's zero or some random number you can save that here
Cedric this is not a numbers or anything that is empty with zero
Next Tuesday
Two different types of fish forward fill in backward fields
That you can do by saying GF Dot
And method
Equal to
If it's forward fail
Take the forward values you can say FF
FC
Similarly if you want to use
Backward field use diesel
So this will enter value based on the data that is available for Woodfield or backwards which kind of
Makes more sense but
Still in salaries it makes more sense but
Still is not the right way
Then we have interpolation
Now you can use interpolation because it kind of uses a linear interpolation here
You can get the data set like for example California houses and their salaries
But now you can use linear interpolation to kind of
Add value that are similar to other houses just because you want
To make sure that there is no empty data set so no empty columns
You can do that by saying for example column
Equal to
Equal to DF
And then you can just say dot
Bullet
Does the function that you call
Where did I miss it here
Add values based on interpolation
If you don't care about it
You feel the missing values if you need the values that are available for example sometimes
Does data available for 95% and not available for 10% it might
Fluctuate your values but depending on what it is you want to fill some missing values you can do that
You can interpolate
Add based on the data that is available in Tripoli add interpolation data
To the nearest data
Let's look at data transformation
Three different things that I want to cover here
Renaming your columns that sometimes happens when
The column is named in the data frame which is not something that you would like or you prefer
So you want to change that that's
Renewing columns
You can
Change the data types
Sometimes you have data sets which are which are that's a particular column name
You want to change that
From
Strings to float you can do that here
Integers to Florida to integers you can do that
I did change the data types
You can also add we also can look at an example of how to convert
Today I'm a particular date that is given in a particular column
And then we have
Creating or modifying columns
You can modify a particular column for example if you have
A column with some data but you want to multiply that with two you can do that
So let's say you have a data frame
And first you want to rename the columns
So let's say d
Genie
And then inside that you can specify
The columns
Do you want to rename
What is its own name
What are the old name is
You want to rename that
To a new name
Can do that here
So this is how you can
Rename any of the columns
Next thing that I mentioned about was changing the data types
Now this can be done by saying let's say if you have a data frame
Also particular
And you want to change the data type from whatever it is
Let's say
You specify
Column name
And then
What type you want so I want to convert that as time
For example
There are some time does data says that is available in a particular let's say
Integer 64 and you want to convert 20032 because Pi towards doesn't work with it or Frameworks that don't
So you can do those Transformations using this you can change the data type like this
Rd
Another one I'll give you example that I mentioned
Was a converting to date time
So you have data but that is string but you want to convert it to daytime
I specify DF
Column name
So what it does is it takes the existing column and which is string in this case
Can you convert today's time for us
Next I mentioned about
Creating or modifying columns so you want to modify the data in the column
I can say that okay the whatever the new column is
Or whatever you call him that I want
I want to use the older column which is let's say
Existing column
And then I want to multiply all those values by two
Just an example
To create a new column and you modify
The value of that column
So that's how you can create a modify existing columns
Next
Let's look at combining and merging data frames
So sometimes you might get data frames from different places or it might be that say population
Data for 1990 1991 1992
Bunch of different
Data sets available but you want to combine them together
You can use the contact method
Which will concatenate will combine data frames
Along rozar columns
You can do merging where you can use the merge function which merge data frames based on a key or
And then we also have joining option using join
Which joins the data frames using
How this works
Delete everything here
So if I want to combine
Two different data frames along Route or columns
I can say
That's it for a rose first that's a combined data set
Kansas City PD
Comcast that is a function
I'll say I want to use data frame 1
Data frame to I want to combine these data from
Axis of
04 Rose
So first one will combine
Play the two data frames along rows
The second one
Will combine the
Data frames along columns depending on how you want to use it you can use this
Auctions
Data frames based on a key or condition
So I can have a merge data set
From PD dot as I said
Function is merge
Can you create the First Data said you're the first data set give the second data set
And then
On which column
Which common column do you want to merge them on
So let's say
You have data about
Houses and you have data about
About the people and then you want to merge both those data set based on the salaries of our income
Of that particular book of house so you can do that using this
Next
If I want to do more on the now if you're familiar with data set
This is the first one was merging on a common column but what if you want to do left join
PD
Do you have
Data Frame 2
And then you can say how
Equal to
Turn on
Which column what is the column that you have common column in both the data frames
You can specify that so this will do a left
Left
If you want to do inner join you can just say inner here
And specify the common column give both the data set so this is almost same as this function just that
How parameter changes
Next
How about joining joining data frames
Using index alignment you can do that similar to about
I can say joined
Equal to df1
Don't join and you pass the df2 here
And you can see how
Equal to in or you can say left just like before but this is how you can join data frames
Using index alignment without the column just index alignment
This is what it does
Now that we
Learn some of these
Different combinations and how to play with data frames let's go ahead
And work on a Hands-On exercise
Are exercise one is to clean a data set
Buy handling missing values and rename columns
The objective here is to practice handling missing data and renaming columns
What you going to do here is
Load a data set with missing values
Then fill the missing values in numeric column with the mean
And then rename the columns to follow consistent naming convention
Let's go ahead
And create
4 underscore
Exercise 1.3
I am going to import my libraries which is
Panda say
Most important numpy
Has Envy someone use everything that I have learned in the previous days
Then let's create a
Data set a sample data set
Since we don't want to use or use anything that is available
I'm going to create one here of simple easy one
Where I have names
Names I can enter
There's a list
Alice
We have Bob
And then
We have NP dot not a number is missing value
And then I have David here
So these are my
Names
Then I have it
Each column
And this has
Different values 25 Alice is 25 years old I don't know the
Age of Boston
The third person I know the age is 30 but I don't know the name and 35 for the day for David
Now
Coarse let's use instead of great we can use code
Discord 85
I don't know how much this person scored there's no data available
And 88
For the last bus
Guess what I have my data set
Available now I'm going to say DF
Dot PD for this dictionary that I am going to convert that into a data frame which we saw how to
We just call the data frame function
And pass the data to it
So we converted the dictionary into
Now that I have it
Let's print
Original
Data set of how it looks like slash
Call Ma
It's DF is what we're going to print out the entire thing because we don't have much did only three
Are three columns and four rows
No next I'm going to fill in the missing values let's run it just to check check it out
So I'm going to say python
Therefore underscore exercise
01234 it didn't text them not a number not a number is a missing values here and there
So now let's fill the missing values
I'm going to say dear
Age for age I can just say
Wherever there is an age which is
Missing values
Not available
Meaning of
All the different colors So based on the mean just fill this so it will probably be I would say around
30 song Let's see what it does
So that's the first part
I'm going to search for school
I'm going to say DF
I will interpolate in this case
Call the interpolate function So based on the straight line it will
Add some values based on the values that we have here
No
If I want to
Print this thing I can
Check it out
Let's say let's go here clear it out
Put on it
Now if you look at
The age if you see Alice age
Something
Score
If you see it's 80 now it's interpolated based on the values that we have here so even if this person never gave the score
The not a person not no name
Oscar more than Al
Ben Davis
Pretty good
Based on interpolation
Next let's rename some columns
Let's see how we can rename columns so I am going to say
Equal to
DFD
Rename
In this case I want to rename
Let's call
Columns
Equal to
I haven't seen name
I want to change that to
Student underscore name
And then
I want to change
Exam
And then
NetSpend
This entire thing
If you saw earlier still kept the same names now when I do this
Get it out on it
We have the new student named exam score is available
Now I can drop this one which has not doesn't have a name
But I don't want to write I'll keep the way it is and this is already decided that is available
So this is what I want you to do if you were able to follow along good if not
Whistle and let me know if you have any problems
My second exercise
Is too much to data sets and perform data transformation
The objective here is to combine the data sets and apply some transformation
What we will be doing is will create
Two data frames with a common column
Based on the column a common column
And then finally add a calculated column to the merge data set
So let's go ahead and do that so I am going to
Create a new file
Therefore
Underscore ex2 Dot py
Okay let's copy this these are always required most of the times
I'm going to create my first data set I will call data set
Airplane
Equal to PD
Data frame I'm just directly going to call this instead of creating a dictionary and password
Where I say ID
Is
A list of
1 2 and
Next I'll say
Is
Al
And Charlie
Okay next one
Is let's use it again
And this time I'll say
And 35
So I have my first date of frame
No the second one I'll create with the same IDs
Someone said do you have two equal to
Speedy Dot
Data frame
And this Frame I will give
IDs are same so I'm just going to copy this and paste it here
And then I said scores that these people these students have scored
And 88
So I have these scores available
Next let's bring them and check this out
So I have my
First data set
Slash
Comma df1
Right and I have my
Second data set I'll call you data set
Candida said
Do you have fun and df2
So my two data sets next I want to
Equal to PD Dot
March what's the function that I'll call
What's the first data set was the second data set
And then how do I join it I said I want to use in a joint
And what is the column that I want to join it on
On ID so I will say ID
Perfect next
Let's print and see how does it look like
Merge data set
Slash
Comma
So that will give me my money dat
Now let's add a calculated column to it so we will create another column and add to it
Based on the data that we have
I want to see much
Let's create
Score percentage
And this percentage
Will be
Most did I set
Whatever the score is
What was the score is okay I think I have to use this
Bracket
Divided by 100
* 100
So this is the percentage
And this is a print
And I'll say
Transform
Data
/
Look up the name Sam so that should not cause a problem
So let's go ahead and run this
I hope you were able to follow along
If not pause the video just make sure that you are at this point and then
Put on python D4
280 so I'm going to go ahead and say
Ex2
And they are data set initially 1 to 3:40 the ages
We have this courses now it's the most data set 123 Alice Bob Charlie
And their scores here transform data
I got the percentage now this is out of 100 so of course
Values will be almost same unless I change this
Being out of 200 than it will be
Will be half of it most probably 4245 and 44 so that's how this works and I've created it so this
Can be helpful even in
This data set where you have
Data set with all the students and you have their scores
In a different data set
And then you want to also calculate the percentage so you can use this entire data set
To get what is the overall percentage of
Students that you have a how many of them passed or what is the grade level
In there so you can use the data set for additional
Calculations
Now that you completed this for additional practice
You can
Drop columns with more than 50% missing values
You can merge three data sets and analyze relationship between them
You can also do convert
Categorical data to numerical
Using one hot and cold if you don't know what that is look it up but will be covering that
Suggest to summarize
Today we learned how to clean and prepare data sets
Using pandas focusing on handling
Missing values renaming columns and combining data frames
These skills are essential for pre-processing data and data science and are Workforce and will be using this
Quite a lot in every single projects
So if you had any issues or problems let me know so we can catch them early
And then you can move on to the next days