Welcome back to day 5 today we're going to cover data aggregation
And grouping in pandas
Let's start with grouping data by categories
So now why group dat
Grouping data allows you to perform operation on subsets of data based on shared Kate
We can do group by
Using Group by in pandas
The Syntax for this is something like let's create a new file first python
Save it inside day 5 I'm going to call it de 5
Underscore samples
I'm here let's look at the syntax so grouped
Equal to
Data frame
Group by
And then you select the column name here
So that's how you use that's the Syntax for group by
So now let's go ahead and look at what are the different operations that are available
Now first you can go over it right over groups so you have a groups have a bunch of groups and you can
Retreat over this by name and group you can do that
By saying
Go ahead and
Name
Group
Groot
A box of this group that we have
Name I can
Group
So based on that it will it rain over the groups and you can show display the
Name and the group out here
Operation is to apply
Aggregation
This can be done using you can say
Group
Dot mean this is a function that you can use
And you can also say grouped
Dodson so you can create apply these aggregation functions
Do a group category
Next
Let's look at aggregation functions
So first is using Group by we can combine grouping with aggregation methods
We can do that by
Saying something like this I can take a data group data frame
Group by
And to that I can specify
Category column
And then
I can say
Numeric column
Numeric
Underscore column
And then directly give me to it
So this will give me the meaning of that particular columns grouped together
Next is I can say
Group by
Category underscore
AGG know this is the aggregation function
You can
Specify the
Numeric underscore column
End of that column
You can
Specify in the list format of what are you looking for for example I can say I'm looking for me
And looking for men
It will do that
All together
This is this is the power of group by where you can combine grouping with aggregation methods
Next we have using the pivot table
Now you can reshape the data
With aggregation if used pivot table function so
Dads can be done using that says pivot
Equal to data frame
Favorite underscore table
Into that I can say values
Equal to
Numeric underscore column
I can see the index that I want to use
Is
Category column
And the aggregate function
Aggregate
Function that I want to use
Using pivot table you can do this
Another
Operation that another aggregate function that we can do is custom aggregation
Now this you can apply custom function using AGG function
So that can be done using I can say let's say create a function called as
Underscore
Function this is my range function which takes an input of let's say X
And then I can say return
Extra Max
Minus x dot
If I want to use this range function this is my custom aggregate function I can say
Do you have
Group by
Category
Numeric
Shear dot AGG
Group by category column
Please close this
Off numeric column
AGG
The function that you created function
What is the fastest values and it will Group by based on this custom function and will be doing a lot
Lord of these in our hands on so if you don't understand exactly how it will work I'm going to show you some samples
In the in the hands
How to apply custom functions using AGG here we use
Is range function be created a custom function and we applied
To that which is x-maxx - X-Men which will kind of give you the difference between the maximum and minimum
Next thing that I want to look at is
Calculating summary statistics for group data so if you have group data how do you get
The statistics Forest so some of the common statistics that you can get a mean
Max and min
I'm going to go here
I have my category column not to get the mean I can just say mean something like this
Let me just make sure that
Play keep the previous one
Move it
The category column and then here I can directly use the mean function
And get me from it
Similarly for Max all you do is change this to Max
And now I know how you and I know you know how to do men is this way so these are the three functions that are
Common statistics that are available
For us now if you want to do
Multi multi aggregation that's our next topic of how to do
Multi aggregation that you can do
In a similar format which we saw a little bit earlier
Group by and here I can just say dot aggregate
Applies to numeric
Numeric column
Close this
End of this I am looking for what am I looking for that make sure everything is closed
I'm looking for mean
Call Ma
That's what I'm looking for and
This aggregation function ends
And if you want to format it nicely can always have it
So now I'm gripping buy multi aggregation that I'm saying I want to group by Bas mean Max and Men
So these are different things
That I wanted to cover inside inside inside data aggregation and grouping in
When does now let's go ahead and to understand it better let's jump into Hands-On
The first exercise that we're going to do is we're going to group data by a categorical column
So we'll know the data set
And group the data by categorical column first will load a sample data set with a categorical
Can you call him inside it and
The group the data by categorical column and calculate the mean for each group those are the steps that will follow pretty much two
Steps that will do to see how all this works comes together
I'm going to call it day 51
Inside this
First that's important because
You're using the pandas functions
The sample data says let me create a data set here
That I have
Which is
Someone else got a
Then someone got
Someone got sea and then I'll use one more C
So these are different classes that are available
Next
I'm going to see the score
For each one of these
Is
Let's give some numbers 85
And 80
So I have my numbers
Next I am going to get
Create an alarm for 8
Where it will show the agency 15
16 and 15
So I have that I have three columns here last score and age now let's create a data frame out of it
Already so many times did frame and pass it this data so I creating a
Video film from Ki Valley dictionary
Once I have that
Let's print out
Original data set
Slash in
And to this I'll pass DF
And calculate the mean so the categorical
The categorical column that you're going to select here is glass
And will calculate the mean so to do that I'm going to say
Group
Equal to I take the data frame
And I said goodbye
I'll select the categorical column class
And I look for me
No let's go ahead
And print this out
Grouped
Let's see how does it look back I'm going to go back here
Alice and I'll say python
Define underscore ex1
Reddit this is my original as you know ABC a b a b c c and these are the score and this is the
Now here it's group
Based on this categorical Class A B and C the group together based on class that's what we
And it got a score so if you got the mean score for
A which is 86 based on this and this
It got based on this and this 81 and she should group them properly
And give me the statistics
Of mean for this particular project
Next
I'm going to do exercise too where we will calculate the summary statistics for group date
The objective is to use grouping
And aggregation function
To calculate summary statistics
First what we'll do is we'll group data by a categorical
Column class that you use before
And then
Calculate the statistics like mean Max and Min for
Numeric columns
So we already have created this project so we can just work off this
I am going to comment this out
Stats
Equal to DF
Dot Group by
I want to put them by class
And since I want all the different
Aggregates and I want it for
Let's see I want for
Score this time
Say this before
And here what are the different things I want
I want
And I want
Men
Now if you want to add also age because we did that before you can also
Use
And inside this I can
Copy and paste the same stuff
Now let's print this out
And see how does it look like
Go back
And there you go so we have
The class ABC
Add me and Max and men are calculated
And given to you in a nicer data set
For both score and age
In two different columns and there's a columns for me and Max and minimum
So there you go this looks like what we wanted we broke the data based on the class and we got all the
So somebody statistics for this group data
I hope you were able to follow along and understand if you have any questions on this let me know
It just helps you group
Different types of data types together and then get me and Max and Min or different statistics
Information based on what you're doing another option is if you want to do some more additional work
You can practice with
Creating a data set of sales data and group it by region or product category you can find these dat
Online so you can pick that you can use the pivot table to calculate total sales per region
Also you can create a custom aggregation function
To calculate the variance for each group
And again while working on this if you have any problems or questions let me know and I can help you out
Summarize today
We learned how to group data and calculate summary statistics using pandas
These techniques are fundamental for aggregating and summarizing data in preparation for analysis
Search for visualization of the data when we are doing some AI projects in the future