Basics
Data visualization with Matt plate
NC
What's the fun in working with all the data if you can't plot your data
So this
Day is dedicated to that
Let's start with introduction to Matt plot lib for plotting data
Now what is Matt plot lip
Is the foundational python Library
For creating static interactive and animated plots
It allows for detailed customization of plots
Let's look at the basic syntax
Doing using matplotlib
I want to go ahead and create a new file
Python save
In my day 6 I'm going to call your day 6
Underscore samples
And here I am going to first import
Matplotlib
5 PL
Do a basic plot
Saginaw College
Basic
Not to do that let's see if I have a list of items x equal to 1 comma 2 comma 3
And four
Which is
September
Comma 30
So these are my basic X and Y if I want to plug this I can just say PLT
Dot Plot
An X and Y is what I want to plot
And if I want to see it not that show
As simple as that
Let's go to our terminal
Can you get it out
I can say
Python
Day6 underscore samples
San Diego VCR
Laureate x-axis and y-axis
And based on the coordinates that I've given it has plotted that
Using my plot
Next let's look at some basic plots
We have the line plot used to visualize Trends over time or sequences
We just saw one
Which is similar to that
But we can create another one what I can do here is
I can say
TLT I can keep this actually
Just for future
So for line plot
What's a line plot
PLT Dot Plot I can directly use that instead of creating variables I can say
3 here give the first place I want to give the second list which is
20 +
And I am going to give label equal to
BLT
Title I'll give it a title
The previous one we didn't give title so this will
Give you an idea
Over the title shows up I'm going to call it line plot
I can give up the attributes like
Next level
Which will give a label to the x-axis I'm going to just call it X
Access
All right next I'll say Lord Dot
Why lab
Again as you probably guessed it
They call it my access
And then next I am going to support Dot
Legend create a legend for this
Mplt
Sure so now if I run this
I have a straight line because 1 2 3
10:20 will be a straight line you see x-axis you see the line plot y-axis all those lab
Let's look at
Bar chart
The birth chart as you probably have seen is a bar
Alarm for bus displayed
So for that
No comment
This
Go up here
NC bar
Chart
At this what it does is used for
Categorical data comparison that's what
Bar charts are usually used for where is line plots were used for to use to visual
Strands overtime or sequences
I'm going to say Carter
Gold is equal to how many credit list of categories
And just to make it simple I'll call it a
Category
Next I will
Give me the values
List which will have let's call it 10:15
And 7
Can probably already
Draw the bar chart in your
So I can say PLT or bar
And here I'm going to say categories of pass categories I'll pass the values
And I can also pass
Colors
In this case I am going to use let's use blue color
BLT Dot
Title for title I will give
Bar chart
How old is
And then say
Lord God show
And on this
Okay this is still running I guess
Run this again
And does my bar chart with my values which
Abnc categories
And I have 1015 and 7:00 displayed right here and the color is blue you can change that to whatever you want
Customize it to however you want
Next one that you're going to look at
Is histogram
No histogram shows the distribution
Offer data set so for that
Comedy South First
The thing that we want here is histogram
For Instagram I'll give a data set
I use one
4 +
Bunch of data set point
For plotting histogram you say
Plot dot Heist
And inside here I have to give the data
Next I need to get
How many bins I need to create for this Instagram I'm going to say I'll create four bins
Color that I want to use equal to
Since we use blue last time
And there's also something called an edge color
Reuse Black Friday
So that's how you created now I can give the same all
Parameters and just give title for this again
Histogram
And then I'll see plot that show
Save
23 and 4
Displayed right here in the histogram format
And we have four bins and
It has color green and the edge color
Which is black is displayed that so
That's it I close this app
Make sure this is closed clear
Next thing that I want to talk about is
Scatter plot
Does scatter plot visualizes the relationship between two continuous variables and you've got a lot in
Nearby project
So I am going to go back here
Common desert
Pixel just say this is
Scatter plot
X equal to let's give it some numbers 1
234 and 5
I want to give some numbers to why
Probably 10:12
945 some random numbers
How to create
Catapult I call PLT dot schedule for schedule give X and Y
And the colors for the schedule I'll give
Lord God
Tit
I'll call it scatter plot
Next finally
The Ziploc
Let's look at how the scatter plot look like
Good on this project
And they got a scatter plot so think of it if you have like a big data set how it will look and that's what you
Be quite a lot these days
When data scientist talk about the Scatter Plots are the items or how it's scattered and how they are
Play classified into different places and so this is very useful for building things in future
So go ahead clear this out that's all that I have here
Next let's talk about customizing plots now we saw that we can add title X label
Available Legends all those things what are the different things we can do in here so we can add a dimension tit
Access labels we can give Legends
We can adjust the colors and styles
So let's look at some of those things that we can do I'm going to use this exact same thing
Here that we have here
You wanted to give a title
We can give
Text lab
Next level
Access lab
I can give you the same thing for
Why label
Y-axis label
And I can also give
A legend
For now I don't have any Legend so I'm just going to create
Empty list and call it
Data set one something like this
Go back run it
And we have this year you see the legend on the top I can give multiple Legends
Find the list and you see the entire x-axis and y-axis
Title is already given scatter plot
I can also change the colors
So when I
Plot a particular thing for example if I want to
Now let's use
1300 earlier
Someone comment this out
Go ahead
And when I plotted here X and Y
We gave the label a strength
And then we can also give
Color
Orange
I can give
What is going to do I can give line style because it's a line
Does equal to if I want to give daughter I can just say Dash and dash
And I can give
Mark
Equal to
Small or something like this
Put on this now
Let's make sure that
What is closed
Run it again and there you go I dotted lines
Are orange
We have color orange nice lifestyle dashed because of this
San Marcos zero that's what I've given here you can also use
Expertise
San Diego now we have X points over there that's how it looks like
So these are different customization that you can do
2 + 2000
Next
Let's get introduction to Seaborn for advanced visualization
Now what is Seaborn
Built on top of Matt plot lib
For easier and more visually appealing plots Seaborn was born to bring some more
Customization to Mad plot live
It provides a high level interfaces
For statistical graphics
Some of the common Seaborn plots include we have the heat map
Which visualizes a matrix of data
We have Airport
Which shows are wise relationship in a data set we can kind of
SDS out
What I'm going to do is I am going to take this
Same project
Import
Seaborn as SNS
Next
I am going to
Import numpy
As NB
So now let's get some data data equal to
MP dot I'm going to just create some random
Integers Sears random numbers
Will fly by 5
And then I said SMS
Dot heat map this is for the heat map that visualizes the Matrix of data so you can give
Give the data to that since you created that Matrix data above
Annotations equal to
And then see
Equal to it has bunch of different
Things that you can use for colors and for that I'm using cmap
Which has bunch of different options I'm going to use cool warm
Next I'm going to say blood Dot
Title
Heat
As usual not that show
Save this and I'll run it here
San Diego on heat map
Pretty cool right so based on the Matrix that it created of 5 by 5 Matrix
It has this one two three four five one two three four five items here and it shows the heat based on where
The numbers have been randomly created of course every time you run this it will look different because I'm not given a seed
Cincinnati again it will look a little different from the previous one because it randomly generates these numbers and then
Make this heat map out here
Next for Fairport
Which shows where is relationship in Adidas set
You'll have to say instead of saying this
Please comment this
SMS
And then to that you'll give DF which is the data frame which I don't have
Is it right now but we'll see in one of our hands on example and then
You said that's
That will give you a show the pairwise relationship in this particular data set and we'll look at those in our
Hands on but that's those are the two different heat maps and their plots that you can do using so these
What are the common C1 plots that you can build
Let's run to our hands on exercise so based on whatever you learned
First exercise we're going to create basic plots with matplotlib
The objective here
Is to plot a line graph a bar chart and a scatter plot
So what are you going to do is we're going to create
Data for Trends categorical comparisons and relationships
And then we're going to customize
Plots with titles labels and legends let's get started with exercise 1
I'm going to close this and create a new file
Save it
6 underscore exercise 1
Dot py
And make sure my other projects are
Close all close this
Go back to hear clear this out
To start with first we need math problem import
Rockledge
ESPN
So first step
Is to create a line plot
But for that
We need some data so create an object variable called as years
And inside this I'll say 2010
2012 2013
I didn't say sales number for these years include
100 12
140 and 160 good sales numbers increasing
Of course
Elt dog
I'll pass the years
NCL says why
And then I'll say label
Equal to
Sales
Trend
I will give a color
Off blue
Windows
I'll use the marker of
And then I said give a lot of title
Sales over years
Next how to plot Dot xlabel
I'll give X labeled as is our ears so I'm going to say
Yes
BLT dot while label
Is over the sales someone says sales
And then let's just play The Legend
And display the plot
Do this go back here
Well it's only cleared I'm going to say python day
6 underscore ex-1 running
And we have a line plot here based on the say yes and the sales
So that's pretty cool we have the legend of wood displayed perfect
Next thing that I want to do is a bar chart so I can say bar
How to create different categories
For this let's use
Electronics
Another category is clothing
And another one is groceries you can pick whatever you want
I'm just using randomly
Revenue for this
Is let's say 250
For electronics
For clothing
And 150 for groceries
No I'm going to say plot dot bar because I want to see a bar chart
I'll pass it categories
And Revenue
And give a color
Off green
Then I can say
Lord Dot
Title I'll give it a title I'll say
Revenue by
Kate
And show this a lot
Now if I run this
I have my line plot
Close this
I have
Bar chart I had to I should have commented that but if you close that the next one will run
I'll show you your categories you'll show your Revenue here
And if you have three different numbers to 5400 and 150 depending on what it is and that's why it is open
Connect to bar chart
Next thing that I want to do
Is
The scatter plot
So for this
Scatter plot
What do you need to do is first use let's say our study of how many hours
Stud
If I study 1 Hour 2 hours 3 hours 4 hour and 5 hours what's the difference
Exam scores based on how much are study
Say 531 hours I get
7085 just on the graph you can say depending on how much you study better use code
In your exams
Next episode
I passed this our studies
What's this exam scores
And I want to display
Nice color for these products not the status
Lord dot title
Exam scores
What's a plot Dot xlabel
I want to use a viable to
I'll call it
Exam scores
Then finally show me this plot
Run this
And I have my exam plots based on how much
What are study more High School
So these are the
Three jobs that is greater recruiter line graph showing
Sales Trend we did a bar chart
Showing Revenue comparisons and then we just got the plot showing the relationship between study hours and ex
So I hope you are able to follow along if not let me know and I can help you out
But let's move on to exercise to
But we will be creating a heat map with Seaborn
So the objective here is will you see born to create a heat map from a correlation Matrix
Instructions that I can follow here is first I load a data set and calculate the
Correlation Matrix
Then I'm going to visualize the correlation Matrix
Using a heat map
In this particular case
I will be loading up that same Irish database
That we loaded earlier in one of the days this week
So I am going to go here to create one
Day6
Underscore exercise 2.0 by
And this is the URL
We're going to get the data from
So first let's get pandas
SPD
Next we need
Seabourn
As SMS
Next I want to use
The Mad plot live
Lauderdale.by
Southeast 3
Next let's load the data set that we have so I'm going to say pound
Copy this from here
Load data set
And I'm going to say DF equal to
DD
Read CSV
In this series is coming from this URL
So I have my
Data set
Calculate
Relation
Matrix
To do that
I want to see
Correlation this is just a variable so it doesn't matter if it is a typo
CDF
Corr that's the function that will give us the correlation Matrix for the data that we have which is the
Types of petals
Open this we have
Next
I am going to say
The Heat
SNS
Heat map
Unpause the correlation
Where is it
Correlation Matrix
Next I will hope I have
2007 equal
Next I want to give annotation equal to
Drew annotated
Fancy
If you like the previous School warm I'm going to use that same
The same heat map
Lord God
Title
Equal to
Correlation
Heat map
Next I'm going to see plot dot show
So this should show me a heat map with annotation showing correlation between numerical columns in the data set which is
What is
If you remember this I can
Open this up again
In Chrome
Indigo supplements separate battle length battle with and species
So I will run this up in my
Okay I think we have a good grass running clothes this
Lights on
Day 6 underscore EX
2.3 run this bill pull the data could not convert string to
Foster the last column that we have over there is
Is is not is not numbers is not numerical so it will cause problems for that so what I'm going to do
I'm going to drop that
Column from my data frame
So to do that I can just say d e l
And that
Column was
Call
Let's open that
Data set again
It was called
Species go back
Jose drop that
Let's go back
Clear it out
Run it
And now we have it based on the other items that we have better pedal and petals settled with
What's the length in Federal Way it has the heat map depending on how the correlation Matrix shows up
So if I hope you were able to follow along with this if you have any questions or had any other issues not something that I'm
Can you sing let me know
For now
For additional practice you can look at
How to create a histogram with multiple
Data sets overlaid that's one thing that you can try
Next you can try is
Seabourn
To create a violin plot or box plot
For visualizing distributions
Try to combine multiple plots in a single figure
Using matte black lips
Subplot so try this out and let me know if you have any issues or problems
We learned how to visualize data using matplotlib and Seaborn focusing on basic plot
Asian and advanced statistical visualizations are these skills are crucial for presenting data
And uncovering insights in data science and are projects that will be working on in the future weeks so
Let me know if you are able to follow along if you had any questions or problems let me know and we can move to the next day see you tomorrow