Day 7
Exploratory data analysis or something called as Eda project
So here on day 7 we're going to create an exploded data analysis project
To do that let's look at all the different steps that
We need to follow
Applying data manipulation and visualization for India
So what is Eda
Explicitly data analysis involves summarizing data sets to uncover patterns
Relationships and insects
The steps in ETA
Include First Data cleaning
Handle missing values remove duplicates and fix inconsistencies we have seen that before earlier this week
Data transformation
Changing data types normalized data and create new feature if needed and that's also something that we saw
Spell this week
Aggregation and filtering
Summarizing data and applying filters to focus on specific aspects again something that you've already
Lower this so we are going to put all these steps together and that's what is called idiot or exploratory dat
Next
Let's look at identifying patterns Trends and correlations
Some of the visual tools that we use for these insights include line plots for
Sending data over time
We do bar charts for categorized companies comparisons
We use Scatter Plots
Define relationships
And we use
Heat map
For correlation analysis and we already learned how to build all these line by line plots bar
What's catalogs heat map using matplotlib and Seaborn we can build any of these
The key patterns that we are looking for
Is relationship between variables what is correlations
You looking for distribution of variables
How to build histograms box plots
And we'll find the outliers or anomalies these are the patterns that you're looking for
Let's talk about the summary statistics
Vigilance sites and hypothesis generation
What's
Think somebody statistics
You already seen how to get these
You can create a data frame
And call the describe function
Which will get you
The
The standard deviation
The main values the max values and much more so that's already taken care
Buy the data frame describe function
We have correlation
Which provides your correlation Matrix which we looked at
When we created a sea bone matrix earlier this week this week
Where we took the Irish data about all the Petals of flowers and we created a correlation Matrix over there
Next about
Hypothesis generation
Now formulate hypothesis
Based on observations for example we're going to take
Titanic data set in this particular today in in our project in a handsome and
One of the examples over there is
Passengers in higher Titanic classes
How high is survival rates
Is that true is that the hypothesis that is true that you can use ETA
To validate
All refute this hypothesis and that's what we will be doing
So we take the Titanic data set and our hypothesis is passenger in higher Titanic classes
What are survival rate now based on common sense or if you even watch the movie
You probably have seen
Highest Titanic glasses customer service
What allowed on the deck and they could get out of it there easily
Passengers in the lower
Glasses
What locked downstairs so there's much less survival rate for them
But at the end of the day you know what happened
But you're going to use the data set now
What kind of
Validate or refute this hypothesis using that's what we will be doing
So let's jump directly
Into our hands on Edda
On a on a sample data set which in our case
Will be picking up
Titanic data set
The link I'll provide you in a second
But our first task in this particular project
Will be to perform data cleaning
Aggregation and filtering
The data will be available
Using this URL
Just something similar to
Irish data set it's a CSV file here
Titanic CSP which is available in GitHub user content.com /
Dart data science Dojo / data sets Master Titanic
What's your speed has passenger ID
If you survived or not is 0 and 1
PC class what class they belong to 3rd class first class
A name of that person sex
Tickets for cabin and unboxed so it has all this information
That we can use
And it has a bunch of data available for us
So using these data set
So we have from Passenger ID 1
All the way
Okay let's close this
All the way to passenger ID 891 we have these many records now again this data set might not be
Barbie clean so we will be performing data cleaning as I mentioned aggregation and filtering to this particular
The first step that will be falling here is load the data set
And inspected structure
You will handle the missing values
Duplicate and inconsistencies in here
Then you're going to apply filters
Are aggregation to summarize
Specific groups
So let's go ahead and create a project I'm going to start a new project
Python file
Save it as
Day
Underscore EX
And here I am going to first import
Pandas SPD
I need to load the Titanic data set so I'm going to copy this URL
You can take this URL from here
Titanic
Data set
Let's get the URL equal to again it's HTTP raw GitHub user content.com
Data science Dojo data sets master
Titanic CSV
And then I'm going to create a data frame out of that PD
Underscore CSV
And pass the URL to this so I have loaded my
Titanic data set next
Let's inspect
The data
So for that I am going to say print
DF dot info
Get some basic information
I also get some stats of it so I can say DF Dot
Describe
Based on what we have right now
I'm in the right file I am going to say
Lights on
Day 7
And here is our
First few rules the first info about this particular
Thank you the info information is available here
Messenger ID support all the different columns that are there
Not now
Non-null count if you look at it some of them don't have aged information
The cabin information is not available for all the data sets
That is 889 891 so there are some things missing in here is what we can
You can say and this is the basic
Describe which give us some stats on count mean
Standard deviation minimum 25% 50% 71st person and Max
Off the values that
In the data set so that's pretty good
When I take the data and first what I'm going to do is I am going to handle
The missing values
What do you recommend we do here
So as I mentioned there is probably
Age which is not
Which is missing over here
I am going to get it give a median
Based on the other ages that are there
Zodiac age
Any whatever is not available
I will feel DF
Median
That's what I'm going to fill here
Which makes sense because ships bad that back then
What they can based on a particular age criteria and whatever is missing we can just fill that by that
Well also take the embarked data which is I think
Let's see Embark which is 889 normal
I want to take that and over there I'll fill them more for it
Bart for this I am going to say if not available
Usdf
Embark
So that's what
Feel this way so that will kind of takes care of
Handling the missing values
Let's remove some duplicates let's see if there's any duplicates and
Remove duplicate Siri even if it doesn't have duplicates
It's a good idea to run this
Underscore duplicates just running this function will drop duplication you don't have to do anything special for
So why not
Just use it anyways because having duplicates
What kind of cause problems in your data set
The filter data next one
Passengers
In First Class
Let's do that
That's your first underscore
Class is a variable that I'm creating
And here I am going to say DF
And for that I think we use
B class as you seen
Equal to 1 so this will give me all the first class
Passengers on data for that and I can say
First class
Passengers
Slash
Call my first class
Dog head just let's look at the
Top five of them I want to save this
Go back here
Clear it out
Aranda project
And we have the data here
So we are displaying the information again
What is being the description with all the different count mean median
Everything here
And then
For passengers with first class on displaying their information or just the top five of them
So that's
Ask one
A task
Is to General generate visualizations
To illustrate key insights
So we're going to create
Visualizations for
Friends
Comparisons and distributions in this particular case
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to go back here
For visualizations we need
Matt Clark
Live
Dot pipe Lord
As plot
Next I'll say import
Seaborn as SNS
That's what I need
No
To build a go all the way to the bottom
Now first I want to display bar chart
This will display
Survival
How to do that
Create a variable
Survival
Glass equal to DF
Dot I use that group by that you have learned earlier
Goodbye
Pause the big glass
Glass that I want to display and then
I'll get survived out of that so group
Come together
And get the mean out of it so that will give me Survival by class
Next I'm going to
Use the survival
Buy glass
Kind equal to
Color lets you sky blue this time
Make it a little bit lighter
Sky blue
Next Generation blood dot title
I want to use the title as
Survival
Read
I'll use a plot do
Why label
Allergy create text label survival
This is a bar chart
Pendant plot Dot
Show me that bar chart
So let's run this and see how does it look like
You have a bar chart in sky blue which looks much nicer than others
Now depending on class what is the survival rate so from the data itself we can say that more people Sur
In first class then second class and then finally 3rd class
Next Step
Let's first close this
When I clear this out
And then go back here
We're going to use created histogram of age distribution
So I'm going to say
Histogram
Age distribution
So I'm going to use Seabourn for this I'll probably say SMS
And are you DS of
Call
Next thing is my KDE equal to
Next I want to give how many beans I want for this histogram
Which
How to write 20
And color
Equal to values purple this time
Next
I'm going to say plot the title
How to say
Distribution
Next I'm going to say blood dot X label
Is
Lord DOD
Why lab
Is
Frequency
And I'll support
Dog show
I am going to comment this out so that doesn't
Brian top of this
So we have our histogram
So let's go ahead and run this
And we have a histogram
Display depending on the age distribution
So depending on what your age is That's How many passengers that
That in the in in in Titanic so see most of them are focused towards from
95 to 30 around outside
So that's the data that we have
Close this
Clear this out
Go back here
Comment this
The next thing that we want to
Brew is a scatter plot
Off age versus Fair
San Francisco
And this is
Age versus
So for that I'm going to say plot
Scatter
When you use age for it age
Mercedes of y-axis is another thing that I use is fair
RC Alpha is how much does Sprint I wanted 0.5
Next is color equal to
Green and you start
I'll give a title
This time
As
Versus Fair
I'll give the X label
I'll give my label
Show
So let's try this out
Indigo
Scatter plot age versus fair so depending on
How much more older you are more you paid nope it's actually this is where most of
Cattle is
Which is that the further
Play somewhere around here
At the age of 30 so this is shows you
The scatter plot for that so that kind of concludes
Ask to where we generate visualization to illustrate some of the key insights
Next task
Used to identify and interpret patterns or anomalies
So what we going to do is we can use the visualizations and somebody statistics to identify these patterns that
And look for anomalies such as unusually high fairs or missing data trends
Some of the example observations that I can mention based on our plots is
Higher class passengers have higher survival rate we saw that in the first floor graph
An older passengers
Play higher sales that's what we saw in our scatter plot where the concentration
Older people had more
Hyatt Place
A task force to summarize
Findings in the report
No the things that will do here is will create a report summarizing insights including key visualization
When should I start a stick with somebody and you can upload these different different plots that we did
Some of the plotting looks like if you want to create a document
It looks something like this where I can say
Titanic
Data set
Eda report this is how we will create a report if you are
Data scientists get
I love that
And here I'm going to say one
Overview section and create overview section
Where I can say
Data search
Contains around 891 I think
And 12 alarms
Next I can specify
Missing values
Handled
4 minutes for age
And what did we do for that we
Filled
Median
That's what we did
We also did something for
Embarked
And that was
Say that with more
So I can say filled with
More something like that next
You can give so you can skip this that's basic overview
Next I can say key
Insights
The insights
Make sure I don't
Thai Patrol
Next I can say
Survival
Subway
Why
Highest
Passengers
It's around I think 62%
Based on the plus that we have seen
Lowest
We had 1st and 2nd class and 3rd class
Customers but it was lowest for
3rd class
Customers
Which is around 24% so you can display those kind of attach those graphs that we have created
Hear the plot that you created and I can say majority of
Passengers
Aged between which check the age distribution it was between
2240 years and mostly between 25 to 30 years
So you can specify that and and display your plot here you can include the screenshots
And a positive
Boise
Correlation
Exist
Between
Fair
Set a reminder because
We saw that
Older people paid more amount
Which means they have higher survival rate because they were in the first class category whereas the younger people
Who paid less fat had less chances of survival because they were in 3rd class
And then finally a third ones which we did was
Visual insights based on
Whatever we did about so what we can do is
You can include the
Screenshots
Of those plots ride over here so this is how Eda report looks like and this is what is expect
Where is expected as a delivery you have the clean data set with missing values
Handled and duplicates remote a set of visualization showcasing trends
Comparisons and relationships and the return summary
Off key findings patterns and potential hypothesis that's what we give
No for additional practice what you can do is you can use another data set
And apply the same media steps
You can explore Advanced visualizations like box plots or bear plots in C1
And you can create a dashboard
What are your findings using ploty or Dash which are other tools that are also available
Summarize our last day of week 2
We applied our pandas knowledge and visualization skill to perform a full
Play project
Culminating in a report that highlights our ability to manipulate analyze and
Would you like data effectively this is very helpful in the world of data science to provide reports to
Data scientist and
Business managers
Which can make decisions accordingly based on the reports that you specify so I hope you are able to follow
How long if you have any questions or problems or issues let me know and I'll get back to you